So in this module, we kickstart building the
actual content strategy based on all the analysis
we did earlier and the team we need to execute
the strategy. So we're gonna build both the
strategy, kickstart it as well as hire a team
and build up a team of existing internal team
members or external team members that can be
used to have the different tasks in the strategy.
Now, the first thing that we need to do. is
how to choose your content persona and select
different content formats and choose your own
content formats to build a content calendar
that you can use to decide on which content
formats you should start working on and start
assigning those content tasks to your team members.
But in order to do that you need to understand
the different roles in our LinkedIn content
marketing team. So we'll dive into that and
I'll explain what are the different roles in
a LinkedIn content marketing team like content
manager, copyrighter, video editor, graphic
designer. executive assistant and the main
executive who will be managed, who will be like
the responsible, the owner of the process and
what their individual responsibilities are.
And then we will also dive into the recruiting,
hiring and onboarding processes for each of
these team members so that you can onboard
them, hire them and onboard them into your LinkedIn
content marketing team. And then we move on
to the ClickUp Content Board, which is the best
content management system that you can use
for your content management work. for LinkedIn,
why you need it, why it's important, and then
templated content management board in ClickUp
that we built for you with templates of every
single content format that we teach for you
in the program. Now, after that, we'll show
you how to organize content addition calls and
show you how to use them to review, ideate,
and brainstorm really good content in a structured
fashion in a repetitive manner. So this will
be done every week. And finally, we'll jump
into how to Go about activating your network
and activate your existing first degree network
to get increased the reach of your post. So
this is a growth hacking part of the strategy.
We do this to make sure that our network is
primed and the algorithm is primed so that more
users see our content when we actually go ahead
and publish it.
After this, we jumped into the last part of
this module, which is the biggest part, but
this part is all about content formats. So there's
about 20 different content formats that we're
teaching you in the program, including experiences,
stories, videos, tips and tricks, videos, Q&A
videos, resource giveaways, slide posts. So
all of these are interesting content formats
that you can use for your LinkedIn account.
And we'll walk you through first the content
management of how the... creation and the publishing
and the promotion process. Each of these content
formats can be handled within the template cards
in ClickUp. We'll walk you through the template
cards. Then we'll talk about how to ideate these
content formats on ideation calls or by a manual
research. And we'll finally talk about how to
go about creating those with the help of outlines,
hooks, formatting tips, and so on. So that's
it for the overview. This section should take,
based on like how much, how many content formats
you want to experiment with, this section,
should take about. seven to eight hours to completely
finish the initial work, but then you'll have
weekly recurring work based on how much content
you're creating and the tasks that your team
will be spending on each of the creation of
each of those content formats. So all in all,
it should take in between. 15 to 20 hours in
total every week to execute all the work that
we're teaching you with this process. But this
is the start of your LinkedIn content marketing
after all the analysis and set up work that
we did. So let's get excited.