In this video, we will be discussing Engagement
Baits. Now, Engagement Baits is one of the
easiest content formats that you can use to
quickly generate engagement. There are a few
things that you can use in this content format.
The first one is that you need to have some
engagement coming in consistently on your content
on LinkedIn for this content format to be really
effective, but feel free to include it in your
content formats and the content formats that
you're using every week. Let's take a look at
what this content format is first. All you
do with Engagement Baits is call up a bunch of
roles of viewers who will be reading your post
and get them to engage on your content. This
engagement can come in the form of comments,
likes, or shares. What we've done is we've included
a couple Engagement Baits outlines in the Content
Marketing Modules Workbook. And in here you can
find very easy outlines that you can use to
create posts or Engagement Baits of your own.
So I'm going to go through a couple of them
just so you understand how this works. So in
here, say we have, hey, and then we call out
a specific niche role. So community member name.
So we can say fitness founders, for example,
if your fitness founders are your niche, are
your target audience, and they can say, come
in below with your favorite workout. All right.
And a bunch of people will come in below that
will increase the reach of the post. and it
will help you. get your content in front of
the connections of these folks, the fitness
founders who come in below the post, thereby
getting you more targeted reach on the content.
All right, so it's very similar to resource
giveaways, but the advantage with Engagement
Baits is that it's very easy to create. So
they're very short, because you don't need to
create very big post copies. You just need
to quickly think of what you can, what would
be an interesting topic or what would be an
interesting question that you can ask them
and get them to come into that. Let's go through
some of the other outlines. You may have seen
follow-drains a lot on several social media
platforms. It used to be very active, very common
on LinkedIn like a couple of years ago. But
what we do over here is we just ask people to
drop their LinkedIn profile URL so that they
can connect with each other, find more people.
This doesn't work really well if you do it
in a generic fashion, but if you say something
along the lines of, hey marketers or hey construction
engineers or hey logistics managers and so on,
if your audience on LinkedIn or your first
degree network on LinkedIn has a bunch of these
folks, you could get a bunch of people commenting.
As long as you're getting that traction for
these posts, at least 10 people commenting
on these posts, more and more people will see
these posts and you'll keep getting engagement
over time. You can also look at the Engagement
Baits by allowing them or giving them a platform
to promote their own products or services. You
could say something like, what are you selling?
Drop it in the comments below. This is something
that I've experimented with myself and it's
worked really well. This is another Engagement
Bait outline that you can experiment with.
Here's another one. What can you give the niche?
For example, in my case, I would say marketing
or LinkedIn growth marketing or content marketing
and so on. In your case, you could say content
construction, or you could say fitness, or you
could say logistics, and so on, or the SaaS
community, or AI community for free. Drop it
in the comments below. All right, and finally,
we have one more outline over here. I won't
get into that, but it's one of the easiest
content formats that you can quickly create
simply by filling out these personalization
fields or brackets. Just fill them out, copy
paste into LinkedIn and publish them. You could
promote these with LinkBoost as well to get
some initial traction. But as long as you have
10 organic, genuine comments coming in, the
post will generate quite a bit of reach with
more people engaging and commenting on the post.
Now that we've gotten an understanding of how
this works and how we can get started with it,
let's take a look at the process. So the process
is outlined very clearly in ClickUp. The content
manager first creates an outline. This step
is not really needed, but again, we follow a
structured process for all the content formats.
So the content manager starts with the outline.
We can mention the post topic in task typing.
And then he assigns all the tasks. And the copywriter
will start with the post copy, which is very
short. This is an optional step, adding the
hashtags. You don't really need hashtags for
most Engagement Baits. You could include them
though. It's always a good practice to include
hashtags. We need to make sure that the hook
is good enough. Any first comments can be added.
And then do a grammatical check for all the
copy elements. Now, This is also an optional
step, but as always, whenever we publish a piece
of content on LinkedIn, it's always a good
idea to include a selfie or an image with it
so that it takes up more space on the feed,
thereby attracting more dwell time from the
people who see it on their feed. And it takes
up more of the space on the LinkedIn feed as
well, so it grabs more attention or more eyeballs.
So it's always a good idea to include a selfie,
not necessary, it's an optional step. but it's
always a good idea to do it. And then finally
the same reviews, the post copy and all the
elements in the post and approves it. And if
they're good to go, then it moves on to the
executives' approval queue, and the executive
reviews, the post copy and the post elements
are good to go. They can be moved to the ready
to be posted user, user queue and it can be
published on the user profile and on the company
page. All right. That is the simple structure
of the process. The process is more or less
the same as the other content formats, but
it's all listed in detail in ClickUp. The sub-tasks
have all been listed, and the action items for
each of the sub-tasks have also been listed
in the ClickUp task itself. Now, that's it
for the Engagement Baits. See you in the next
video.