So in this video, we're gonna be talking all
about experiential stories and experiential
videos and how to create them. Now, this is
one of my favorite content formats because
I built an entire business on the basis of experiential
stories, simple text experiential stories.
And experiential stories are simply experiential
text stories in the media format. That's the
only difference between them. So these videos
will move in a structured format. I'll first
give you an overview of the task template. and
how the task template works for each of these
content formats. And then I will move on to
how the ideation process works for the specific
content format and how we can find content ideas
and use existing content ideas and so on. And
then I will move on to how to create the content
formats using Outlines and a bunch of other
tools that we'll help you with. All right, so
let's first talk about the ClickUp content
task. So, the template board. So in the template
board, you can find like the template task
in here. So this is the Experiential Story template.
So once you open this, there are different
sections in here. What I'll walk you through
are the different sections for this specific
content format. So Experiencer Stories follow
a very linear, very simple process. A content
manager creates an outline and then it is assigned
to a copywriter. The copywriter creates a draft
and sends it to the content manager for approval.
And then the next subtask is the executive
will review the experience of the story. And
then once the executive reviews it, it will
move to the next stage, which is ready to be
posted to you when it gets published on LinkedIn
on the user profile and then the company page.
In case the executive has any suggestions for
feedback, these can be discussed on the content
editing calls and the content manager will
assign it back to the draft stage. And this
entire process will continue until it is ready
to be posted. Now, for each of these template
cards, for each of the individual steps, of
these subtasks, we've outlined the entire process
for you and each of these steps are personalized
for that specific content format so that you
don't have to guess and be confused around
like how to go about doing this. So at the start,
whenever a content manager is assigning an
outline, what they will do here is they will
assign a specific outline to this. So these
outlines can either be fetched by the copywriter
or by the content manager from the content
ideation sheet. is the content ideation sheet
that I want to work you through. So, this is
an example of a content ideation sheet and this
is an example of a content idea. So, what the,
if the content manager is assigning the post
to the writer, all the content manager needs
to do is copy paste this entire text, come into
the outline section, just paste it. That's
it. We have the entire outline in here on the
different stages of that process and the different
elements in that idea. the copywriter can go
ahead and create the post. But if the copywriter
is creating it, he can either copy this in the
exact same way and add it to the outline, get
it approved by the content manager or by the
executive on the content edition calls. And
once it's approved, he can go ahead and start
creating the post copy. But the first step
is adding the outline. So once the outline is
added, the content manager will begin. So the
first step is creating a copy of the template
task. which we have not done. So let's first
create the copy of the template task. So we
create a copy of the template task by duplicating
it. So we click on this and we duplicate and
we can remove attachments, comments and comment
attachments. So these are not needed. And we
can also remove post watches and assignees.
And then we add the name of the post that we're
going to create. So if the post is going to
be on this specific topic, this is about made
a short-term sacrifice for a big game. So,
but yeah. Okay, so I'm gonna add that made a
short-term sacrifice for a pinkie. And then
I'm gonna come in here and click on duplicate
task and this task will be duplicated. Now
click on this copying the task, it'll take like
a few seconds. But once the task is duplicated,
it'll open up and you can start working on that
specific template task. So that is this first
step. So once that is done, the post can be
edited. So I'm gonna wait till that. task is
created. So it will come at the bottom in the
templates queue itself. So now you need to
open that task and then first go through each
of these stages. Alright. So the first step
is create a copy of the template task and assign
parent task to outlines. So now change parent
task to outline. So now what needs to be done
is we need to move this to outlines. Alright.
And then the post topic in the task title is
to be added. So this is the post topic for
the time being, we can change it later on if
needed. and the outline of the description.
So this is the outline that we copied from the
content ideation board. So I can just copy
this and come in here and paste it over there
so that it's there. I can also paste it without
the formatting so that it comes as one single
block of text and then I can segment it better,
but it's up to you how do you do it. And then
after you do that, we move on to the next task,
which is assign the sub task for draft CW to
a CW who will write the post. So next is assigning
all of these two individual roles and the role
names have been mentioned at the end of the
subtask. So for example, this is for the content
manager. So if I'm the content manager, they'll
assign it to me. If this is for the copywriter,
so whoever the copywriter is on the team, I'll
assign it to them. This is for again, for the
content manager. So whoever the content manager
is on the team, I'll assign it to them. This
is for the executive. So whoever the executive
is, I'll assign it to them. I'm just doing this
for example sake. So I'm not assigning to other
team members, but. After you add more team members
into your board, you will be able to assign
this to other team members and just keep doing
this until all the subtasks are assigned. So
that is all these steps. And then the next part
of it is moving the parent task to draft status
because now you've assigned the outline, you've
added the outline and you've added the subtasks.
But you also need to one more step, you need
to set status of all subtasks as assigned.
we just, we can see it as assigned. So we just
mark it as assigned. This one is assigned,
this one is assigned, this one as assigned,
this one as assigned, and this one as assigned.
So now all of these sub task statuses have been
updated, they turn green. And then we need
to move the parent task to draft status. So
that is the next step in the checklist. So
we need to move the parent task status, so this
is where you can select the parent task status.
You can either just select on this, but if you
click on this, you can see all the statuses
and I click it to draft status. So this is done.
Then you need to mark outline CM sub-task status
as complete. So I come in here, outline CM sub-task
status as complete. So I move and come in here
and mark it as complete. So outlines has been
added and that step is complete. Then one thing
to ensure is ensure due dates for each sub-task
are assigned correctly from where the work
is assigned to the CW to post-publishing. The
end duration should already be two weeks. is
from the due date of this task to the due date
of this task, it should be two weeks difference.
So, if this was done yesterday, this should
be around, okay, so this is today is 19th.
So, yesterday was 18th. So, ideally, like the
entire duration should be done, the entire
post should be done and published by May 1.
All right, so that is what we mean by this.
And you can Based on, let's say, how much time
you think and your available resources, you
can quickly update the due dates. So the due
dates are correct. CM approval should be the
next day after that. So I can mark it as Tuesday
or Wednesday, and the EX approval can be after
that. So I'll mark it as Thursday. So ideally,
the need EX approval should be on the day of
the content edition calls whenever you're scheduling
it. And the ready to be posted can be, well,
based on when you want to publish it. So the
ready to be posted queue, can be understood
from the content ideation sheet. So when you
go to the content format sheet, you can see
the dates in which that content format is supposed
to be published. So ideally market on that
specific day. So if this is Monday, I will mark it
on the next available Monday when that is supposed
to be published. So when I would publish this
is on the 29th. All right. And the company
page, again, it's up to you when you're publishing
it to the company page. Typically we just repurpose
the same post onto the company page. But because
this is an experience, the story of the user,
I wouldn't publish it on the company page. So
what I would do is delete this. But again,
it is mentioned at the latest stage on what
to do about it. For the time being, let's just
proceed as it is. So this completes all the
sub tasks for the outlines stage. And next
we move on to drafts. So the copywriters will
also have a step by step information on exactly
what to do. So creating the post copies, ensuring
three to four relevant hashtags, rereading
the hook of the posts. adding any required first
comments, adding images or photos of the executive
in the respective section in the description.
So we have sections in the description for
images, first comments, post URLs after it's
published. So all of these post copies, everything
is there in the description. So all you need
to do is just follow this exactly as it is
and the process will be airtight. After the copywriter
creates all required elements and adds it,
all they need to do is come in here and update
their subtask, which is the draft subtask as
complete. And then the content manager will
come in and they will follow the steps in the
CM approval revisions checklist. So once both
these are done, all they need to do is come
in here and mark it as complete and then move
it to the relevant queue as well. So for content...
For this specific content for my needy, it's
approval is the approval process for the executive.
And then on the content edition calls, the content
managers can themselves approve it. That is
the best scenario, but you can also assign it
to the executive so that the executives come
in here, they review the post copy and the image.
And if it's good to go, they can approve it,
move it to the next stage, which is the ready
to be posted stage, and they can mark it as,
mark that sub task that is assigned to them as
complete. Or the content manager can handle
it themselves by getting the executive to review
this on the content ideation calls itself. That
is the best way, but this process can also be
followed. All right, and then the executive
assistants come in here, the EAs come in here
and they follow these exact steps that are
outlined in here. So we will talk about and
learn. how to generate comments using ChatGPT
and how to promote content using automated bot
tools and manual bot tools later on in the
content marketing modules. Until then, you can
hold off on these promotion steps if you're
not familiar with them. But after that, you
can start this process of promoting posts as
well. And each of the steps involved in promoting
the posts are also mentioned in here. So you
can prepare relevant comments using chart GPT
prompts and then add the generated comments
as a comment in the parent task. So you need
to add them as a comment in here. You need
to check if all the post elements, so the post
copy, the image or photo, hashtags, et cetera,
are in place and publish it on LinkedIn on the
executor's profile. After you publish, you
need to add the LinkedIn post URL in the description
section. So we have the post URL section for
the description section. Just paste the URL
in here for reference later on. And then...
you can promote the post in the pods and periodically
check in over the one hour to respond to all
the comments from the pod. So if we use pods,
manual pods or automated pods, you'll get like
a lot of other users coming in and commenting
on your posts. So you need to reply to them,
which is very important, which is why we have
this step. And then finally, after you're done
with all these, all you need to do is mark the
ready to be posted subtasks complete. So that
is this subtask that has been assigned to you,
mark it as complete. And then finally, after
you're done with that, you can move on to the
next sub checklist, which is if ready to be
posted company, a sub task exists above, move
parent task to ready to be posted company status,
else move parent task to posted status. Now
what this means is sometimes the sub task will
be absent. The content managers may choose to
delete them if the content managers don't want
this post to be published on the company page
as well. If the post is supposed to be published
on the company page as well, this task will
be So based on that, the parent task status
will change. So if the post is supposed to be
published on the company page, the content
stage after ready to be posted user will be
ready to be posted company. If the company
posting step is absent, they can directly move
it to posted, which is the final content status.
And by then that post should be done. All right.
So that is the task. And this is how you go
about managing that piece of content. So this
covers the entire process of managing the journey
of an experiential story post from ideation
and creation to publishing. Now let's take
a look at how to create experiential stories.
So ideation works for experiential stories
in two ways. One is from the content ideation
sheet. So the content ideation sheet, which
can be found inside the content analysis sheet,
will have a lot of ideas that the executives
have written down. But these ideas may also
come from the content ideation calls so that
you can discuss new ideas. All you need to do
is take a look at the anecdotal story section.
So this is the section that is most apt for
experiential story content ideation. So on the
content ideation calls, you can ask the executives
questions about, What is a major life change that
you've had? Like moving to a new city, quitting
a job or starting a new business. So they will
recall an experience about a major life change
and they will talk about it. And then you can
prompt them with questions. You can ask them,
okay, first can you give me a short and quick
summary? After they answer that, they can say,
can you give me some background information
and a two to three sentence elaboration? Or
what was the moment of highest drama when you
made this major life change? Or how did this
major life change make you feel? How did this
major life change make others around you feel?
What did this major life change make you realize?
What is the lesson you learned from this? So
ideally you need to note this down. You're
making sure you're recording the content ideation
calls, but you also need to note this down
in the content ideation sheet when you're working
on that content idea. So over time, the content
ideation sheet will become a living, breathing,
robust document with a lot of experiences and
opinions and ideas from the executive. You can
use it later on in a much quicker fashion,
in much more efficient fashion if you have a
lot of content ideas in here. But for that
to happen, you have to ask these questions,
ask questions about each of these prompts to
the executive and note them down in the content
ideation sheet when you're working on that post.
Right before you start working on that post,
make sure you get the transcript from the content
ideation call. You add the idea in here for each
of these columns. So don't just add everything
in one column. That is not a structured way
to do it. Add it in a structured fashion in
all these columns. And then copy paste that
idea into the outlines section in the template
card, in the card, and then start working on
the post copy. All right, so that is how ideation
works. So the ideas can come from existing ideas
in the content ideation sheet, or it can come
from new ideas that you discussed on the content
ideation call, but the new ideas also need to
be documented in the sheet. So you can edit
this as you like. So if you want to add like
one more example or idea about a short-term
sacrifice or big gain, you can just copy paste
this exact same row down below and you can edit
that idea and create like a new idea for the
same prompt. So you can create like multiple
ideas for the same prompt. So for example,
learned from a big loss. There are multiple
losses in the life stories of entrepreneurs
and founders and powerful people and rich people.
So you can talk about, you can add multiple
ideas for each of these lines, but you need
to make sure that you're asking these questions
and prompting them with more deeper, deeper
questions with each of these prompts and columns
had as mentioned over here. All right, the only
way to create good experiential stories is by
getting really deep into that experience. and
really getting details about that experience.
You cannot just talk about, okay, I made a short-term
sacrifice where I begin, this is what I learned,
this is what the experience was. You need to
give them the details. So you need to give
them, I was struggling with cashflow, we began
like say with LinkedIn, these are all details.
So this is an example of good detail in an experiential
story, and these details will enable you to
create good content. So unless you're asking
these questions, these questions for each of
these prompts to the executive, it is very difficult
to get these details. You cannot research all
of these details yourself. So, you need to be
asking these questions. Now that sums up the
ideation part for Experiential Stories and Experiential
Videos. Let me go back to the content template
board and also walk you through how the process
will differ for Experiential Videos. So, Experiential
Stories are simple text posts, but when it comes
to Experiential Videos, The process is a bit
different because now you need to create a video
script as well. The executive needs to record
the video, thumbnail images need to be created,
the videos need to be edited. So there's a
few more elements in the process. So let's walk
through that step by step. So the content process
and the subtasks in this is a bit different.
So first the content manager creates the outline
as usual. Then when the copywriter creates the
drafts, there is a small change. So the copywriter.
will now also create a video script for the
experiential video. So based on it's very similar
to the experiential story, but this will be a
video script as opposed to a text copy. Okay.
And they will create a different post copy than
the video script. So the video script and the
post copy shouldn't be the same. It should be
different. It should be unique. And then follow
the remaining, like say parts of the checklists,
the remaining steps in the checklist. And then
it goes to the content managers approval queue.
So that is the next sub task after it. So the
content manager will review the script as well
and the thumbnail caption elements. So many
videos you can add on LinkedIn, on videos you
can add a thumbnail image as well that is a
bit more click-worthy or gets people to click,
stop scrolling and click on it. So you can
add a thumbnail image and the video editors
can create that thumbnail for you. But you
need to add a caption for it. So that is this
section called the thumbnail image caption.
So the copywriters will add that and then the
content manager will come in. They'll review
the post copy, the script as well as the thumbnail
caption and it moves on to the next stage if
it's approved. So the executive will again review
the post copy, thumbnail image, caption and
script and only after this will the executive,
it moves to the awaiting recording here. So
this is where the executive records the video
themselves using their phone. The smartphone
is more than enough, records the audio in a
good fashion so they need to be recording it
in a good setup. and checks of these checklists
in this specific subtask and then it moves
on to awaiting media file. So, the awaiting
media file is where the video editor works
on it. So, when the content manager is assigning
all the subtasks, they need to be selecting
the video editor for this subtask, assigning
this video editor for that subtask. So, the
video editors, this will come to the queue of
the video editors and click up and they can
edit the videos. Create the thumbnail images,
make sure the video audio quality is good.
Um's and ah's and unwanted gaps in the videos
are all removed. They add some background music
in the videos, it will look good. And then they'll
mark the subtasks, they'll move it on to the
next stage. They'll mark their subtasks as complete.
And the next stage is awaiting media. Sorry,
this is what we completed. The next stage is
CM approval revisions. So that is where...
The content manager reviews the finished edited
video and the thumbnail image in the finished
video URL section. So it will be linked over
here in the finished video URL section and
all they need to do is review it. If they have
feedback and revisions are needed, they can
send it back to the video editor or they can
send it to executive's approval. So the executive
will now look at the edited video. If they have
feedback, they'll send it back to the content
manager. or they can approve it and then they
move on to be ready to be posted to you and
ready to be posted for company page queue. So
it's a bit different from the experiential story,
but all the other remaining processes for how
the content is supposed to be created is the
same. And now let's finally move on to how to
create an experiential story. So now we have
some ideas that we can work with, but how do
you go about creating an experiential video
or a story? So this is where the IG content,
viral content marketing workbook comes in.
The best thing about the book is that for each
of the content formats, we have a separate
dedicated section. We can find the link to this
direct section in the progress tracking sheet.
Or you can just search for it in the sheet.
So you can just search for experience.
So, we click on experiential story, it will take
you to the experiential story section. So, these
are details about the experiential story section,
but the section that we want are the outlines.
So, in the sidebar, you can see it. These are
experiential story outlines. Now outlines are
very similar to the hook outlines that we talked
about earlier in the modules. But outlines
are basically viral posts that we've source
from LinkedIn from various creators. And what
we've done is we've reverse engineered these
entire outlines for you. So all you need to
do is come in here and find among the outlines
that examples, we've added five different examples
of experiences story outlines. So you can go
through each of these outlines. And you can
choose an outline that is relevant enough for
you. So this one is about company name is Chinese
or people criticizing us. Outline three is about.
My real name is Adi Suja, you see this woman I'm
in Love with, she is the one who taught me about
love. So this is about my mother. So that's
a very emotional thing. It's a very shocking
controversial topic. So made a shocking confession
related to a relationship started. So that is
what this post is about. Fourth outline is
about define describe a painful moment, public
moment. So these may not exactly be aligned
with the content ideas that you've the most
apt outline that in your opinion on that content
idea. So, if you feel that this outline is apt
for this, you can select that outline and you
can start working on it. So, just choose the
outline and all you need to do is read the
content idea thoroughly and then come in here
and say, in that entire experience, what is
a painful moment that I can describe? You can
add one or two lines or three lines for it,
but in that entire experience, what is a painful
moment? public moment that we can detail as
a one line over here. And you move on to the
next line. My first reaction was hard to resist.
So think about what, let's say, a reaction could
have been or could be. It's not necessary that
all the details for all the lines comes from
the content ideas itself. The executives are
going to review this anyway. So it's fine that
you add some detail of your own. These can
be corrected later on the ideation calls when
the executive reviews it. But it's important
that you
look at each of these outline prompts and add
a line for it. Look at the outline prompt,
add a line for it. We won't be getting into
an over the shoulder version of how to do this
because content ideas can differ a lot, but
this is how you go about creating outlines.
Now even for video scripts, if you're creating
an experiential story, the same exact same
outlines will work for you. You don't need different
outlines for the video scripts. The exact same
outlines can work for you. But here's where
it gets After the outline is created, after
you create the actual post copy of the video
script, you need to create the hooks. So for
the hooks, we go back to the hooks section that
we covered earlier. So we have 100 viral hooks
over here. So after you create the post from
the outline, then you need to come back to
hooks and ensure that the first few lines, the
first one or two or three lines of the post
are optimized. using these hooks. So you can
go through, we have about a hundred hooks.
You can definitely find a hook that is valuable
for you, that is good enough for you and find
a good hook and personalize it and add to the
top of the post and make sure that the post
flow is good enough. But this is how you go
about creating experiential stories and videos.
As always, if you have any questions about this,
this excellent content format, just ask us
in the group coaching calls or Feel free to
drop your questions in the WhatsApp community.