So now we are going to take a look at experiential
stories. So this is the experiential story.
template in ClickUp, and the process begins with the
outline section...subtask. So the content manager
first creates a copy of the template task, changes
the parent task status to outlines. Then they
need to add the post topic in the task title.
So that's over here. The post topic needs to
be filled. This needs to be edited. And then
an outline of that topic in the description.
So this is done usually on the content ideation
calls. Whatever content ideas that can be
the executive shares or the feedback that
they give on the ideas that you provide to
them. These ideas can be fetched on your own
or from the content ideation sheet. You need
to add them in here and detail it on the content
ideation call, and this needs to include like
what the experience is, what changes it brought,
what lesson was learned, what message or lessons
to be conveyed At the end of post everything
needs to be included in here. Make sure
the outline is very well, um, detailed, uh, so
that the copywriter has enough work
enough stuff to work on. And then next, he assigns
all the subtasks for all the team members.
So the subtasks will include the drafts for
the copywriter. So that is where they create
the draft of the post, the revision or the approval
process for the content managers. This
needs to be assigned to themselves like this,
and the executive approvals, The executive needs
this needs to be assigned to the executive.
This needs to be assigned to the executive
assistants on the team who will be handling
that the publishing process on LinkedIn, so
assign the subtasks to the relevant team members.
So all of these tasks are for that, and then
After he assigns it to all of them, he needs
to update the status of the content manager
needs to update the status of these subtasks
as assigned. So there will only be two subtask
statuses. One will be assigned, and the other
one will be completed. So just mark it as assigned
and you're good to go. So after you mark it
as assigned, the last thing is change the
parent task to Drafts status. So,
need to click on this and change the parent
task status to draft status. That's it. So
that the entire team is aware on where that
content piece is in the content management
process. And then after all these steps are
done, they can mark their subtask of outlines.
So this subtask of outlines as completed because
they've already added the outlines and finished
that entire process. They can go ahead and mark it as
completed. Now the next step is the process for this subtask
process for this subtask has been covered already
in these checklists. Just go to here and follow
these one by one. So the first one is adding
the post copy. So review the outline that the
copyrighter added for you carefully, create
the post copy and add them in here. And the
post copy should have the hashtags. So which
is the next step. you need to add three to
four relevant hashtags with good followings.
We already covered how to do this in the previous
videos. That's usually good to go. And then
re-read the hook of the post copy. The hook
is very important for experiential stories and
all the LinkedIn posts. So re-read the hook
of the post copy and make sure it's catchy enough.
Then you add in the required first comments.
So first comments are only added if you need
to add external links or you need to add link
to another external source or you want them
to take an action specifically after they read
the post. So, If you're adding any first comment,
you need to mention it to the post copy that
check the first comment for so and so. So you
need to mention that in the post copy at the
end, and then you need to add a first comment
on how it's supposed to like any with any links
and so on. Do not include any direct external
links in the post copy, and then finally, they
need to add the image or photo of the experiential
story. So typically, experiential stories need
an image or photo, so that needs to be added in this
step. And then finally, do a grammatical check
of all the post copy elements and then they just need
to do two things. So the first thing is they mark
the subtask as complete, the subtask is complete,
they can click on here and mark it as complete,
click on completed and it's done. And then the
next thing is to move this to the next stage
in the content management process, which is
CM approval or revisions, so that the content
manager get go ahead and approve it or suggest
revisions. So that's it for the draft CW step.
The next step is the content manager approval or revisions
step. So in here, what they need to do is they need to come in
here and Take a look at these checklists in this section.
So they need to approve the content manager needs to
review the post copy and the and the image or the photo with
the experiential story. If there are revisions needed, they
need to drop a comment in this section. Tagging,
so you can tag like different team members like
this. So you can tag the person, the CW, the
copywriter with the feedback and then move
the main parent task back to the draft section
so the entire team is aware that this is still
in drafts. And then set the status of the draft
CW subtasks, so that's this subtask, draft
CW subtask, move it back to a site. Okay, that's
it, and if any changes are required, now these
copyright will follow the entire checklist again
because it's back to drafts. Now if it is good
to go, they can move the parent task to. need
EX Approval. So it's been mentioned like which
task, which stage to move it to is already marked
in here. So you just need to follow the checklist
as it is. So they need to move it to need EX
Approval, and they need to mark their own sub
task for CM Approval as completed because
they finished the review process. All right.
Now the next step after that is for posting it on the
user profile. So this is for this subtask posting
it in the user profile and the company page, since we
assign to the executive assistants on the team and what
they will do is they will first create the comments
using chat GPT and they will add the generated
comments as a comment in here for later reference.
They will check if the post elements like post
copy, image, photo, hashtags, etc., are all in
place in the description, so then you do a manual
check of that, and if it's not in like say good
to go, they need to contact the content manager
and get that sorted but if it's good to go they
can go ahead and post it on LinkedIn on the
executive's profile. They need to copy a link
to the LinkedIn post URL and add it in the
description section, so that's in here in the
description section, and then finally after
they've done with both of them they need to
move the Academy, 18th strategy call, starts
at 10 minutes.
We need to move. Draw your gallery. Eighteen,
seven...
So they add the post URL in the respective section
in the description and then promote the post
in Link Boost or Lemp or the manual boards and
periodically check in over the next one hour
to respond to all the comments from the post.
So you need to reply to the comments and then
mark the ready to be posted subtasks. So this
subtask as completed, and you move the main
card to the ready to be posted user stage in
here, so that everyone is on the same page
on what the status is of the specific part of
the piece. And then finally, you mark the subtasks complete.
The subtasks complete. That's it for this step.
And the next step is that of
the company page. Now, we follow the exact same
process for the company page as well, and you
update the sub-tasks and the statuses. But for
the company page, you need to create new comments,
again in ChatGPT, and add them as a comment
in here, because you cannot use the same comments
for promoting in different places. And after
you publish on the company page, in this case,
you need to copy the link to the post URL in
the company page and add it to the description
as well in the LinkedIn post URL section, so
just post the links over there.