So most of us assume that funny content, like
we share on TikTok and like we share on Instagram
Reels and YouTube Shorts are not really a good
fit for LinkedIn. But that's not true. In fact,
it is one of the best performing video content
formats on LinkedIn. When you add humor to
posts and when you add a fun element to posts,
it stands out from the rest of the boring content
that you typically see on the LinkedIn feed
completely about business topics. So I'm going
to just play this video so that you understand
what this is about. So this guy is on his way
to bother 40 more LinkedIn connections about
positivity and encouragement. So look at that.
He's just playing with his dog. That's it. It's,
it's a five second video. So it takes a bit
of time to refer to like, say, like record it
and then edit it, you have like a super short
post copy, but that's it. That's what you call
a fun video. Now fun videos can be created
on the most mundane, irrelevant topics. You
just need to think about them creatively. So
this is more about how open you'd be to recording
interesting, funny videos. You will be able
to find more interesting examples of fun videos
in the IG Content Outlines book. In the IG
Content Outlines book, we explain more fun videos.
You can take more examples over there. But.
That is it for fun videos. You need to create
the script. The process for fun videos is almost
exactly the same as that of experiential videos.
So there is an editing process involved in
it because you record the videos yourself. You're
not taking third party content and just publishing
it and there is repurposing or resharing it.
You're recording your own videos. So the process
is very similar to that of experiential story
videos where a video script is created and
you record the video. You don't need to even
say anything in the video. It can be video
scripts where you don't say anything. You just
explain what you do, the actions that you're
taking in the video script. But to a large extent,
this depends on the creativity of the copywriter
to understand what are your limitations with
the recording, what are the executors' limitations
with the recording, how much effort they can
put into it, and what kind of videos they can
quickly record using their smartphone. You don't
need to use huge recording setups for this.
A smartphone or an iPhone is more than enough.
But then once the copywriter gets an understanding
of what type of videos you can record, how much
time you can spend into the recording, they
can come up with a quick script with the scenes
that are to be recorded. And then they can
create a video script for it. And then it follows
the usual approval queue that we have for video
content formats, where the video script and
the post copy is created by the copywriter,
the content manager reviews it, the executive
then reviews it. Then the executive goes ahead
and records it, uploads it to Drive and sends
it to the video editor for editing. The video
editor then creates the video and then sends
it to the content manager for approval and
then the executive again reviews it after the
content manager's approval and then finally
it moves to the ready to be posted queues for
user profile and the company pages. Very simple
and they're very easy to create but at the same
time hooks are again important. The video keeps
playing. So hooks are again important for this
content format. So it's important that you
take a look at the hook section and optimize
the hooks for this content format as well.
And you can find the hooks in the content marketing
modules workbook. Just search for 100 viral
hooks in the doc and you should be able to find
it quickly.