So in this video, I'm going to walk you through
a structured process to identify your competitors
and analyze them and their content on multiple
social media platforms and their website so
that we can understand what content formats
they use, what topics they create content on
and how to document it in a good manner in the
content analysis sheet. Now why is this important?
This is important because the best way to build
the foundation to your own content strategy
is to analyze what other competitors in your
space are doing and how they're doing it. In
addition to this benefit of giving you a validated
understanding of what content works in your
industry, it will also help your content team
in having this documented in one place so that
they can refer to it to come up with more content
ideas. The name of the sheet we use to do this
analysis is called the content analysis sheet,
and you can find it in the progress tracking
sheet and below the video. This analysis will
take about three to four hours in total to
complete fully, including watching the training.
So let's jump into it. So let's go to the content
gap analysis sheets and we have the competitor
analysis sheet in here. So the competitor analysis
sheet basically list down has a column for a
bunch of competitors, their websites, their
company pages, the key profiles of users of
their company who may be active on those profiles,
especially on LinkedIn. And then we have a list
of links to their different social media profiles.
And then the analysis begins where we analyze
their LinkedIn content, their top of the funnel
content, their middle of the funnel content,
their Bofu content and so on. so that we
can get an understanding as to what types of
content each of these competitors are creating.
Alright, now let's start off with finding competitors.
Now if you're in the consulting space, I'm
going to explain how to find your competitors
with the help of this case study. That's a
robotic process automation and process automation
company called Rhenus Automation. They're part
of a conglomerate. We work with them. So let's
take a look at how we can find some competitors
with this client. In most cases, if you're running
a consulting or a service company. you will
already have a very good understanding of your
major competitors like who are the big players
in the niche, who are brands, service companies,
or consulting companies that are already doing
a good job of creating content and generating
brand awareness with their content. So you
can list them down in the sheet, but in case
you need to find more competitors, you need
to do some research about this, this is the
process that you can follow for this. So the
first way to easily find other... consulting
or service companies in your space. This is
just enter the keyword for the service which
you offer, say in this case is process automation
or intelligent automation or business automation
and consulting or service and so on. And Google
will give you like a bunch of results of companies
in the space, but ideally to look at companies
that are not very big. So ideally look at companies
that are maybe up to four times your size,
but not beyond that. If it's beyond four times.
what happens is the content style and the tone
of voice will be completely different. The target
audience that they focus on will be completely
different, so they won't be a good example for
the analysis. But if I search for process automation,
I can see Bain & Company, which is very big,
EY is very big. We have a bunch of stuff in
here. And what I will do is I will scroll through
each of these. I will go through the next few
pages and try to come up with some names of
companies that are better doing a good job
over here. Now I keep doing this for a while
and I'll try to come up with a bunch of companies
that are a good fit. So I've done my work and
I've identified some competitors but in addition
to Google there are a few other places that
we need to look. So one of them is G2. So what
G2 is, it's kind of like a directory website
that lists software providers, consulting service
providers and so on. So all I did was search
for robotic process automation services and
it dropped me this page with a bunch of sub-optional
listings of different companies that offer
robotic process automation or business process
automation. And in search for more keywords
and I can find more. But from websites like
G2, again, we shouldn't be looking at big companies.
Say for example, Tata Consultancy Services is
one of the biggest IT companies in the world.
And it's a bad idea to take them because the
donor style of the content and their targeting
persona will be completely different from say
a startup that offers robotic process automation
or business process automation services like
Rhenus Automation or an SMB. So you should
either be looking at companies of similar size
or the same size. So all of these are very
big companies, but then I did get some good examples like
AccelerateRPA or Aggranda and so on, Now what I would do is
go through Google as well as G2. There's one
more website that you can take a look at. So
that's Capterra. I'll explain Capterra in more
detail later in the video. But Capterra is another
website that you can use to take a look at.
I need to win, find, prove that I'm a human.
So just get that load. This is frustrating.
Alright, we're done.
Okay, so we are on Capterra. And you can do
the same thing that we just did on G2. We can
search for say, robotic process automation,
services, and click enter, and they will bring
us a bunch of stuff. I got good examples like
Automation Anywhere, which I was already familiar
with, but even then you will get good results
from here. And you can... I suggest spending
a bit of time if you're not very familiar with
the industry and you need to find competitors.
But most of you watching this video will already
have a good understanding of who your main
competitors are. But it's good to do this so
that you get an understanding of which competitors
are doing a really good job of marketing their
business online with Conte. Now after you've
opened up a bunch of apps, I suggest doing this
for about 15 minutes till you come up with
15 to 20 different competitors. And please remember
that when I say competitor, I don't really
mean that they've offered the exact service
that you offer. They could be offering the
exact different kinds of service model. They
could be offering a different proposition in
the same sub niche or niche. They could even
be a software company, even if you are the
consulting space. But the core identifier that
we need to use over here to consider them as
a competitor is that they need to be focusing
on the same target audience with similar pain
points. right and they need to be solving the
same pain point so for example even if we are
a robotic process automation consulting company
UiPath which is one of the biggest RPA companies
in the world and Automation Anywhere which is
a competitor of UiPath are both software and
tools that we use for our clients to help them
automate so even though we are a consulting
company we may be using a bunch of softwares
that focus on the exact same target audience.
So in our case, I know that both UiPath and
Automation Anywhere are focusing on the exact
same target audiences as well, so I could consider
these as competitors and analyze their content
as well. So that's a good idea. But try to make
sure that they have, they're focusing on the
similar target audiences and they're solving
the same pain points that you're solving with
your product or your service. All right, so.
I have opened a bunch of tabs over here and
if you are not familiar with that brand and
like say you need to consider or evaluate them
to see if they are a good enough competitor
the best way to do this is one take a look
at the traffic that they are generating to their
website and two take a look at the number of
employees that they have and the number of followers
that they have on their company page. Now how
do we do this? So the best thing to do is to
use the SEOquake Chrome extension. So it's
called SEOquake. I will just open up their extension
page so that you understand how it looks. So
that's SEOquake. Just google this SEOquake Chrome
and you should be able to find the Chrome extension.
Install the Chrome extension. You don't need
to activate it or anything. Just install the
Chrome extension and when you go to any website
you can just click on this link. Select this
one. So just select this one and click on Semrush
SE Traffic. a very similar search engine traffic.
So that will give us an understanding of how
much traffic they're generating. So it seems
they're generating about 80 visitors, which
is very low. So I don't think this is a good
one, but let me also evaluate the LinkedIn page
of this user. So when you, any website you
take, if you go to the footer or to the header,
there should be social media links like this
one. So you can just click on that and it'll
open up the company page of these. companies
on LinkedIn, you can take a look at the number
of followers that they have and the number
of employees that they have. So if they're big
enough, you can take a look at the website
and also see if they have an active blog, if
they're publishing content actively. So it
looks like these guys don't seem to have a lot
of content on the website. They have some case
studies, but let me also take a look at their
company page and see their publishing posts.
So this is a good way to go about, let's say,
understanding if they're actively creating
content or taking a look at this. They published
the previous post like, yeah, they're publishing
it one month ago, three weeks ago, and so on.
Let me sort this by recent using this filter
over here. So they're not publishing content
very actively, so I don't think Blackbook is
a good competitor to analyze. In this manner,
I keep going to the next one that I came across.
So VURAM is another one. See. on podcast,
they are creating some content actively. So
let's take a look at Insights. They do have
a blog. Let's take a quick look at the blog.
And let's take a look at their SEMrush traffic.
So the SEMrush traffic seems to be about, how
much is that? 213, better than the previous
one. But let's take a look at. There are social
media profiles. So they don't have a lot of
social media content. So what I would do is
open them up in LinkedIn. So.
VURAM. Search for VURAM. WNS VURAM. Alright they
seem to have 913 employees, quiet big, and they have
15000 followers Not Bad, So let's take a look at the posts
and the content on the website. And in this manner, I keep
going through all the competitors that I've, that
I've just opened up new tabs with, and I'll just go
through them and then try to understand
if they are a good competitor that we need
to analyze that is creating good content.
So just quick checks,
But that should be more than enough to understand
how and well they do. So if you take a look
at the LinkedIn page, okay, they're publishing
daily. They're attending Summit
for, one week. Okay. Not very active. Maybe
they're publishing once a week or something.
Okay. Twice a week. No pro capabilities. Okay.
They, okay. I haven't sorted it yet. So it's
sorted by recent and yeah, they are publishing
content actively.
So this is someone I will keep open to WNS VURAM
will be someone I keep open and I will keep
moving on to the next one Scalepointer is another
one again like usual we open up the LinkedIn
company page we take a look at how much traffic
they're generating to their website this was
NA which means they don't assembles doesn't
have the data so I'm taking a look at their
LinkedIn and their content on their company
page and try to quickly understand if they're
a good competitor or not. Now, this is how you
can do it in the consulting space. But please
remember, don't filter out competitors who may
be offering a definite business model. Now,
irrespective of whether you're in the consulting
space or the SaaS space, the actionable walkthrough
that we're going to jump into right now will
cover the entire process. You can follow the
exact same process for whether you're a consulting
company or a SaaS company. But in this case
for this video, to explain the process in detail,
I'm gonna be using a SaaS example, because
SaaS products tend to have better content so
that I can explain this better in the video,
all right? Now TraceCost is a SaaS company in
the construction niche. They're one of our
clients. So I'm gonna be using this to give
you an example of how to go about doing this
in the SaaS space. For most of you who are in
the SaaS space, this process should work for
you. So the first step to do here in order to
identify your competitors is to list out existing
identity existing competitors that you're already
familiar with. So most of you will already
have a good idea on who your competitors are
or who are the big players of this industry
or creating really good content. And from my
own knowledge, I know filter trend is a very
good competitor that we should be analyzing
in this industry. But if you're not familiar
with like a lot of competitors in your industry
and you want to do additional research. We
should be doing this for at least three or four
competitors. But in order to go about doing
this and finding additional competitors, an
easy way to do this is to use Capterra. So Capterra
is a website that well shows you.
a lot of alternatives to a specific software.
So you can just search for one competitor,
name it, then Capterra in Google, and just
open it. And this should give you suggestions
for alternatives you can use. So if I just keep
scrolling down, I can find some construction
workforce management. So this is a good one
that I can look at. And there's Autodesk Construction
Cloud. So that's another good one I can look
at. I can just open this in a new tab, CoConstruct.
There's a bunch of them, construction jobs on
track, this is also a good one. Contractor
Foreman, this is also a good one. Fieldwire
construction scheduling software, this is also
a good one. So I read through the alternatives
and I try to get an understanding of which
of the relevant ones in my industry that are
targeting the same target audience that I have.
It's not important that they have, they've offered
the exact same products and services as well
as they offer solutions and services or products
to the same target audience. that is similar
to your product or service, you can consider
them as a competitor. All right, and from this
research that I've already done, I've identified
a bunch of competitors. So the first one is
the Autodesk Construction Cloud. So I will
go back to the sheet. I will add that in here.
Let me follow that correctly. And I'll keep
going till I add this. So I also identified
the website for them. So I'm gonna come in here
and I've added the competitor website URL.
on and then keep doing this activity. So BuildPro
Okay, looks like I'm unable to find home builder
software. Okay The essential construction management
software cool. This looks like the correct one.
So I'm gonna open them in here So CoConstruct
I've just googled them. They have a website
Pro Crew Schedule their website so
I could burn and look at that build it Oops
sorry, okay, build it is not that build it.
I can just maybe so truck constructional software
and I should be able to get an idea. Yeah,
I think this looks like the correct website.
So I'm going to open that and copy the URLs
of all the ones I find in here. All right, so
I'm adding that and
the troll. A piece that we hear. And then we
have full construct. And a that we have here.
then we have a Pro Crew schedule so I'm gonna
copy the tech wordpress and add that in here
and the trend is going to be this URL. Now that
I named. So now I found five competitors. Now,
ideally you should be selecting the best, the
biggest five competitors, so that all of them
have active content strategies that they're
using that they get to learn from. But the
best way to do this, you should take a look
at the software as you will already have an
idea on who these competitors could be. So you
can just list it down. You don't need to do
additional research using Capterra. But if you
don't have a good idea, just take a look at
their website, see how many users they have,
see if they have a content strategy, and the
ones that seem like the biggest businesses,
add them in here. All right, the next step
is to add the LinkedIn profiles and the social
media profiles of all of these different softwares.
And the best place to find this is, again, in
the other websites themselves. So you can open
up each of these websites one by one, and you
can easily scroll down. to the bottom and in
the footers of most of these websites you should
be able to find the different social media
profiles. So I can easily find the Instagram
ID, the Facebook ID, the LinkedIn ID, the Twitter
ID and the YouTube ID is in here. So this is
the best way to go ahead and add URLs. So I'll
come in here and I will copy-paste all of the
URLs that I find in here. You can also open
them up because we're going to be doing some
analysis on them shortly and keep... doing
this activity. I'm gonna add the competitor
LinkedIn page in here.
I'm now copying Twitter.
and I'm gonna copy Youtube.
All right, now we've added all the social media
links and the next step after this is to go
to the LinkedIn profile and add the key profiles,
stand some key profiles of users who are working
at these companies on LinkedIn, who are active,
are someone active on LinkedIn. Now, how do
we go about doing this? So we first open up
LinkedIn and we search. we can open this company
page on LinkedIn. So let me open up this company
page on LinkedIn. We can find it in here. And
in here, I can find that they have 793 employees.
That's quite a lot. So I can enter, I can click
on this button over here. That's a bunch of
my messages opening up. So I can add a bunch
of these, open this up in here and get an idea
of the employees who are working in that company.
Alright, so we have the Chief Strategy Officer.
Anything with Chief is something that I would
look at. So I'll just open up his profile. He's
the founder, looks seems to be the founder.
But the easy way to go about filtering for this
is to click on Search with Sales Navigator.
And in there you can filter for the seniority
level. So ideally we should be looking at the
CXO levels at the start and try to identify
some key profiles in that company. and then
look at the VP level, then at the director level
and so on. So you should go by this in steps.
So let's first go to Sales Navigator and search
for the CXO roles in this company. In the meantime,
I can quickly look at the profiles and try to
see if they are active. So the way to find
the content that they publish is to go to the
bottom and click on Show All Activities. So
we click on Show All Activities, you should
be able to connect the posts that they publish.
He seems to be head of fintech and digital banking.
So I wouldn't see his key profile, but either
way we'll click on show all activity. He's the
founder at Buildertrend, so I'll open his profile
and then click on posts in each of these profiles.
The posts will show you the posts that they're
publishing.
On right, so looks like Buildertrend is a quite
co-constructed. That's an interesting observation.
But when I look at this profile, I can see that
the previous post was two years ago. So this
person is non-active. So I'm gonna close off
this profile. This person is also not active.
Okay, let's take a look at that. This person
is also not active. He's probably three years
ago, so I'm gonna close that off. This person
is sharing stuff like five months ago. So again,
not very active. I'm gonna close this off. And
now in Sales Navigator, let me take a look
at... the seniority levels. So I'm going to
click on see all filters, click on seniority
levels and I'm going to add CXOs. So CXOs would
be the first key profiles that I look at. So
I've already looked at some of these guys, but
I'm going to open this person, achieve revenue
officer. Ideally, we need to be looking at the
financial officer. We will need somebody who
is the CMO. So now I've looked at all the CXOs.
I'm going to remove the CXO job title and look
at the VPs. So you go out of this in this step,
so this is the WISE system of customer success.
I put open his profile, I could look at SVP of
operations, EVP of marketing, engineering operations,
architecture, software development. This is
just so I can get an understanding of who's
active on LinkedIn by just quickly going through
each of these profiles. This is a wise person
to people, but if they don't have an active
profile in me, then that's a signal that it's
not a good profile to look at it. So let's take
a look at this person and try to get an understanding
of whether they're active on LinkedIn, but you
won't be able to see this over here. So you
need to open up their profile on LinkedIn, click
on this Tab icon here, and click on View
LinkedIn profile. So I'm going to do that for
all the profiles that we just saw. So, we're
open View LinkedIn profile, without this View LinkedIn
profile, I've gone this View LinkedIn. Profile,
gone this View LinkedIn profile. So I'm just gonna
go ahead and open all the LinkedIn profiles.
There, now I've opened up all the LinkedIn profiles.
I'm gonna click on Show All Activity in all
of them and then go to posts in each of these
profiles so that I can get an understanding
of the content that they're publishing and quickly
just close the tabs where there are no posts
published. All right, so many of these people
are not really active on LinkedIn. They're
getting some PR mentions. Okay, that's some
good to know. But if I take a look at this,
many of these people have just published stuff
2 or 3 years ago Not really active on LinkedIn
This gives me an idea that, okay, this competitor
is not really active on LinkedIn This person,
she's the EVP of marketing so I guess she's
a bit more active on LinkedIn They publish
some content on social media, she's resharing
that This is a blog post that she said, okay,
but not very active But I've gotten a quick
overview on What she's doing in here, so I'm
gonna look at more profiles Cool, this is one
year before this was three months before I
get this person seems to be a bit more active
And this person is also not very active. So
now I'm gonna take a look at the content on
each of those profiles So it's gonna be three
months ago BuilderTrend company looking to grow
a team. So to the hiring post this kind of
like employee experience story or a company
culture story. So if you take a look at that,
available homes, so many builders. So she traveled
a bit something, so she's updating on that.
This one was an event that they attended. Builders
wanted to work simpler on construction pros
trust to help them succeed in every aspect of
their business. So there's a blog post that
they shared on social media. All right. But
that's about it. Not as huge, um, not a lot
of activity that we can learn from, but now
what I'm going to do is I'm going to take a
look at the content on the company page. So
I'm just trying to form thoughts around, um,
what these, um, what this company is doing on
LinkedIn and what the user profiles are so
that I can get a validated understanding of
what works. And then I took our posts on the
company page and again see the company page
content looks like they're publishing every
day and they seem to have They seem to be Interesting.
Okay, so the interview attending podcasts.
That is an interesting observation. This is
a customer experience, sorry. So Shelter Solutions
LNC seems to be their customer.
data that I've seen in addition to supply chain
issues remaining continuing at Borage of Labor,
even apply three I think, gentlemen.
Interesting. So they've also linked to something
in here. Let's take a look at what that is.
Alright so this is the announcement for a lead
magnet that they created on the construction
outlook in 2023. And they've announced it on
LinkedIn. This is seems to be.
and link to a blog post this is also a link
to a blog post this is a video
Let's take a look at what that is, stay right
over me.
how to pick the right clients for your business.
Interest takes, this is a blog post again on
the Buildup Trend website that is hand-privileged
to their customers. Cool. Now I have a very
good understanding on, on like say how these
users are filling it out. So I'm gonna go ahead
and open my. competitor analysis sheet, and
there are many key profiles that are actively
publishing really good content, so I'm not going
to go ahead and fill it. You can go ahead and
fill it, but I will start to enter what some
stuff I found. So LinkedIn content specifically,
some interesting posts I found were on the company
page. So they are adding customer experience
stories. So this looks like this, this I believe
is a smaller version of their website or something
they shared a blog post that they shared on
their website. They've included a link to it
which is not a very good idea but what I'm gonna
do is I'm gonna copy this, I'll be linked to
this post, come to the sheet and this is an
example of a good post. I'm gonna add more
examples in here. You can label this as well,
so this is a customer experience study.
Yeah. Right. Let's add more. This is sort of
like announcement for lead magnet. So these
guys are publishing lead magnets as well.
Let's look at more that they've published over
this week. They're sharing links to blog posts,
plus they're sharing snippets. Take a look,
this is a one minute video. So this is a snippet
from a podcast, a video podcast that they did.
So that is something we could add. Video content
is always a good. inclusion. I'm going to copy
the link to that and I'm going to add that
as a video podcast Snippet. So you see, just
from a few minutes of work, we have an idea
of the content pieces that they're doing. And
now we just need to document the content formats
that they're using. Let me just fill that out.
All right, so the content formats that they're
using are customer experience stories, lead
magnets, and video port So I'm just gonna
quickly enable them or copy them from what I
find in here, customer experience story, sorry,
I'm bad at typing. Alright, and then we have
lead magnets, which is another one I could
add. Video podcast snippets are another one
I could add. Alright, and they're also sharing
links to blog posts. And then the counter.
All right, now what is the tone of voice that
they're using on LinkedIn? So this is a very
important element to look at. So they're mostly
looking for company, business focused content.
So all of them is business focused. They're
not really looking at the experience side or
humor or any emotional highs in the content.
It's almost always highly professional. and
business focused content.
Interesting. Okay, so this is what I will include.
We use a
um, they use business focused on tone of voice,
um, and head, head for it.
target onions? that.
on thoughts about how that for not to is helping
users, helping customers, or how they are events
they attend on funding that they fulfill.
All right, so I've filled that out. And now
I can go ahead and enter the analysis part
for the ToFu, MoFu, and BoFU content. Now,
before we proceed with this specific, these
columns, let me give you an idea of what they
mean by ToFu content. So ToFu content means
top of the funnel content. What that stands
for is content used to generate awareness.
about their product or service. So these can
be blog posts that are short form, awareness
focus pieces. These can be LinkedIn posts that
are awareness focused, viral videos, news and
trends. These could be simple videos focused
on YouTube, on Instagram, on Reels and so on.
So now we need to take a look at all of this
analysis and make some notes on how they're
going about doing this. Now this is important
because not all content will be focused on
generating awareness. Some content will be focused
on generating, like say, focus on sharing their
expertise, which can be in-depth blog posts,
strategies, or how to focus on the blog posts,
white papers, so they're creating some white
papers and so on, then they're creating a bunch
of middle of the final content. Could be e-books,
it could be webinars, it could be podcasts,
it could be newsletters that they're publishing
and so on. Or they could be bottom of the final
content. So bottom of the final content are
more targeted towards people who already know
and like and trust them. and they are focused
on converting them up with case studies or
testimonial videos or demos and free consultation
calls. So those customer experience stories
that we saw fall into this category. So now
we're going to go ahead and add some examples
of each of these. So from the research that
we already did, we also need to take a look
at the social media profiles, but from the research
that we already did on LinkedIn, now we can
start categorizing them into ToFu, MoFu and
BoFu content. Now this is the end of the corporate
data analysis for say Builder Trend. and you'll
have to replicate this process for Autodesk,
BuildPro, CoConstruct and Pro Crew . Now I'm
gonna go ahead and show you how you go about
doing this. So let's start off with taking a
look at blog posts that they're publishing
on their website. So I'm gonna open their website
from here, click on that, it's gonna open up
their website. And from the website, I can quickly
take a quick look and understand, okay, that's
weird. So I'm opening up for some reason, and
we just opened up from fall.
All right, so again here we have resources,
so blog, ebooks, everything. Most of the stuff
is in a structured manner. So we can already
understand, let's say, from established players,
established competitors, what are the different
types of font that they're creating. So the
first piece we need to take a look at a blog
post, right, so we're going to open the blog
and try to get an understanding of what kind
of font that they publish, all right? Now take
a look at this, construction materials management.
Okay, that is an interesting topic. on solving
employee turnover in construction. This word,
how to guides on how to do different stuff,
how to improve construction cash flow. And by
top digital marketing strategies, I believe
that's for construction companies, how to track
construction equipment easier. So there's a
bunch of blog posts in the apparatus, see the
old post that they've published, that's interesting.
But these are in-depth guides, these are how
to track construction equipment easier. So
these are in-depth guides that are quite long.
that explain how to use I believe the builder
trends software to track construction equipment.
So we have the videos on LinkedIn right here,
but now we need to go ahead and open up the
social media profiles on Instagram, Facebook
and so on. So if you take a look at that this
column that specifically in let's say the YouTube
channels and Twitter channels we can easily
open them up to get an understanding of what
they're doing on different social media platforms.
I'm gonna go ahead and open all of these up.
Store where there's one more, that's Instagram.
And now let's take a look at what kind of video
content they publish on all these other platforms.
All right, so I can easily come in here and
I can just scroll down to get an understanding
of what they're doing. This is something that
I noticed on the LinkedIn page as well, so it
looks like they're repurposing their LinkedIn
content to their Facebook content. I'm gonna
keep going. I remember seeing this as well
on their LinkedIn. This is well of their LinkedIn
so looks like they're repurposing the same
content that they're publishing on LinkedIn
to their Facebook page now let's move on to
their Instagram page and I see similar a similar
trend on Instagram as well I'm pretty sure
from the follower count on their Instagram page
that they're primarily publishing on Instagram
and Then they're republishing the content on
their LinkedIn page Let's take a look at this
to make sure. So this is the same content in their
instagram page as well. You may see this trend for, for a
lot of competitors that you analyze. This was also published
on their, on their LinkedIn. This is a re share of their LinkedIn.
Sorry re share of their blog post. Then we have blog
post again. This is a customer experience story.
So it looks like they're publishing more or less the
same things.
on different social media platforms. And finally,
we go to YouTube. So YouTube is a very good
place to get an understanding of what are events,
what are videos they're publishing. So you
can click on videos in here. And in videos,
you can get a very good understanding of What
they published is that they have something called
BuilderTrend University. That's interesting.
I'm going to click on videos and then Opular
to get an understanding of their best videos.
Less stress and more success. This looks like a VSL
video, like a video sales letter. I could take
a look back just to get an understanding of
what this is.
So that is something that I could add in the
content gap analysis sheet. So I'm going to
move to the specific column where we need to
add stuff about videos that are awareness focused.
So this is awareness focused explainer videos.
I'm going to add that and hyperlink it in here.
Um, that's done. Move on back to YouTube and
try to get an understanding of what other stuff
they do. new web episode series, essential features,
or not very interesting, re-use of episode
series. So this is more of middle of the funnier
content where they're explaining about their
products, solutions, like features and so on.
So not really important, I'm just gonna keep
looking at specific formats where they're generating
awareness about their product. These are all
features, manage all product videos. Okay, this
is again, looks like a video, interesting video
about them, so let's take a look at that. Does
your project schedule look like this? Are documents
hard to find and fill their trunk and straight
line your jobs from day one to the track with
reduced risks with detailed bumps and impressed
clients by keeping them informed. That's project
management done. So this is more like
video sales letter that they have, but this
is also focused on awareness,
but let's take a look
at the content sheet and let me include this
one as in there. So I'm gonna add this as a
VSL or a video sales letter I'll fill that up for you.
So this is typically that they used to send
the prospects. and generate awareness
So let's go back and let's see.
Okay, they have something called the building
code templates why we love them and why you
should do so the building code I believe that
starting to think that there are a series of
videos.
Part 2 of 5, Product Update, Home Depot Integration,
Quick Win Scan Receipts, Building Code Episode,
okay so this is more like a...
I'm going to search for the building code on
YouTube and try to get an understanding of
more videos. So this seems to be the building
code podcast and Let's see the plainness. So
here we can see, okay, it looks like this is
the podcast that they upload on YouTube and
they're generating a lot of awareness using
this. So this is a perfect example of what
we can add to the awareness video stage. So
I'm just going to add the building code
video podcast series. Right? And I am going
to hyperlink that to this playlist that I just
found with all the videos of it. All right?
Notice how you can come across really good
content formats that they're using that are
generating awareness for them. Now let's move
on to the in-depth blog post. So we already
took a look at the website, and we came across
a bunch of blog posts that they're using to
generate awareness on the website. So this
one, for example, is about how to track construction
and make it easier. And this is an in-depth
blog post that talks about how BuilderTrend.
allows them to do it. So I am going to include
this one in here. I'm gonna paste the title
and I'm gonna copy the URL and hyperlink it.
All right, we're done with that. And I'm gonna
keep looking at the other ones I found. So
this is the other blog post that we found earlier.
It's about construction materials management
best practices. Again, see this is a short blog
post and not really in depth. This one is a
bit more in depth, stop using construction workers,
but again, not in depth as in depth as a guide.
I'm going to close that off. How to manage and
improve construction cash flow. Okay, look
at this. This is more in depth with a lot of
helpful stuff in the yard. They've included
lead magnets. Again, this is something that
I would include in in-depth videos that talks
about like how to strategy actionable walkthroughs
and so on. All right. So I'm going to copy
paste the topic in here. And I'm going to hyperlink
it to the URL of the blog post. Alright, we're
done with that.