So in this video, I'm going to walk
you through a structured process to
analyze and document what we're already
doing with our new content strategy.
So before you start executing the
work and filling out the existing
content analysis sheet, which we use
in this step, make sure you have your
website, your social media profiles,
and all the sales and marketing for
collaterals you may have published
online publicly with you so that it is
easier for you to complete this quickly.
If you're not sure where everything
is, just watch the video once for
you, and then reach up to your team,
get everything we've talked about in
the video, and then start to work.
This analysis will take about two
hours in total to complete, fully
including watching the training.
Now let's jump into it.
So this is the existing
content analysis sheet.
So just like the competitor analysis
sheet, we already have TOFU, MOFU, and
BOFU sections that we need to fill out.
And all we need to do is take a look
at our existing website and our social
media platforms and the key profiles
and understand what type of content
we are already publishing and just
document them here so that we can
easily compare them to our competitors.
Now, how do we go about doing this?
So the first thing I would do
is I would go to the website.
I would take a look at the blog
if we have a blog and so on.
So this must be there in the
header section, the dropdowns of
the header or in the footer links.
So we do have a blog, we do have.
Case studies and so on.
So I've opened them up in new
labs and at the same time we
also have social media profiles.
So we have LinkedIn, Facebook,
YouTube, and Instagram, and
I've opened all of them here.
And this is the key
profile that we can find.
You will know like who the key
profiles are, who are actively
creating content on LinkedIn.
You can just ask your team if you're not
familiar with who does it, but otherwise.
These key profiles would be actively
publishing content on LinkedIn.
Those are the only profiles you should
be analyzing and then the company page
with all the posts on the company page.
So just come to the company page,
click on posts and then all and
you'll be able to find all of the
posts that they're publishing.
And now what we're going to do is
we are going to go through each
of these sections one by one.
So TOFU, we have blog posts,
LinkedIn posts and videos and stuff.
So we need to take a look at these.
And we need to link them over here.
So I'm going to go about
and do that quickly.
So the first thing we need to look at
is awareness focus blog posts, so that
short form awareness focus pieces.
So let's take a look at blog posts.
So we already have the blog in here.
So let's just take the blog and in
the blog, we have a bunch of posts.
So I'm just going to open these up in
new tabs just to understand what they are
about, how in depth they are, et cetera.
I'm going to open all of them.
You don't need to open all of them
always, but it's good to take,
spend some time and take a look.
These only seem to be so many.
So yeah, I think we have more so
I can take a look at these just
to understand a general view.
If you go through like 20 of the posts,
you should get an understanding of
different types of blog posts they publish
and what they're about.
So.
I'm just going to open them.
I think we have enough.
So I'm just going to quickly go
through each of these and try to get an
understanding of how these blog posts are.
Take a look at this one.
So this one is quite short.
So I'm going to include
this in this section.
I'm going to close it off and
I'm going to include it in here.
So I'm just going to enter the
name and we need to hyperlink it.
So I'm going to copy this
URL and close that tab.
I'm going to move on and
hyperlink it there, right?
That's it.
And then we have let's just
move YouTube towards the end.
Then we have a digital future
for the infrastructure industry.
So this is more like awareness
focus, again, very short form.
There's links to something, just links
to the image and not properly optimized.
And there is a demo CD at the end as well.
So I'm just going to go through these.
I'm just going to find some, some ones
that I find that I think are good.
Maximum benefits from
construction project management,
construction management software.
So again, this is like a it's more the
awareness focus and, but it's very short
without a lot of detail in it or images
and illustrations in it construction
industry's next step mobile technology.
So this is good.
This is again an awareness focused piece.
I'm going to take this.
I'm just looking for like
different types of content.
We've already added a
generic blog post in there.
Implications of the
industry, again, very short.
Data visualization and its impact
on construction project management.
Okay, that's not bad.
This is a bit more longer,
but still quite shallow.
So maybe this is an
example that I would add.
I close all of these tabs
that I already reviewed.
Go back.
The link.
Make sure you always add
the headlines and the links.
So that it's easy to understand what
it's about, and you can check the link
if you need more information later on.
This one is about five ways in which BIM,
Building Infrastructure Modeling, has
transformed the construction industry.
Again, this is a good example.
It's a shallow piece, but I
think it's bit value adding
could be an interesting topic.
So I'm gonna include that in here.
I'm gonna get the link, and
I'm gonna paste it in here.
Effective allocation using
contract management system.
So I guess this is a
feature that they have.
Mobilize and demobilize
full kitting module.
I guess this is a module inside
their inside their software.
Trace cost full kitting module, yeah.
So, that is something
inside their software.
Again, not very interesting.
Not like awareness focused.
Five ways technology can solve
common construction problems.
Again, this is like an
awareness focused piece.
But I'm going to keep managing the
rest of the construction industry's
digital transformation role.
Why should construction technology be
required for bidding and project planning?
Top 10 construction industry trends.
Yeah, trends articles are always
stuff that people commonly use.
So I'm going to pick that.
I'm going to go here.
I'm going to add that in there.
And I'm going to hyperlink it.
All right.
So I'm just going to
close all of these off.
How technology is increasing
productivity in construction industry.
Oh, interesting.
They've created a video about this.
Let's take a look at the video.
So this is more like a
slide video with just music.
So they just insert some music in this.
And they've just added the text in there.
So I guess they repurpose it from
the blog post content itself.
Drones.
Yep, they repurpose it from
the blog post content itself.
Okay, maybe it's a bit
more detailed than that.
But, they've created a video
out of just music and text.
Cool.
Okay.
Data brick road to efficiency.
This is a bit more detailed,
but it's still not big enough to
show cover like in depth or to
qualify as an in depth article.
So this is also just like a slide video.
So I'm not going to look at that.
RP in the construction industry.
No, not a very disruptive title.
Golden threads that
connect us to the world.
Lack of visibility.
Yeah, still not very good enough.
Alright, I think we're
about done with TOFU.
And one thing I like to do after I
fill this out is, fill out how do I
think this helps your target audience.
So, how do I feel these posts
help our target audience.
So, I'm gonna merge all of
these, because I have the same
opinion about all of these.
So these are,
these are quick reads on various topics.
Related to the construction niche, but
not very helpful to our target audience.
So don't always need to mention,
like have the opinion that this
does help our target audience.
You can also disagree with it.
If they're not helpful, you can
just mention that over here.
All right.
So I don't think this is a very helpful
content piece for target audience, so
I'm just going to mention that over here.
Do you wish to creating
this gutted format?
Again you can if these are different
content formats, so there's some
like different versions of blog
posts and stuff like that, you can
include them over here, but most
of these are in the same category.
So I'm just going to merge all of these
and I'm going to enter a no over here
because I don't honestly feel that this
adds a lot of value, this type of content.
So I'm going to add a no and I'm
going to move on to the next one.
So the next one is LinkedIn posts,
awareness, focus, viral news and trends.
All right.
So now let's jump to
LinkedIn and let's see like.
What are they doing that
are awareness focused?
So this one is about Hub
of Construction Expo.
Okay, they attended an event and
this is a post about that one.
So this is something that we can include.
This is a company page post.
So this is about, how would I name this?
This is something I would
name as event, event news.
All right, and I would
hyperlink that post.
Link in here and I'm done and I'm
going to move on to the next one.
How are you managing
your invoices right away?
Yeah, it's more of like project financial.
It takes up things for the better.
We have some reposts on this.
Okay.
It's not visible yet.
Dynastrace lost SAP store.
Okay.
This is like a collaboration
with SAP, a new integration.
So this is like a product feature update.
So I'm gonna copy that.
The product feature
updates come more in BOFU.
And stuff like that.
Or in here.
So I'm not gonna get
into that at this stage.
I'm just gonna keep going down
and see what else they do.
Again, this is an events news post.
Hmm,
this is like, there are critical injuries.
So, what I'm trying to understand
is, are there awareness focus posts.
Now, awareness focus posts are not
really about the product or the service
or they're not salesy they're not very
in depth, they're just used to generate
awareness for the trace cost brand or the
key profile personal brand on LinkedIn.
All right.
So, I'm just going to go through
the company page posts first.
Top 10 global construction
projects in 2023.
Okay.
This one is not bad.
Good engagement as well.
Mumbai International Airport.
Okay.
I like this one.
So I'm just going to copy top 10
construction projects in here, and
I'm going to hyperlink to that post
by copying the link in here done.
So that's good.
This is more like product
feature and stuff like that.
So,
okay.
This is like a, it's like a
testimonial compilations like post.
So this is more bottom of
the funnel because we have
testimonials in here, I guess.
We have testimony videos
and stuff in here.
So what I would do is I could copy this
there, but I'm going to keep it like this.
I'm going to get to it only at that stage.
All right.
So construction projects.
Okay.
This is like a news post about
Canada's national housing policy.
Construction is expensive today.
It's just 2 X blah, blah, blah.
They do mention resource in the post.
Constituent projects in your TLO
should budgets and timelines.
How do we stop this?
Okay, not, not a lot of engagement.
KPMG report.
Okay, so this is kind of
like a KPMG report summary,
something like that, right?
So that is a good one.
It's not really about
summary of KPMG, right?
I'm going to copy that, copy the link
to the post and that that's done.
Yeah.
So these, these are the kind of posts that
we mean by TOFU a wireless focus post.
So
yeah, Spain.
Okay.
They're adding pictures at
the end of all the posts.
Not bad.
They've gotten some engagement as well.
Okay.
This is more like a
customer experience story.
You see this?
Before TraceCast.
So they started using
TraceCast and they reduced it.
So it's not really TOFU content.
I'm going to keep going.
You can add it to the sheet at
this stage, like in that section.
But I want to go about this in a
structured fashion, because otherwise
it could become a bit confusing.
So, there's a trace cost.
This is more, not again, TOFU.
Canadian economy and construction.
So this is more like an
awareness focus piece.
So I would mention this
as Canadian economy,
Just to get like a fair
idea about the topic.
All right.
Now I need to give, what do you
think about, how do you think I helps
this helps your target audience.
So I could enter something
along the lines of this
helps keep my audience on LinkedIn
engaged with niche content.
Updates.
All right.
So that's how I think it helps it.
Do you wish to continue
creating this content format?
Yes, I do.
Because I do think it helps
with our LinkedIn efforts.
And it generates engagement.
But not a lot of engagement.
So I'm not like a huge fan
of this content format.
I think there needs to be
more in depth stuff as well.
Most of this content is just TOFU content.
All right.
So I'm going to include yes.
And now we need to talk about videos.
So videos are awareness focused,
LinkedIn, YouTube, Instagram, etc.
So and we only need to enter four of them.
So I've only like done the company
profiles for most of the niches.
Most of your niches, most of the
industries that you're targeting.
The most of the content will be
published from the company page itself.
In case there are key profiles,
you can include content.
So in this case it's Prabh who
publishes most of the content.
Prabh has a good following.
He's about 16, 000
followers, blah, blah, blah.
He's publishing content actively.
So he's publishing like say almost
every single day except weekends.
But he does get a bit
of engagement as well.
So he's publishing
different types of content.
Carousel.
So these are all good
examples of TOFU content.
So you could include them over here.
If you want to include additional content
pieces, all you need to do is just add
a new role below this and just fill
that out with this post, for example.
So it's about how in Iraqi British
architect pulled off the impossible.
So this is the kind of like a news post.
I'm sorry.
I'm going to include it as a slide post
or carousel just to add some context.
All right.
So same question that we need to answer.
This helps keep my audience
on LinkedIn, engage the niche
content, updates and trends.
And carousels seem to be getting good
engagement as well on his profile.
So I would say it's a
good idea to publish this.
The seven deadliest construction
projects in the world.
These are interesting topics.
I would, I would continue publishing
them and do you wish to continue
creating this content format?
Of course, I do think the
content is interesting.
The audience, I am seeing engagements.
You should be taking a look at the numbers
on your profile or on your company page
when you evaluate the TOFU content.
All right.
And now we are moving back to,
let me just merge these as well.
And now we are moving back
to videos, awareness, focus,
LinkedIn, YouTube, Instagram rings.
So let's take a look
at the other platforms.
First we have Facebook we
do have some videos in here.
So record progress that
works on a construction site.
So these are more like construction
reporting and stuff like that.
So it's like a slide video with music
that you create using some tool and
you enter some text into it and so on.
So what I'm going to do is I'm
going to add a link to that.
And I'm going to say construction.
importance of construction reporting.
Okay.
And this is a slide video.
So I want to
stretch this out a bit so
that it's easier to see.
And I'm going to link to that
post, which is a Facebook video.
Now let's go back to
Facebook and keep going.
If we can see any other
type of videos in here.
So again incident free operation site.
Oh, okay, that's a big number.
But, yeah Construction safety,
importance of construction safety.
But it's the same slide in blue.
Not very different,
just a different topic.
This is also a slide video, so I think
they publish a lot of slide videos.
Now let's go to YouTube and Instagram.
So we have YouTube and Instagram
here and you can see like all posts
in here, but if you click on real
specifically, you can see videos that
they're publishing and they have.
Okay.
They're repurposing the content
from Facebook to Instagram and
let's take a look at the next one.
The other one incident struggling
with contract management.
Again, it's a slide video.
Let's take a look at this one
productive while saving cost.
Okay.
All of these are slide videos.
So we know now know that there.
We are repurposing content from one
platform to the other platforms.
Again, in your case, you will
already know these things.
But because this is a client, I'm
just analyzing the other profiles.
Cool.
Now we have Instagram.
Let's take a look at
YouTube, YouTube, same thing.
They are just repurposing the content.
I think the primarily
creating it for YouTube.
And then they're repurposing it
for other social media platforms.
All right.
But these are good examples
of awareness focused content.
I'm not really like, I don't really
like them a lot, but these are good
examples of awareness focused content.
Now let's take a quick look at all the
other types of content they're posting.
All of these are short,
short video, short videos.
I can see the time codes over here.
You see the time times over
here, the durations of the video,
I can see the video durations
of the video in this corner.
So I'm just going through
them and trying to understand.
If all of them are videos like these,
okay, this one seems to be a bit longer.
Let's take a look at what that is.
So this is inventive.
So he's speaking at an event.
That's what's happening over here.
It's facing at the Nick Mark conference.
And I guess this is his
presentation during the event.
And it's somebody else at the company.
Okay.
A bit of engagement, not
many likes, very few views.
And the entire channel
is not performing well.
It's just publishing a bit of content.
So let's take a look at
what we can do over here.
Okay, so this is more like pain
points in the industry and then how
trace cost helps them with that.
Pain points in the industry, features
of trace cost, our journey so far.
Okay, so again, this is
awareness focused content.
So these are like what
would you call this?
These are, these are more like, I
would just say NICMAR conference.
conference speech.
All right I would enter
the name of the person.
So I know the name of the person
because we work with them.
But in your case, it'll be a team member.
So you can just include that.
Or you can ask around about who it is.
So his name is Shailendra Pennywall.
So I'm gonna include that over here.
And then let's add some stuff from
LinkedIn and Instagram as well.
So Facebook, Instagram.
YouTube stuff.
Other stuff is mostly the same.
I don't think those are good examples.
So let me look at LinkedIn.
If they publish any videos on LinkedIn.
Now they don't publish any
video on the key profile.
Let's see the company page.
See if they publish something over there.
We can specifically look for
videos if you click on this.
So these are four months ago.
Again, the same thing.
It's the same thing
that they're publishing.
But that is getting some engagement.
Okay, that's interesting.
Hmm.
Do you see delay?
Is it feeling stuck?
Okay, so
copy the link to the post.
Yeah, too many hashtags.
Not very optimized for LinkedIn either.
So, I'm going to include that.
Say, budgeting and construction.
This is a LinkedIn video.
So, but repurposed.
Right?
I'm going to link that.
I'm not going to add
more examples over here.
I think slide videos are a good
idea, but they're not very good
to generate engagement because
again, there's slide videos.
And I think there needs to be a person
in the video speaking, or it needs to be
a really valuable actionable tutorial or
something for it to be a good slide video.
So this is not a format
that I'm very interested in.
So I'm going to not going to merge
these, I'm going to enter like
separate comments for each of these.
So this one, for example importance
of construction reporting.
I'm going to say something along
the lines of it gives a big
overview on pay pounds
or issues in the niche.
All right.
So that's what it does.
But not very useful or insightful
for our target audience.
Now, why is it not very useful and
interesting for target audience?
Because think about a target audience,
a target audience of face cost the
company that we are analyzing, our
founders and CEOs of companies.
So they don't get like a lot
of value from doing this.
We can generate some brand awareness,
but that will be like, it is more
interesting to say people who are in
other niches who would be interested
in understanding that reconstruction
has a problem like this, right?
But construction managers are already
aware that this problem exists, and
this video is too shallow of a topic to
explain, like, how it actually helps.
So if there's, like, a template or, like,
showing them actually how to how to, like,
budget properly then this would have been
helpful, but it's not, like, in depth
enough to explain how to budget properly.
It's just saying that budgeting
is a problem, and with the
right tools, you can solve it.
But and then we're just
pitching trace cost.
Not really very interesting.
So I'm gonna say not very useful
or insightful for target audience.
Now I have the same opinion
about budgeting and construction.
So I'm gonna move this a little bit up.
Okay, we can't merge that.
So I'm just gonna copy
paste this over here.
And this one is something this
content is more about painpoints
And how trace call solves that.
But speeches at conferences
that add actionable value.
That add actionable value.
And basically end up more in depth.
Could be a good fit.
All right.
So I've just mentioned that,
and I'm gonna wrap it around so
that the whole thing, engineers.
Cool.
So now do you wish to create,
continue creating this content format?
This one is obviously, no, I
don't think it makes sense.
This one?
Yes, because I think speeches
can add a lot of value.
There should be a bunch of speeches.
They also recently attended conferences,
so I think if they've created some
content that that is something we can use.
Budgeting and construction LinkedIn
repurpose from other channels.
Again, I don't think that alternative
value it's too shallow, so I'm
going to mention no over here.
All right.
Now let's take a look
at in depth blog posts.
So what do we look at in depth blog posts?
No, I already reviewed the blog.
I know that we don't have
any in depth blog posts.
So this is a section
that we have to start.
I'm just going to add a yes
over here because I think.
Adding more in depth content is important.
Strategy and how to focus LinkedIn posts.
So this is something that
we have to take a look at.
So let's take a look at
LinkedIn and see if they focus
on the strategy stuff, right?
So we've already reviewed the
content on the company page.
I didn't come across any in depth stuff.
I did come across some BOFU content,
bottom of the funnel content,
like testimonials and stuff.
But not much stuff is about...
Okay, I published an article.
Let's take a look at that article.
Streamlining construction process.
Oh no, again, too shallow, too shallow.
You see, it's too small.
So not very big.
I don't think there is
much MOFU content in here.
Let's take a look at this one.
Monitor productivity of assets
in project execution article.
No, it's not very in depth enough
to deliver like actionable value.
Now let's take a look at the
key profiles and see if they
are doing something over there.
That is MOFU.
This is TOFU, Top of the Funnel.
This is also Top of the Funnel.
This is an event news post.
This is again, Top of the Funnel.
Statistics, Top of the Funnel.
Top of the Funnel.
Construction Backlog.
Top of the News or Trend article.
Provide a safe environment.
How can construction work?
Okay, so rather than talk about, like,
say, how can you solve the problem of,
like, Work related debts because of
environmental heat exposure, like what
are some things that you can do about it.
It's not getting into
the in depth part of it.
It's just talking about it.
This problem exists and
you need to do something.
Construction companies must
continuously innovate, right?
It's not talking about
how to solve the problem.
So the how to part of it will be the
MoFo content, but that is not there.
So I'm just going to keep going and see if
we have any middle of the funnel content.
Industries.
No, nothing.
So I'm going to go back
and just enter it as yes.
There are not many there's
not much more for content.
And then I'm going to
just merge these as well.
And at nil, we don't have any, right.
And now we have strategy and
how to focus LinkedIn posts.
No, we already look at blog
post strategy and how to focus
LinkedIn posts are also missing.
So I'm going to mark that as nil as well.
Video strategy, educational
focus, YouTube, Instagram related
to the service or product.
Again, that is also missing.
We have a lot of more
content missing for this.
Front.
So white papers.
That is something we can look at.
Now let's take a look at the website
and see if there are any white papers.
I'm going to close off the blog posts.
The Facebook sorry, Facebook stuff.
We may need to look at later.
So keep it open.
But let's take a look at, okay,
we have case studies, we have
demos, but do we have white papers?
Okay, let's take a look at this.
Investor, case studies,
about us, contacts.
Okay.
So you will be familiar, you'll
be aware of like what is existing
internally if you do this analysis
yourself, but here's the thing.
Sometimes white papers, etc, may not be
published internally, but then you may
have them like stored in a drive, etc,
even if it's not published on the website.
So this is the drive where we've stored
all of the the decks and the pitch
decks and some case study decks and some
product overview decks and, and stuff
like that that we send to clients and
prospects, but most of these are about
The product as opposed to white papers
that focus on a specific topic, say,
we do have one about AI and reality,
but this one is also about trace cause.
It's not very in depth, doesn't
fit the criteria for white paper.
So the white paper should ideally be
like, say, 90 over nine pages at least.
Should have some good content about it in
it that is not really focused on the on
the product of the service that we offer.
We can mention the product of the
service that we offer at the end
of the white paper, but ideally
the start shouldn't be about it.
It should be an interesting lead magnet
that users in your industry can download
that they would be interested in.
It should be an interesting topic and
so on, but none of these are about it.
All of these are product decks, so we
don't really have any white papers.
So what I would do is go back and,
and fill that as nil out as well.
So I'm going to fill white
papers as nil as well.
EBooks, same criteria as eBooks.
We don't have eBooks on this topic.
We do have some case studies and
product text, but not really eBooks.
Webinars and conferences.
Yes, we do have webinars.
Okay.
That's a good one.
So I know for a fact that they don't have
any webinars, but if in case you want to
see if we've published any webinars in
the past and you're not familiar with it,
you can just Google webinars and no, these
are all, all other stuff panel discussion,
CIOL, and for some reason, this one
turned up, let's see if we have webinars
somewhere over here, it's a different
website, so not really an owned webinar.
So I don't think we have
webinars for that fact.
So webinars are also a no no.
We don't have webinars yet.
So that is something we should be doing.
Again, my opinion in all of these is
that we should have it because more for
content is as important as TOFU content.
We do have a lot of TOFU content,
but we don't have more for content.
All right.
Podcasts.
No, I know for a fact that we
don't have a podcast, so we
can mention that as no as well.
So I just can drag this down to save time.
Newsletters.
I know for a fact that we
don't have a newsletter, but
you can check on the website.
Most newsletters will be there on
the website and you can check that
and see if there is a newsletter.
If it's a LinkedIn newsletter.
So LinkedIn is a
newsletter feature as well.
And if you go in here on the profile and
click on articles, you should be able
to see if they are publishing articles.
So they seem to have some article, but
when we go on the article page, there
should be a newsletter icon over here.
There should be a newsletter
icon somewhere over here.
It should add the name of the
newsletter in here, but that is missing.
Now, let me give you an example
of what it will look like if
it is a newsletter on LinkedIn.
Okay.
I want you to cut out the portion
where I'm mentioning newsletters.
So I'm going to come back here and
start all over again about newsletters.
So for newsletters, I know for a
fact that okay, start from here.
All right.
So for newsletters, I know for a
fact that we don't have newsletters.
I've marked it as nil and
yes, but here's the thing.
You can search whether you
have a newsletter on LinkedIn
or on on the website.
Best way is to just ask your team.
So you just go ahead and do that.
If you want to check on the profiles of
the key profiles just come to the profile
of the person you're analyzing the key
profile you're analyzing and come to the
activity section and you should be able to
see if they have a newsletter over here.
So it should look like
it should look like this.
So they have a newsletter, the newsletter
will be named over here, the subscribers
and like the recent posts in the,
in the newsletter, but if there's no
newsletter, it will show like this, there
won't be a newsletter tab over here.
So this person does not have a newsletter.
So we're going to move on.
Now, we do have case studies.
We do have case studies
published on the website.
As well as the platform.
So the case studies have
not been published actively.
So let's take a look at the different
case studies that they have.
So they have a JMC case study.
That is quite good.
I'm not very in depth, but
they do have a JMC case study.
So I'm going to link to that.
Alright, I'm going to move
on to the next newsletter.
So the next one is QMS.
So, okay, so I guess they've used a
single slide to explain all the different.
features of the product.
All right.
Is the other one is also a GMC case study.
Cool.
Let me look at the drive folder
as well to understand if they
have any other case studies.
So I just went through the files
in the drive and even there we
have only the GMC case studies.
It looks like not many case studies,
but case studies are really good.
You need to have case studies actively.
Let's look at this folder as well.
I can easily see that I've already gone
through them, but again, I can see that
they don't have many other case studies.
So we're going to move back and these are
good, but they need more case studies.
So I'm going to link to these anyway,
EHS, Employee Health and Management
System, so that we have it in one
place GMC Employee Health and Safety,
all right.
And close that off.
We have DPR Daily Progress Reporting.
So that's GMC Daily Progress Reporting.
Contracts Management System.
Alright, I've linked all of them in here.
And the first one was it is all GMC.
So let's take a look at what
the first one was again.
Yeah, it's the same thing.
So I'm just going to delete this.
And how do you think this
helps our target audience now?
From my perspective, it gives
them an idea about the feature
and it's the same for all of them.
So that is the pain points.
It gives them an idea of the pain points.
It provides a solution and it shows what
a solution is and what the impacts are.
So this is what I would do.
And they've done it with
a company called GMC.
All right.
So it's the same one
for all three of them.
So I'm going to merge the cells, and I'm
going to say it presents the challenges,
the solutions, and then presents our
solution, and then shows stats or reports
on how The solution helps the audience.
I would like to be a bit more detailed.
It should be a bit more
detailed and with lesser text.
That's my opinion on it.
But it can be done.
But it is useful.
Because it helps them understand
how the product Perfect.
Help them with similar, similar case.
Alright.
And I've done that.
Now I'm gonna mark this, this.
And now would you wish to continue
creating this content format?
Heck yeah.
I think we need more case studies.
I could mention that feedback
over here but we need more case
studies from different clients.
Right.
We need more case studies
from different clients.
I've included that in here and
now we have testimonial videos.
So, we don't have testimonial
videos, we already took a look at
all the content that they have.
Most of the content that they
have, but they're publishing from
some testimonial images and so on.
We came across like a few of
them, like one of this is this.
So this one, for example is
about why can't I copy this post?
Okay.
That's really hard.
It's a bit weird, but sometimes Facebook
doesn't allow you to send stuff.
So the only way to get the link is to
share it to somebody in your contacts.
So I'm just going to send it
to one of my own profiles.
And what that will do is it will
bring up the message in the chat and
you can, then you can copy the link
address and then paste it in the sheet.
It's a bit of a workaround around it,
but this is not really a testimony video.
This is more like an image post.
Testimonial.
There aren't any testimonial
videos for this line.
So I know for a fact.
I work with them, but
that is one testimonial.
And then there's one more testimonial
that we came across, which is this one.
So the same thing we are going
to share it to messenger.
And I'm going to send it to.
So you can send it to anybody, but it
should come it up, come up in here.
And then after it comes up in the
inbox, you can copy the link address.
Sorry, copy the link address
and then go back here.
And then include the, this is
also a testimonial image post.
And the name of the company
can also be included.
This is Broadcast Engineering Consultants.
Right, so Broadcast
Engineering Consultants.
That's the name of the company.
I'd like to mention that in there
and let's add the name of the
company as well here as well.
So, these guys are called,
what is this called?
JMC projects.
Okay.
This is the JMC guys.
So link address oops, done.
So
we have two testimonials.
Of course we would like.
to create more testimonials.
So what I'm going to do is I'm going
to drag them, I'm going to merge it and
add a single comment for all of them.
And the comment is that we need more
testimonial videos rather than images.
And we need more of them.
Okay?
Now do you wish to continue
creating this content format?
Heck yeah.
I want to create way more
of this content format.
Because case studies and
testimonials are very important.
Demos, yes, we do have a demo.
We had linked to it somewhere over here.
So this is the page for the demo.
So all we need to do is link it over here.
We don't have like more
categories or types of demos.
Free consultations, I guess the demo
qualifies as a free consultation.
So you just keep that over there.
Competitive comparisons.
So competitive comparisons compare
trace cost to some other product.
But TraceCost doesn't seem to have it.
We're not comparing
ourselves to other products.
It should have been visible
on the blog otherwise.
But what I will do if you want to
find competitive comparisons is
go to the go to the search bar and
search for site colon our website.
So that our website is TraceCost.
com.
Then what I would do is I would
enter something like this.
TraceCost versus.
So.
This is the common criteria common,
like, say, title of, of topics of
the blog post that we publish when
we do a competitive comparison.
So you can search that, but I know
already that we don't have competitive
comparisons, so that is also something
that we should start focusing on.
So I'm just gonna add it as nil
right now because we don't have it.
So I'm gonna copy that and I'm
gonna come in here and add.
NIL for this and NIL for this.
All right.
Regarding this, I'm just
going to enter how it helps.
It helps users in the constructed space
evaluate our product
before close.
That's the purpose of a demo, right?
All right we're gonna
move to customer stories.
We do have customer experience stories.
So we took a look at LinkedIn
and we came across a few customer
experience stories in the past.
So let's go through LinkedIn and
spot that customer experience story.
Where we found that Okay, not this one.
Was it in the user profile content?
I think it was in the
user profile content.
So I'm going to switch to the
user profile, click on posts.
And see where it is.
Okay, this is not, it's not this,
it's not this, it's not this,
it's not this, it's not this.
Okay, not this either.
There was a post where they
said before trees cost.
So we're trying to spot that
specific one must unpause the video.
So this is the post.
This is our customer experience story.
But we're not naming customers, so
we should ideally be naming them.
But I'm going to link this in there.
This is the only customer
experience story that we have.
Just to be clear, the difference between
customer experience stories and I think
this one is about reducing Reducing.
Alright, so the difference between Case
studies and customer experience stories
is that case studies are more about
who the, who the, who the case studies
about introduction, introducing them,
then we have the problem that if they
were facing the solution we provided
for them and what results we generated.
So that is the the format
of, of a case study.
Customer experience stories are
about the experience of the customer,
ideally from their point of view.
So.
This is how, this is the
problem that we're facing.
This is how they found TraceCost or like
contacted Prubb or like somebody at,
at TraceCost was working at TraceCost.
This is how the initial conversation went.
This is why they converted.
And this is what they did.
These are the challenges that they
faced even after buying the product
and this is how we help them.
So it's more about a perspective
of the interaction with the company
from the customer's point of view.
So these how do you think this
helps your target audiences?
I think this helps them understand
how the customer experience will be
like with a real example of a client.
So that's how it helps them.
But we need more examples and stories
with multiple clients.
And we need, and we need what?
And we need
to mention client names, to name clients.
All right, so that's
what I would like to do.
And yes, this is a content format
I would like to continue creating.
Now, we need product walkthroughs.
I'm going to merge all of this.
So that it's easier.
And I'm going to merge these as well.
All right.
Product walkthroughs or explainers.
Yeah, we do have some product
walkthroughs or explainers.
But these are in the drive.
So we do have some stuff
about how TraceCourse improves
construction performance fast.
So this is one example.
I'm going to copy that
and include it in here.
Now we need to link to it.
So I'm going to link.
I add the link as well.
I'm gonna go back and look at
more unlocking value in the
construction technology ecosystem.
This is an example.
I'm not really impressed by the quality
of it, but this is an example, so
I'm going to link to that as well.
Ideally in the BOFU stage when you are
copying it, When you're adding the links,
add the links to everything you can find.
So all the different case studies that
you have all the different testimonial
videos, demos, consultations,
competitive comparisons, customers,
just keep adding rows and include
all of them that are relevant.
So this is a single pager.
This is a case study.
Yeah.
workflow solution.
So this is relevant.
So I would add this one as well.
And I would copy a link
to that one as well.
Copy the link, done.
We don't really have
anything on the website.
I already checked.
But these are the product walkthroughs
and explainers that we have at the moment.
So again, this helps
clients in the same fashion.
I'm going to merge those rows first.
And the way this helps clients
is it gives the clients a good
overview of all the features.
The product.
Now it's common to think it's
easy to think that, okay, some of
these are just irrelevant because
it's obvious as to how this helps
clients or your target audience.
But here's the thing.
This is not just for you
to evaluate or analyze it.
It's also good for the entire
quantity to understand how each
of these content formats that we
use helps our target audience or
doesn't help our target audience or
what we need to improve about it.
So you can include as much details
as you can in this, in this column.
Okay.