In this video, I'm going to walk you
through the content ideation sheet,
where you'll be documenting a lot
of stuff from your own experiences,
struggles, successes, obstacles you
faced, your interests, pain points
in your industry, and your own
insights on your own target audience.
This task is going to take quite a
while because you need to spend at
least 10 hours to fully complete it.
But this step you can choose to do over
the course of a week or two when you
get some time, but maybe you're done.
While filling out the sheet properly,
it'll act as a good source of ideas
for your content team to come up
with content that has your own voice
and your own personality in it.
So they're going to be using
it a lot in the future.
So please make sure you spend some
time on the sheet and fill it out well.
Without further ado, let's jump
into the content ideation sheet.
So this is the content ideation sheet.
What I will do right now is I'll go
through each of these individual sections
and I will fill them out as an example.
But for the sake of this video,
I'm going to be filling them out as
myself for my own company and my own
industry, because it's very difficult.
To understand the exact pain points
that you want to focus on if you're
not working in that industry.
So I'm not going to use the case
study of trace cost, which we
used in the previous videos.
For this video, I'm going to be using
my own personality, my own background,
my own experiences and so on.
If you take a look at this sheet you can
notice that there are different sections.
So there's one section for
who is this content for this.
So this is outlining your different
personas or ideal customer
personas you're focusing on.
What their industry is, what
are the topics they care about,
what the influences, who the
influences in the space are.
There are anecdotal stories.
So these are all about
your own experiences.
So when you may have had a
major life change, so when you
went through a significant life
event, there are stuff about your
background and your tone of voice.
So that's about your date of
birth, where do you currently live?
What's your expertise?
How long have you been an
expert in your field and so on?
And there are problems in industries.
This is more industry focused.
your own interests in the space.
What are the lessons you
learned along the way?
What are the successes you've had so far?
What are the obstacles you face?
So it's a combination of both
industry stuff and your stuff.
Now for the industry stuff, like who this
content is for and what are the problems
in an industry, you can have like one
sheet for all the personal brands that
you're trying to create in your company.
But if you have multiple people in your
team who are creating content actively
and using the content process that we
coach you with in the program, you need
to create duplicates of this sheet.
So the content ideation sheet, you
need to duplicate it multiple times,
rename it and name it, say Alex content
ideation or RD content ideation, et
cetera, so that you have different
sheets for different people on your team.
You can just write like this and duplicate
it and then fill them out yourself.
So this, the section for the
industries can remain the same.
But the stuff on the anecdotal stories And
the background and tone of voice and your
interests, your lessons, your successes,
your obstacles, et cetera, needs to be
filled in separately for each team member
who's creating content on your team.
All right.
Now, the first step, when you get
started with the content ideation
is not to fill in the sheet.
The first step is to go through
the competitive analysis sheet.
I want you to spend at
least one hour on this.
So I want you to go through all
of these links in the sheet.
So if it's linked to the
sheet, go to it, try to get an
understanding of what this is.
So in the sheet, what we've done is
we've analyzed all of our competitors.
So we have five competitors that we've
analyzed in the sheet for this case study.
And we have their website,
their company page, any.
important LinkedIn profiles of key
team members, say the CXOs, VPs,
etc, who are active on LinkedIn.
We have their links to their Instagram,
Facebook, TikTok, YouTube channels, etc.
Then we have examples to individual
content pieces that are LinkedIn
content, the content formats they're
using on LinkedIn, what are the tone of
voice they're using on LinkedIn, etc.
We have top of the funnel content, which
includes short form blog posts, LinkedIn
posts, awareness focused LinkedIn posts.
News, trends, et cetera.
Then we have videos, LinkedIn
posts YouTube videos,
Instagram reels, et cetera.
We have middle of the funnel content,
which are in depth blog posts,
strategy and how to focus LinkedIn
posts, video strategies, reach
strategy focused videos, white papers,
e books, webinars, conferences,
podcasts, newsletters, et cetera.
And we have bottom of the funnel
content, which is case studies, testimony
videos, demos, free consultations,
competitive comparisons, customer
experience stories, and product
walkthrough videos or explainer videos.
And we have a summary of
each of these competitors.
What I want you to do is you need to gain
in some inspiration about this industry.
So you fill out the
content addition sheet.
That is the best way to do it.
So what I want you to do is go through the
entire competitor analysis sheet, open all
of these links, just skim through them.
It'll take like a minimum of a
maximum of like 10 seconds to just go
through each of these content pieces.
I don't want you to consume
them or read them through.
Just go through them and understand
what content topics and what formats
each of these competitors are using.
All right, the next step after you've
spent at least one hour on, like,
say, just going through all of the
content, you don't necessarily need
to spend one hour, but you need to
take a look at all of the links of
the sheet for all of the competitors.
But after you're done with
that, go to the existing content
analysis sheet and review it.
Take a look at it.
Go through each of these
links and see like what type
of content you are creating.
And then finally take a look at the
gap identification sheet and see
like, which, where do we have gaps?
So all of these marked as yes,
are the gaps that we have.
What gaps mean is
competitors are doing it.
We want to do it or we could
be doing it right now as well.
But we want to create content
with the ones that there are gaps.
We want to be actively
creating this content format.
All right.
So these are marked as yes.
Now we're not making any decisions on
which content formats or which topics
you're creating content on at this point.
This is just so that you internalize the
idea that, okay, these are the pieces
that they need to get inspiration from.
So you will gain inspiration from
the content linked in here and this
will help you a lot when you fill
out the content evaluation sheet.
All right.
So the first step, you go
through the step by step.
You need to spend at least two hours
separately for filling out the sheet.
Ideally, you need to be filling out all
sections or including some detail in all
of these sections so that your content
team understands a bit more about your
personality, what your tone of voice.
Your background experiences that you've
had, the struggles, et cetera, as well
as some things about the pain points in
the industry and who this content is for.
All right.
And now I'm going to go ahead and
fill this sheet out one by one.
And what I'm going to do is I'm
going to fill this in my perspective.
I'm not going to fill
out the entire sheet.
I'm going to fill out, let's say,
a couple of rows for each of these
sections so that you understand
how to fill this out properly.
Now, with that said, I'm going to go
ahead and fill this out one by one.
So the first section is for
who is this content for?
So I'm going to fill out
like one of our personas.
So one of our personas is
SaaS founders and CHOs.
All right.
So the industry that I want to focus
on right now is assume I'm focusing
on Texas, but within Texas, like what
type of SAS do I want to focus on?
So what I want to ideally focus on
at the moment is SAS in the VC space.
So SAS in the VC space.
So that's again, my own opinion, my
own persona, it will be very different
for you, but I'm just doing it because
that is what I want to focus on.
So the topics that they want
to care about is the economy.
So I'm just going to add like a
list of like stuff that from the
top of my mind, I don't need to
do a lot of research on those.
These are just things
from the top of mind.
They focus on the economy, they focus
on hiring strategy is important for
them, they focus on fundraising,
topics like fundraising, they
focus on venture funding use.
So that is something that they
keep abreast of all the time.
They focus on startup hubs, they focus
on startup training or accelerator.
So you get where I'm going with this.
So in my opinion, what are the
topics that this person cares about?
So that's what I'm including in here.
I think this is enough.
You can include more.
You can go, you can
spend some time on this.
Now the next one would be to include
some influencers in the space.
Now these are influencers that I've heard
about that I follow, that I know about.
It could be brands or it could
be people that I can follow.
So I know a bunch of influencers
in the space, say for
example, Ganymede and Chuck.
is an influencer that I tend
to follow in this space.
Tiger Global is another influencer
that I tend to follow in this space.
And then after Tiger Global, we have
Y Combinator, which is one of the
largest accelerators in the world.
It produces a lot of good content.
I consume it as well.
Belling is a raw, raw generator.
And we also have Google for Startups.
Google for Startups also
pushes out a lot of content.
And then we have Startup
Weekend is a good one.
But other than Startup Weekend,
I think Techstars is a good brand
that I would like to follow.
These are all supposed
to act as inspiration.
Now, what I will do is I will hyperlink
this with the links, the profiles.
So if it is people like Gary Vaynerchuk,
I can link to their profiles.
If it is companies, I will
link to their company pages.
So I'm going to go ahead
and do that right now.
So I've included the links to all of them.
Of course there can be better examples.
You will have better examples as well, but
these tend to be the ones that I follow.
I constantly consume the content.
So I will include them in here.
You can do some additional research
if you're not familiar with good
influencers, or if you want to.
Only include good influences
you can gain inspiration from,
you can go ahead and do that.
But ideally, these need to be good
examples of people who are doing a very
good job of creating content in the space.
And then we move on to anecdotal stories.
Anecdotal stories are all
about your experiences.
Say for example, you
had a major life change.
So these are all examples of
what you see over here are
all example template content.
So you started a new job into soul
crushing, just a skydiving instructor.
You realize that you're afraid of heights
and didn't like this line of work.
Good after a few days felt a lot better.
You had to write out your resignation
after only two hours of employment.
So we have different sections in here.
So we have a section for, say, a short
and quick summary about the experience, a
background info, a two to three sentence
elaboration, the moments of highest
drama, how did it make you feel, how did
it make others feel, what does it make
you realize, what is the lesson learned.
Over time, when you fill this
out, this will give really good
ideas for your content team to add
flair and your personality's flair
in the content that you create.
The content can be on very
different topics, may not be
really about a major life change.
But they can include snippets of
these experiences inside, like
say, an industry relevant post
or a customer experience story.
So that it adds your personality's
flair and that will greatly
impact the effectiveness.
of LinkedIn Content Marketing.
So, I'm going to fill out some of this.
I'm just going to quickly go
through this and fill it out.
Made a short term
sacrifice for a big gain.
Yeah, so a summary of this
experience that I want to fill out.
Okay, made a short term
sacrifice for a big gain.
Would be, I was one of
the lowest paid members.
You know what, I was not one
of the lowest paid members,
I was the lowest paid member.
I was the lowest paid member of
my team in the first two years
of my contract.
Now, the story, I was struggling
with cashflow and I wanted to invest
everything back into business.
And through my agency.
Alright.
So that is what I wanted to do.
And then.
Now let me add some background
information over here.
So what is the background information
and the two to three sentence
elaboration that we can add over here.
So the background information
is something along the lines of.
When we began.
We had a huge traction.
On LinkedIn.
With our content.
And we had a lot of clients
approaching us for our services.
But I was an amateur business founder.
I did not understand how to manage
cash flow and be profitable.
So I earned money.
on unwanted experiments, unwanted
hires and fancy growth hacks and=
did not be focused on building
a profit, profitable business.
All right.
Now, what is the moment of highest drama?
I remember the moment of highest drama.
One being unable to travel back home
to my parents, visit my parents,
parents, because I would have not
thought the cheapest train seat.
This is a true story.
All this when we
were generating about I don't know
the thing which I made about 80K USD
revenue per month but our expenses
were non consistent
higher more than
what we indicated.
Alright, I had already borrowed
from most of My contacts, who
I couldn't borrow money from.
And I was too embarrassed
to ask for money again.
Right?
So what these prompts like
these in this columns do is
they give you food for thought.
They direct your thought to creating
good, to adding good stories
about your experiences and so on.
Now, how did it make me feel?
Yeah, I'm actually, I'm going to
copy paste this because it made
me feel both trapped and miserable
300 miles from my home.
My hometown and my family, I'm
trying hard day and night to build an
agency, chasing my dream, even being
somewhat successful with it, but not
understanding what was going wrong.
I was clueless.
As to how I could resolve the
issues, because I was facing
the same issue for months.
So this thing went on for months.
Now, how did it make others feel?
Team members, both freelance team members.
Consultants we worked with and my
small startup team were concerned.
They saw that I was always tired, always
stressed could never follow a team
because I was staying up nights.
properly with follow routine and
there were always delays in payments.
This made me realize
that irrespective of how many clients we
were landing how much brand awareness.
We were writing on LinkedIn.
I, it wouldn't be a business.
We have business.
Until we generated positive gas.
This wasn't a charity.
To
keep losing money.
I
had to figure out a solution.
So that's how I made me feel.
And then next we need to talk
about what is the lesson learned.
So that is about the lesson learned.
But I think the lesson I learned was
that I should stop focusing on sales
and marketing, start focusing on
building and op steam for more to shade.
Yeah, that's a blow.
Structure.
Processes.
That we didn't have to
keep running expensive
experiments for every
client we worked with.
And that included niching down
The focus on one single Service
proposition rather than offer
all types of marketing services.
All right, so I fill that out.
Yep.
And then finally, we have any other
details that might be important.
Well, what is another detail
that might be important?
Yeah.
So I could mention like the result
of what happened at the end.
I found a CEO in Canada.
That and with his help, we structured
the entire service delivery process.
And I handed off all the hiring to him.
Okay.
Then we niche down to only
offer LinkedIn marketing.
Which saved us a lot of, let's say,
money at the same time on my time.
Okay.
It also, I started paying myself more as
soon as I as the cash flow issues were
resolved after we did both of the above.
That's it.
We have a very good experience that
our content team can learn from,
which is about our personality about
our previous experiences and so on.
So that's how we fill out the anecdotal
stories put some time into this.
This one took like 10 minutes to put
some time into this and, and add a
couple of experiences and do not hesitate
to keep like spend some time on this
every week to do the whole thing.
But the next section is the
background and tone of voice.
These are simple to fill, like
my, my birthday, for example, is
in December 20, in December 1992.
Where do I travel a lot,
but mostly in Bangalore with
a team
with city and country from, of course,
I'm from I'm from South India, so I'm
just going to enter South India in here.
Because that's where I'm from.
What do you want to achieve in life?
I think a positive impact for everyone.
I want to,
to be a force for everyone
around me and beyond, right?
Again, that is not some generic
stuff and it's just filled out
for the sake of filling it out.
This is what I want to do.
I filled this sheet out like 20 times.
So what's your expertise?
I would say my expertise includes
everything from marketing to generation.
I'd say content marketing is
one of my core skill sets.
I would say process design is
something that I'm good at.
Copywriting is something I'm good at.
Coaching is something I'm good at.
So all of the skills that I want to
include, I can include them in here.
So go through these.
These are very good questions that
will help you understand better about
yourself and help your team understand a
lot about you so you can fill this out.
That's okay.
Okay.
Completely.
I'm just going to fill it in here for now.
And then we have what
the problems in industry.
So in my opinion, the biggest problem
in this industry, my industry.
Which is LinkedIn marketing, is
that most businesses haven't yet
seen good examples of r o I positive
LinkedIn funnels which needs
them to consider it just as any
other social media platform.
That is a big pain point
in, in this industry.
So, you could describe your
solution for this industry.
So, my solution for this industry
is create more content that is
actionable enough for them to
execute, to generate better results
on LinkedIn, with the help of a...
Real case studies of clients
we use for them, right.
So that would be a good
solution for this in my opinion.
So this is how you fill out the problems
in your industry and how you would solve
them or you could expand the point or you
could state your own opinion about this.
All right.
Now, what are my interests?
What are my core interests?
So my core interest is, is traveling.
Traveling is something that
I would include, but that's
a generic interest, right?
Specifically, what in
traveling do you like?
What in writing do you like?
So I'm going to write more
along writing content.
So it's a brief thing
about writing content.
Now describe when this happened.
When did I start writing
content on LinkedIn?
So it started back in 2018.
And I started documenting my journey
of building an agency on LinkedIn.
All right.
Now, tangible moments, cite the
conversation or describe the feeling
around this, around this specific
interest, personal interest.
So, I think it was, I stumbled,
so very specific conversation.
I stumbled across Google Sheets that was
linked, linked to a form on my LinkedIn
profile, contact form on my LinkedIn
profile, and this form had 40 links.
This happened two months after
I started posting on LinkedIn.
I lost all but one of those leads.
And it's helped me close my first
new client from when I started.
I founded my agency.
The moment I realized that I had missed
out, I had not responded to party needs.
Just because I wasn't paying attention
to the form entries I just couldn't
help but shout poorly, okay, that's a
bit of profanity, but that's exactly
what I said, loud, out loud, in the
co working space that I was working.
That's it.
One thing that you need to note over here
is assuming that if you publish something
like this, if, if like your copywriters
take, take inspiration from this and
publish on something along these lines,
some ideas that lines from these on
your LinkedIn profile, it may look good.
So there is a common perspective that it
is not a good idea to share unprofessional
stuff, unprofessional stuff on LinkedIn.
That is absolutely not true.
In fact, the more vulnerable you are
with your content, better your results
will be from your content marketing.
We do talk about this a lot in the content
creation steps in the program, but it's
good to be vulnerable in the sheet.
Like, so when you want to talk
about your interests, your problems
your background and tone of voice,
please be as vulnerable as possible,
but be very authentic and honest.
Because authenticity and
vulnerability goes a long way.
Right now that was the interest section,
and now we have the lesson section.
So in the lesson section, these are about
lessons, learning lessons that we learned.
So one of the learning lessons
that I learned is that unless
you have, let's see, s d r work,
s d r, I could say p d r work.
So business development.
in the inbox is one of the primary reasons
why LinkedIn outreach does not work.
Alright?
Now what I mean by this is assume
you're sending a bunch of outreach
messages on LinkedIn, right?
You will get like a lot
of responses from people.
But most of the responses assume
90% of the responses won't be people
who are, who are like straight
away interested in buying your
service or your product from you.
Most of them will be like a thumbs up
or thank you, or I'll keep you in mind
or something like generic responses.
Many of them will be saying,
saying they're not interested.
So what you need to do is you need to
have somebody on the team or you need
to handle this yourself to nurture those
conversations step by step, track each
of those conversations, and eventually
get them to a stage where they're
interested in talking to you about
your service or product and then get
them on a call and try to close them.
So if that process is absent, your
lead generation on LinkedIn would
be like one tenth of what it can be.
And it may not become ROI positive.
So that is a lesson I learned
a couple of years ago.
It took a lot of time to learn that lesson
because I thought we could just reach
out, pitch people or publish content.
People will reach out to me when the
truth is you'll get way better ROI.
If you are spending a lot of
time in the inbox, a couple hours
every day in the inbox, nurturing
people who are responding to you.
Okay, now when did I realize this?
I realized this only in my third year.
Tangible moments, side the
conversation or describe the feeling.
Our clients, so we can
be detailed over here.
I'm going to say something like
our clients they're generating
results, but if they're not...
Impressive.
Being generated our coffee needs
every month with content and
outreach, but nothing to the level
that we would continue us a month.
We were doing outreach, we
were creating and publishing
conduct, but that wasn't enough.
We had to.
Delta patients prospects.
Wow.
I remember saying to Nikhil, so this
is the tangible of the conversation
to Nikhil when I organized this.
This is the last.
That's part of the process
we we can stop scaling.
That's it.
And now we move on to the next
section, which are what are the
successes you've had so far.
So we've actually, okay,
there's a lot of successes.
But I think one of the major
successes is someone writes about
when we formed partnerships.
So partnerships are some of the biggest
successes in terms of both the revenue
and the learning that we, that we gained.
I think one of the biggest
successes is partnering Alex
for IG that's Imagine Front.
Great.
See, that's step by step.
LinkedIn training program in the world.
When did this happen?
This happened early, you
know, I think it was 2021.
See, there were multiple
tangible conversations but
tangible that I can recall.
But I think one that really stood out
was, I remember saying to Alex, after my
first partnership fell through, I made
the decision that we wouldn't do it again.
But now, I want to make a bet on this.
Okay, and Alex said along the
same, same thing Alex replied.
Creative of partnering with strangers.
But, we'll see the value.
Yep.
That is a tangible moment
of the conversation.
I could include more details as well.
I think the learning lesson was
past experiences may earn us and
make us set our minds and set our
minds to things that may not be
beneficial for our long term growth.
We need to come to terms with it.
Previous experiences or past
experiences and get over them and
still choose what's right for our
own growth and the growth of those
that are in our journey.
Alright, now that's a good lesson.
So that's it with the successes.
So the most of our success just
as you add achievements, you can
add achievements about getting
covered in ink magazine or Forbes.
So you can add achievements about
hiring the right team member.
We can have success successes about
landing big clients or like some
client that you've always wanted
to work with and so on in here.
So those are successes.
And then we have obstacles.
So obstacles are about challenges that
you faced while building a business.
or building a process.
So I think one of the biggest
challenges was not having good
content management process.
So without this we were spending 2 to
3x the amount of time not doing work but
just coordinating work between teams.
It is multiple team members were involved
in the creation of FTP support, right?
And now, when did this happen?
This I think we, we
started facing this issue.
This issue was a constant issue
from when we started offering
intermarketing service to when we offered.
board and cost tracking system
in I believe this is in 2021.
Okay.
Tangible.
Will side the conversation.
Describe the feeling.
I think, think we were
spending like around a hundred
dollars, a hundred for say
it's a limited text person.
So this happened when I realized I said
this when I realized that we calculated
the the expenses for creating and
publishing a single piece of content.
So we realized that the content itself,
getting it written by the copywriters
was taking like a lot of time.
And in between like 10 and 20,
but say the different team members
coordinating each piece of content,
somebody reviewing it somebody
adding it, tracking it in one place.
We were using multiple trackers to track
the link to the post or the link to the
Google doc where it was shared, stored,
and then multiple team members handling
it, somebody else publishing that piece
of content and then promoting that content
and then engaging with all the comments.
And then that's for
putting it to the client.
So the entire creation to publishing
to promotion stage for a single piece
of content is costing us way more than
100 USD for the link, singling exposed.
And these are textbooks, not even videos.
So that was something
I mentioned in nickel.
And that is when I said something like.
Letter.
I think the learning lesson from this
was, okay, let me just grab the, I was
frustrated and, and just being like that
this was one of the biggest cost suckers.
That's on the same process, right?
And now we have the learning lesson.
We have to use a task platform so that
on the entire team would be on the
same page about each and every task
without having to get on a call to ask.
All right.
Now that is the learning lesson.
So this is how you fill out
the content edition sheet.
I've given you some examples
for each of these sections.
So what I want you to do is you
don't need to limit it to one hour.
We spent almost one hour
just going through this.
But I did spend a couple hours,
assume like one to two hours each
week for the next four weeks, and
then try to properly finish this out.
Over time, this will be
a very good repository.
of, of content ideas that will portray not
just your personality, but also about the
industry and like which personas you want
to focus on, which pain points you want
to talk about, problems or pain points are
faced by your target audience, et cetera.
And these ideas in the anecdotal
stories, your struggles your interests,
et cetera, will help your team, your
content team on LinkedIn help you
create, help you have that flair
of your personality in the content.
So, that sums up with this video and this
was one of the last videos in this module.
So, you can go ahead and get started
with creating your own content ideation
sheet, your own content analysis sheet
and filling this sheet out properly.
But what I'd recommend is spend some
time On this every week for the next
few weeks and just fill this out a lot,
as many ideas as possible so that your
team can have really good idea about
your personality and the industry.
My opinion would be to fill at
least four rows in this section,
ten rows in this section.
So that's the anecdotal story section.
Background tone of voice,
fill it out completely.
No exceptions, just
And then problems in an industry
include at least seven different
problems in this section.
Then interest, you can just need
to include like five interests.
Lessons you learned are important.
So include at least six lessons in there.
Then we have successes,
include at least six successes.
Obstacles you face include
at least six obstacles.
This is a very good section for you
continue to understand like challenges
we face and how we overcame them.
That's good content areas.
So.
That's it for this video.
You can go ahead and start the work now.
See you in the next video.