So in this video, I'm going to walk
you through a step by step process to
identify gaps in your content strategy
using the gap identification sheet.
We will compare what we're doing right
now with our content strategy with what
our competitors are doing and then use
what we learned to identify the gaps and
add good examples of content we need to
replicate or continue creating so that
when we design our content strategy,
we know exactly what we need to do.
This step will take about 1.
5 hours to complete fully,
including watching the training.
Now, without further
ado, let's jump into it.
So this is the gap identification sheet
that we use to understand and analyze
the gap between what our competitors
are doing, what the industry is doing
in general, and what we are doing.
And both what the competitors
have been doing and what we are
doing with our existing content
have already been documented in
the competitor analysis sheet.
and in the existing
content analysis sheet.
So we've done it for all our
competitors and we've done it for
all the existing content analysis.
Now, the gap identification will take
a lot of time, if you don't do it along
with the competitor analysis and the
existing content analysis, which is why
in the overview I clearly mentioned that
we have to do all three of these, which
is ideally all four of these, which is
the competitor analysis, the existing
content analysis, the gap identification,
as well as the content ideation.
Within a span of one day or a maximum
of two days, because the person who's
handling all three of these sheets should
be should remember what they've analyzed
so far so that they have a good idea so
that they can do this quickly, otherwise,
you will have to refer to each of the to
the data that you've already documented
in both these sheets and go through them
one by one and analyze them but if you do
it together, you can just recall it from
the top of your mind on, on what you saw.
Okay.
Competitors doing and you're doing all
right now, what we're going to do is
we are going to analyze each of the two
food, more food content and identify gaps.
So basically what we're doing over here
is we're going to think about, okay
is there a gap in the creation of blog
posts, which is a top of the funnel
content format short form blog posts.
So if competitors are
doing it, are we doing it?
So I can tell you that we are doing
it, but these are not very helpful
and we don't want to do this.
So we are able to identify gap or not.
We add hyperlinks with titles
to the type of content formats
that we need to replicate.
And we mention, okay, should
this be one-off, should it
be created consistently?
And we give a name to this content format
for the latest stage of the process.
Alright, so this is what we are going
to do one by one for the entire thing.
So what I'm gonna do first is I'm
gonna start off by recalling gaps in
each of these things in the process.
So I know for a fact from the
competitor analysis that I already
did for all the competitors
that I documented in the sheet.
And I also know which content formats are
being done because I just completed this.
So I'm going to quickly
see if there is a gap.
So how do we identify a gap?
A gap exists when we want to
continue to create something.
But we, we are not creating something,
but competitors in the space are doing it.
If you don't want to continue creating
that content format, it's fine.
You can mention that there is not a
gap and you don't need to add anything
in there, but if there is a gap, you
need to document all these columns
properly so that you can start creating
content in those formats actively.
Now, how do we go about this?
So regarding blog posts, we are
already creating a bunch of blog
posts, but we don't want to use we
don't want to proceed with this,
creating this content format because.
It's not very helpful to the audience and
it's the same way with the competitors.
The competitors are creating
short form blog posts as well.
I wouldn't say they're very helpful
to the, to the, to the users.
So these are the links to the
different short form content
pieces that they are using.
Sorry.
So yeah, but I wouldn't say
they're good content pieces.
So which is why I am going to recommend.
So these are the content pieces.
We can take a quick look.
Thank and form your opinions around it
again, once more, it's completely fine.
But I do not believe that these
are, this is a content format that
we should be going ahead with.
So I'm just going to mark it as no.
That's it.
Very simple.
Regarding LinkedIn posts of course, there
is a bunch of them that we need to do.
So if we take a look at the existing
content analysis on, on this post, this
helps me, keeps my audience engaged
with niche content updates and trends.
Now there are several content
formats in this section.
That we can use.
You can name them at this stage or
you can choose not to name them.
Most of the average stuff that we're doing
already are already there in the process.
You will understand that later on,
but for the time being what we can
do is we need to add hyperlinks
with titles to content formats.
You need to replicate that's
yours or your competitors.
So if you're doing something that you
really like and that's producing results.
Or that is generating a
good amount of engagement.
Or you like creating the content.
And you think it's valuable,
you're confident it's valuable.
You can include links to that in here.
So in our case, we are already doing a
bunch of stuff that, that we really like.
So, for example, top 10
construction projects.
So this is something that I like doing.
This is a carousel.
And this is usually it's, it's supposed
to be created consistently, right?
So this is a recurring.
So this is a recurring content
format, and this is a good
example of that content format.
And I can continue to do this process
for all of the ones in LinkedIn posts.
So for example, summary of
KPMG report, yes summary of
interesting reports in the space.
That is something we can include.
This should also be occurring, and
this was created as a carousel.
You could mention a content
format name over here.
But I would say this one is
better suited as a text course.
Please mention you don't have to
like, say it could be descriptive.
So you could enter some stuff like this
is a carousel on top 10 lists or listicle.
All right.
You could name it like that.
It's not necessary because we're not going
to be choosing this in the exact fashion
while we set up our content strategy,
but it's important to like, say, give
some description so that we understand
or get some context as to what it is.
All right.
Now let's keep proceeding with this.
So we have some content formats in here.
Let's look at the competitors.
Canadian economy and construction.
These are all good.
This is also a slide post, so this
is interesting story slide post.
That is how we would name it.
I really like that content format,
I think adds a lot of value.
It is also generating good
amount of engagement on the
profile and the key profile.
So this is also recurring and
this is a carousel or slide post
interesting  construction story.
Right.
And now see, it's not just enough
to include examples from our content
that we're already publishing.
We should also be taking
a look at the competitors.
If we could quickly take a look at
this for the not, do not spend a lot of
time on this to explain this process.
I'm just going to be taking the time
for now, but you should be looking at
all the competitors that have been nice.
We've analyzed five competitors already.
So I'm going to take a look at this and
I'm going to see, okay, what are some.
Content from as they're using on LinkedIn.
What are some good LinkedIn
posts that they're using.
So these are the TOFU content and these
are the LinkedIn posts that they're doing.
They're sharing blog posts their
employee experience stories.
So that is something that
we can, we could use.
So I'm going to copy that.
And that is something that I would
include in the gap identification
sheet as an employee experience story.
So in a moment stories you
can just copy and paste it.
All right.
Thank you.
This is also a recurring and this is
can be image posts with text, right?
Simple.
You don't need to give like a
huge very descriptive title.
You can just mention or a very
branded title to the content format.
You can just mention
what it is at this stage.
And now we can move on to videos, right?
So in this manner, we're going to
go through the entire sheet and
we're going to take a look at.
Okay.
Is there a gap now?
How do we identify there is a gap?
We take a look at the existing content
analysis sheet and we see we are
already creating that content format.
And if there is a gap in that
process we name it as such.
If there is no gap in that
process, we leave it completely.
But if there is a gap in that
process, we make sure that we add
hyperlinks to content formats.
We name if it is one off
or created consistently.
And we also include a description about
that content format, what format format.
Thank you.
Should it be in.
All right, now we're going
to continue with this process
until we document all of this.
So I'm going to quickly go through
and fill all of these out for you.
So that you don't spend too
much time watching the video
rather than doing the work.
So I just filled out the video column.
So what I found is that there is a gap.
So we like the event videos.
It is supposed to be done recurring
because it'll happen multiple times.
And I named them as event or conference
templates for conference format.
And we also noticed that there
are explainer videos, video
sales letters, and building.
There is a, they have a podcast
series as well, Builder Trends
specifically, that is performing well.
So we added them explainer videos
and video sales that just need to
be created once or twice at the max.
But so I added them as one time
and the podcast series is incurring
and I just named them accordingly.
That is it with this section.
And next we go to in depth blog posts.
So I just looked at in depth blog
posts and it looks like there are
a bunch of blog posts that are
quite in depth that are valuable.
And from our existing content analysis,
we already know that we are not
creating a lot of more full content
or middle of the funnel content.
So I'm going to find examples
from competitors that we can use.
And yes, there is a content gap over here.
These are recurring content
pieces and I've just named them as
actionable tutorials because both
of them are actionable tutorials.
That help them solve pain points
like tracking construction
equipments and managing and
improving construction plan flow.
Both are pain points.
And these blog posts help
them explain that, right?
You can take a look at
the blog posts as well.
And we move on to strategy and how to
focus LinkedIn posts and add examples.
So we are not doing this at the moment.
This is something that we should be doing.
And we've already mentioned that
we've needed, need to create continue
creating this content format.
So I'm going to mark this as yes, there
aren't many good examples of strategy
and how to focus LinkedIn posts.
It is not necessary that you shouldn't do
something just because your competitors or
you yourself are not doing it right now.
Most businesses are unaware of how much
LinkedIn can help them generate leads.
So if it is LinkedIn specific content.
Or even websites must be content just
because your competitors are not doing it
does not mean that you shouldn't do it.
Even if you're not able to find
good examples you should, you
can mention it as occurring.
So I wasn't able to find any good
examples of how to focus LinkedIn posts.
Most of them is like company updates.
Product feature updates and stuff
like that that these companies, all
the companies publish on LinkedIn.
So I was unable to find any good examples,
even in the competitor analysis, but.
This is a content format that
I'm confident we should be doing.
So, which is why I'm going to mark
it as recurring and I'm going to mark
it as actionable tutorial as well.
It's the same content format.
In fact this content format,
which is end up blog post can be
repurposed into a LinkedIn post.
I just feel it's the same topic.
It's the same format that we need for this
because it's a how to focus LinkedIn post
and this is how to focus blog post, right?
So, I'm going to mark it the same way.
Now, videos strategy, education, focus,
LinkedIn, YouTube, Instagram, reels
related to the service or product.
Let's take a look at that next.
Now regarding videos, I've
identified that there is a gap
and most of them are webisodes.
So I identified two specific
webisodes that are good examples of
prime examples of, of what we want.
They implemented the section, so I'm
just going to include that in here.
And I'm going to mark them as recurring
because, well, they're recurring.
And these are both webisodes
or webinars that they organize.
I'm going to include that in here again.
Webinars can fall, it's, it's not
necessary that one specific content
format, say like webinars or white papers
and so on falls into one specific format.
It can, it can fall into
both TOFU and MOFO content.
So if they're selling something at the
end of the webinar, it can, it can be
both MOFU content and TOFU content,
but at the same time, many webinars
focus on adding a lot of value in the
webinar, teaching people something
and then selling something at the end.
So both of these webinars
are in that format.
We evaluated these in the competitive
analysis process in that video.
So I think that good examples of
this, so I'm going to mark it as this.
And then we move on to white papers.
Again, this is not something
that we do actively right now.
There is a gap.
We want to create more
white papers that are good.
And if I take a quick look at the
competitor analysis sheet, I can
already see that this client is not
creating white papers, but it is
something that we need to do actively.
So I've identified some other white
papers from other competitors, and
I'm going to add them in this one now.
So I've identified
white papers and eBooks.
We are not doing both of these,
but I identified good examples
from our competitor analysis
sheet and I included them in here.
All of them are supposed to be recurring.
So let me just put that out as well.
All of these are supposed to be recurring
and I've also named some added a
descriptive name to this content format.
So this one is a white paper on a
specific pain point using a data study.
Put topic and type.
Okay.
And this one is a white paper
on a specific pain point.
This is an industrial report.
And this is a process template
that's helpful to the audience.
It's a construction daily huddle template.
And this is a guide or an actionable
tutorial that teaches them about mastering
takeoff for estimations in construction.
So that is it with these.
And these are, these are,
these are gaps as well.
Now, webinars and conferences,
of course, we have gaps.
We have a lot of good examples
of podcasts, webinars, and
newsletters, which we can include.
Again, it's not necessary that you
mark them as you have a gap if you're
only interested in creating it.
What we want this sheet to be is to
understand if there is an actual gap,
if competitors are doing it or not
if we are doing it or not, we need
to document it in here so that in
the future we can understand, okay,
this there is a gap at this process.
So which content formats do we prioritize?
What do we start with right now?
So it's not important that you mark this.
Yes, only if you want to create
that content format, you can
also do it in the future.
All right.
So let me add links to webinars
and conferences as well.
So I've included podcasts and
newsletters and webinars as well in here.
So I found some good examples
of the copy data analysis sheet.
These are all occurring.
Thank you.
And this one is a pain
point focus webinar.
This one is also a pain
This is a conference for the podcast.
I found only one podcast,
interesting podcast series.
This is run by Builder Trend and
they are an interview podcast series.
And for newsletters, I
found Construction Time.
It's a, it's a good podcast, sorry,
newsletter series that they're running.
Interestingly a lot of the comp
leaders we analyzed are not running
active newsletters that they promote.
So this one is also recurring.
It's a good example that we can analyze.
And we, I just named it as newsletter.
And now we move on to BOFU
content which is the last part
of the gap identification sheet.
And let's go through case
studies, testimonials demos,
et cetera, and fill this out.
Now regarding case studies, we do
have a gap over here, but I think
what we can include over here
are both our case studies as well
as some links to case studies.
That our competitors are publishing
so that we get a good understanding or
good inspiration on like what format
we can use for those case studies.
So let me go ahead and fill this out.
So I've looked through the existing
content analysis sheet and the competitor
analysis sheet and I've filled out
the go for content section as well.
So we started off with case studies.
I found very good case studies
that we should use as examples.
They're all recurring because we
do it for each client, and they
just named them as case studies.
We found testimony videos.
I've only included two in them because
I think these are really good format
and I don't want to add more ideas.
But if you find really good examples
that you're impressed by, always
try to fill out at least four or
you can add more rows as well.
But try to include as many examples, as
many good examples as possible for these.
All right?
And we need to do this ideally
for each client that we have.
So it's a recurring
one, it's a testimonial.
Demos and free consultations.
We don't really have a gap for
this because we already have a
demo and we only need one demo.
We don't need multiple types of demos.
You could include them for your use case.
If you feel that you're offering a
different you're focusing on different
verticals and you have multiple
products or features within your product
that you want to market and you want
different kinds of demos make sense.
In that case, you can do it.
And if you're in the service industry
and you want to offer different
types of consultations for your sales
process, you can include different
kinds of consultations as well in
here, but we don't have a requirement
for this for trace cost or case study.
So we're not going to use it now.
Competitive comparisons.
Interestingly, most of the competitors
we analyze do not have competitive
comparisons, which is why we didn't
explain that this content format in detail
during the competition analysis process.
Thanks.
But let me quickly show you
what this content format is.
Because this is very important.
Now, what a competitive comparison
does ideally is compare your product
with another product and explain
why your product is better because
you have better features and so on.
Even if they have like Vimo features
what we need to do is explain our
core selling proposition for USB in
this content format so that people
are more inclined to buy our product
or like our core target audience is
more inclined to buy our product.
And this is important because people
do search for when they're evaluating
multiple softwares, people do
search for competitive comparison.
So if I was evaluating both
Procore and Buildertrend.
I would do a Google search of
core versus build a trend to
understand which is better.
It's like doing something like
Gmail versus Outlook or Namecheap
versus Codaddy, which are domain
registrars to understand which
solution is better for my business.
So this is what a
competitive comparison is.
So we, in detail, we, we analyze this.
It could be shorter because I was
not able to find good examples
from the competitors we analyzed.
I did a Google search for this
for Build a Trend versus Procore.
I found some good examples
on other websites comparing
both the products and so on.
And I included them in here.
Now this is a one time activity because
we only need to do this for like our
main competitors, which are the max four
or five in TraceCostcase and I've just
named them as competitive comparisons.
Then we have customer experience stories.
We have a bunch of them that
are really good examples of
customer experience stories.
I've included them in here
and okay, this is a duplicate.
I'm just going to leave that
and ideally include all the
good examples that you find.
If you're not impressed with an example,
you don't need to include them here,
but if you think that a good example
and good reference points you can
include them in here and label them.
And finally, we have product
walkthroughs or explainer videos.
Which we've included in
here and label them as well.
And that brings us to the identification
brings us to the end of the gap
identification sheet process.
And we've documented all the gaps that
we have and we've included good examples
and we've even given names to the
content formats that we found to be good.
All right.
So that's it for this video.
See you in the next one.