So the very next step in building our own content
strategy is to choose content formats. But
before we jump into all the different content
formats, let's talk a bit about content personas.
And what do we mean by content personas? All
you need to do is take a look at the Viral
Content Marketing book and a specific section
in the Viral Content Marketing book called
personas. And what we're going to talk about
here are content personas. So content personas
are, you could say the personalities that you
adopt or choose to adopt for designing your
content strategy. There are three types of content
personas that perform well on LinkedIn. The
first is that what we call a viral news guy
persona. The second is that a viral influencer
persona. And the third one is that of an niche
expert persona. Now let's dive deep a little
bit into each of these personas and what they
are and take a look some examples of content
created by these personas. So viral news guy
persona is someone that focus on one core niche
and creates news posts or interesting viral
posts in that specific niche. So they always
focus on one specific niche. They don't publish
any and all types of content on any and all
types of topics. They always focus on one specific
niche. So Pascal Bornet is a very good example
of a viral news guy. What he does is he's a
LinkedIn top voice. He only focuses on tech
focused content. Now If you take a look at the
content that he published, this is a viral
news video from that was created by some other
company called EEAGLI. So it looks like a data
analysis company and this compares how the mobile
phone market changed over 30 years. It's a
video. Now what Pascal did is he...
repurposed the content published by this guy
so he's added source attribution in here and he's
repurposed that content and he's published it
on LinkedIn so he chose this because again
it's over the tech market so he only talks about
tech he doesn't talk about other topics but
tech is a broad niche so there's a lot of things
to talk about within tech and he only publishes
content like this here's another example so
this one is created by Quantum Techs which
is another company and this is a video about
a viral news video about a first augmented
reality lens becoming real. I guess that's an
implanted lens and you can see the engagement
that he has received on these content pieces
as well. Now why does the viral news guy persona
work really well? Now the interesting thing
about this persona is that almost all of the
content that they publish is sourced from other
social media platforms. It's almost never original
content. They always source it from other social
media platforms. They publish content in multiple
formats. So it can be a video, it can be an
image, or it can be other formats. And they
also give source attribution to the content
that they publish on their profiles if they
source it from somewhere else. But the goals
of this persona is to build a large, industry-relevant
audience. And they only focus on creating content
using by repurposing content that is performed
well on other social media platforms. And they
publish multiple times a day, which is one
of their differentiating factors about their
content. So on average, we tend to publish
content only once a day, but they publish content
multiple times a day because they're confident
that perform well, again, because they only
take content that is performed well or proven
to work really well on other social media platforms.
Now, after the viral news guy persona, we have
the niche expert persona. Now, what is a niche
expert persona? So you could say both Alex
and me are choose the niche expert persona for
our content. So the goals of the niche expert
persona is to build an industry-specific audience.
So we don't want a generic audience like entirely
in tech. We want users who are specifically
say, interested in LinkedIn marketing and interested
in... learning more about LinkedIn marketing
and understanding more about the generation
of sales, social selling topics like that, and
that a more potential customers of the product
or the service that I offer. Now, the reason
I choose this personalize because with expert
content in that specific niche, I can build
trust faster in that specific niche, which
is much smaller than say tech in general. But
The brand that you can generate and the revenue
that you can generate even with a small audience
in the niche experts with the niche persona
is larger than what you can generate with the
viral news guy persona or the viral influencer
persona. So that's the advantage. I'm not suggesting
that the niche expert persona is far better
than the viral influencer persona or the viral
news guy persona. So these are all good personas
to choose from because of the amount of effort
that you put into the content marketing process
and the amount of returns that you get from
it. So the viral user persona focuses on creating
content in specific formats. But again, it's
almost always original content that they themselves
created with research or from their own knowledge.
But they rarely plagiarize or copy content
or repurpose content that is performed well
on other social media platforms. They may gain
inspiration from them and choose topics from
content pieces that are performed on other
social media platforms. But almost always they
create original content. that is interesting
to their specific target audience on LinkedIn.
Now after the niche expert persona, we have
one more persona, which is the viral influencer
persona. So the best way you could say to explain
viral influencer persona is an influencer or
a wannabe influencer, a creator on LinkedIn,
who is publishing content on any and all topics,
any and all niches, any and all formats. The
only criteria is that it performs well. So all
he does is he finds viral content on LinkedIn
that is performed well on other social media
platforms as well as LinkedIn. And he repurposed
that content for his profile. So almost always,
almost all the content that they publish on
their profiles are repurposed content. The amount
of original content they publish is little
to zero. But... They borrow or repurpose content
that has performed really well on other social
media platforms, so viral content essentially,
and they publish that on their LinkedIn profile.
The goal of this persona is to reach as many
users as possible and maximize the reach of
their content by choosing only viral posts.
And irrespective of industry or niche or subniche,
they want to build a large audience and a large
follower base on LinkedIn. Now let's take a
look at some examples of specific persona. So
you can ideally recommend when you check these
examples out, you can easily search them on
LinkedIn, take a look at their content and
form an understanding of how they differ from
each other. So the best example of viral influencer
persona is that of Daniel Abraham's. So Daniel
Abraham's publishes content on any and all
topics and he's quite viral and pretty sure
he's got over 1 million followers now. And
he's doing a great job with simply repurposing
content that he finds from other sources. and
publishing it on his LinkedIn profile. Anne
Handley is the, I believe she was the CMO of
marketing drops, a famous marketing run. And
she is also a good example of the viral influencer
persona because they publish content, she publishes
content on well, every single topic under the
sun, so it can be any content or in any format.
All she focuses on is making sure that it is
viral or it has gone viral in the past on other
social media platforms or on LinkedIn. So these
are the core. um personas and each of these
personas we've segmented content formats for
you. So in the content format sheet we have
the content formats that you can use to create
content. If you choose any of these personas,
so all of these have separate content formats
that you can use. Obviously the viral news guy
and the viral influencer persona are, have
content formats that are way more easier to
create. The processes for creating content
with these personas are way more easier to create.
But what I want you to do is make a decision
now on which persona you want to choose. Now,
it's not necessary that you focus on one persona
alone. You can use a hybrid between niche expert
persona and viral influencer persona, or you
can use a hybrid between. me, Shakespeare, persona
and viral news guy persona, but ideally don't
combine all three because combine all three,
it's going to be ineffective to some extent.
But after you've made a decision on what hybrid
you want, what I'd recommend that you do is
you make a hybrid between the niche expert persona
and the viral news guy persona. So say, suppose
you are in the construction space, like the
case study that we talked about in the previous
videos and the modules. If you're in the construction
space, you can publish niche expert content
on the construction niche, and at the same time,
you can repurpose content in the construction
niche that is performed really well on other
social media platforms, and you can publish
them on LinkedIn. or other social media platforms.
So the first thing you need to do is decide
on what persona you need to choose. You can
choose a hybrid between two of these personas.
But after you make that decision, the next step
is to think about what are the content formats
in each of these personas that we selected.
So once you make that decision, all you need
to do is make a list of content formats that
you want to start experimenting with in the
content format queue. So the content format
queue is a queue of different content formats
that you want to test on LinkedIn. And it's
not necessary that you use all of this. So
you'll be choosing some content formats or prioritizing
some content formats from the content queue.
Content format queue into content formats and
we're going to test them out and decide on
which ones you want to use long term. But for
the time being, what you should be doing is
you should be copying these. and pasting this.
So I'm gonna choose a hybrid between the Niche
Expert persona and the Viral Niche Guy persona
for the case study prompt in the construction
niche. So what I'm gonna do is I am going to
choose these and paste them in here. I'm gonna
choose these and paste them in here. And the
next step after this is to include content
formats you wish to include in your content
strategy. So we did the gap identification
and we already got... an idea of different content
formats that we want to be using. So we have
carousels or slide posts, which we already have
in the content format sheet. So in the content
format sheet, we already have carousels or slide
posts. So I'm going to keep moving on. We have
text posts already, experiences stories and
informative posts that include carousels again,
image posts with text, of course, and those
are what we call informative posts. That's
fine. we have event or conference snippets.
This is more of a news post or information
post, so we already have that. Explainer video
is something that is new in here. So what I
would do is include an explainer video in here
because that is something that we want to look
at. And we have a VSL, which is also new. So
I would include that in here. And then we have
actionable tutorials. So actionable tutorials,
I haven't yet made up my mind on what format
it should be in, but actionable tutorials is
something that I'm going to include in here.
And then we have webinars. Webinars are an entirely
different process. We're already covering it
separately in the Imagine Growth process because
they're very effective. So I'm not going to
cover them over here, but you now know that
you need to focus on webinars as well. We have
white papers and ebooks, different kinds of
white papers and ebooks. So I'm going to include
that as well in content format. So white papers
on a specific point. our pain point data study
and then we have industry report process template.
So my oh my, we have a lot of stuff in here.
And so we have process templates, guide or actionable
tool. And we've already included in here. So
I'm going to move back. Then we have again webinars,
conferences, conferences again is an entirely
different kind of strategy. I'm not going to
include it here. The interview podcast series
of the interview podcasting. That is a very
interesting addition from the gap identification
sheet. And then we have newsletters. Newsletters
is something we can consider. But newsletters
as well is a separate section in the LinkedIn
Growth campus because we cover it in detail because
it's a very good content format. But I'm going
to cover that right now. But we need case studies
and customer experience stories are some good
content formats that we can consider. So what
I would do is ideally use customer experience
stories than case studies because This is a
content format that performs better on LinkedIn.
Plus we already have it in here, customer experience
stories. So I could go ahead and add case studies,
but to an extent, customer experience stories
come from case studies and then vice versa.
So I'm not gonna add case studies as well in
there because we already have customer experience
stories. And then we have testimonials, which
is something that I could add in here, testimonials.
We have product features. Product feature is
above full video, but this is not something
that I would consider much adding on LinkedIn.
But we could consider that part of the company
page. So I'm gonna include all of them in here,
and I'm gonna... Make sure the formatting is
correct. All right, so we have some content
formats documented in here now. And now that
we've included all of these formats in here
that we want to test out, the first thing we
need to do is select five of them that we should
prioritizing. So what my recommendation would
be take experiential stories because there
are good content format. Slideposts is one of
the best content formats you can use on LinkedIn.
If you have a lot of lead magnets that you've
created internally, say white papers, templates,
guides and so on that you can give away for
free. Ideally PDFs or like tools that you can
give away for free internally. You can use resource
giveaways but otherwise my best recommendation
would be to offer Q&A videos. So Q&A videos
are a good content format. So these would be
the three ones I would select for this use case
which is construction niche. And then the remaining
two slots on the content calendar. So those,
assuming we have a five day work week. So that's
Mondays, Tuesdays, Wednesdays, Thursdays and
Fridays. Three of them are filled and now we
have two more. Now two of these should be experimental
slots. Now what I mean by that is you should
be experimenting different content formats in
these slots and seeing what is working and
what is not working. So what I'd recommend is
going ahead and maybe doing an experiment.
Informative post and a fun video is too much
work, these are all videos, I would also use
an engagement bait. So I would test out these
formats, see whether they're working. If they're
working well, I will continue to do it. Maybe
I'll try switching out some other stuff. And
I'll continue testing with more and more content
formats from the content format.