So let's jump straight away into how to go about
building your own LinkedIn content marketing
team. So this is an SOP with a bunch of useful
information that you can use to start your
hiring process after you've decided on which
of the team members we discussed in the previous
video you want to have on your team. Now, the
first thing we need for that are the job descriptions.
We will need a process to evaluate them, which
is what I'll be talking about in this video.
So... The first step is to take a look at this
SOP. You can find the link to this SOP below
the video. And in this SOP, we basically have
the job descriptions and the test tasks that
you can use to evaluate all of these different
job roles that we just discussed. And in here,
we first have the job descriptions for each
of the roles that we discussed. So you can
click on this table of contents and go to that
appropriate section. And we have a very detailed
job description for executive assistant in this
case, the EA role and we have details about
their roles and responsibilities in the content
process. What are the skills that they need
in the process? Be the number of years of experiences,
what are the manipulation we can offer them.
So this will act as good estimates for how much
you should be paying for these roles. Other
people that you hire in a part-time basis for
these roles. And then we have content managers,
we have copywriters, we have graphic designers,
we have video editors, and we have sales development
representatives. And then we have test stars
that we can use to evaluate each of these team
members. So these are all tests that you can
assign to them after you've they've passed
the first round. done an initial review of them
or you've talked to them at least once and
you can send them the test task. So you can
find everything in here and all you need to
do is post it on job posts or send it to them
after you've reviewed that profile. Now how
do we go about the hiring process in a structured
manner? The first step you need to take is
to decide on whether you want a full-time person
or a part-time person. I would recommend starting
off with a part-time person and then you can
make a decision after you've laid out the process
and you have a very good idea on on how to train
them, how to give them feedback, and the process
is already built out, then you can scale it
up or put more effort and money into it by
hiring more full-time team members or a full-time
workforce for your LinkedIn marketing team.
But at the start, it's good to start off with
part-time team members who work on an hourly
basis so you can set an expectation with them
that they need to put in two or three hours
every day. and that is the best way to get started
with this. Now, how do we go about starting
the hiring process? So the first step in the
hiring process is to post this requirement
on job boards. So if you are looking for part-time
positions or you're looking to hire freelancers,
Upwork, that's upwork.com, then we have free
up, that's free up.net. We have Indeed, which
is quite famous and LinkedIn themselves are
very good places to find really good freelancers.
Now how do you go about doing this? All you
need to do is you need to sign up for an account
in Upwork. So what Upwork allows you to do is
you can post a job, a part-time job or a full-time
job and users can come to that job. So skilled
freelancers can come to that job and they can
bid for that job. So they can either build an
hourly rate or they can bid for like say...
the entire project. In our case, it will be
an hourly rate that's most suitable for the
kind of work that we do. On free up, the process
is a bit different. So what free ups gives
you freelancers, they put you in touch with
candidates one on one. And the best part about
free up is that you have a dedicated hiring
manager or account manager who's helping you
find good talent or good freelancers on the
platform. So if you post a job, you may get
like two applications at the max. You can evaluate
them and like say shortlist them. If you're
not interested in them, you can mention that
you are account manager or hiring manager and
they will put you in touch with more applicants
Applicants and you can interview them and proceed
with them Indeed is a bit more unfiltered. So
If you post something you'll get like a bunch
of spam a lot of inexperienced people applying
but Since it's one of the most used job platforms
in the world. You will be getting a lot of responses
so all you need to do is post your job, click
on this and post your job and enter all the
details that we have at the SOP for the job
descriptions and so on. And finally, we have
LinkedIn. So the interesting thing about LinkedIn
is that there's a specific feature on the LinkedIn
profile called the hiring introductory card.
So this is the hiring introductory card. You
will be able to find something along the lines
of show that you're hiring or something like
that over here. So what you can do, is you
can post the job click on that and post the
job in my case I already have a post live but
I can come here and I can add a job post I can
select the company I'm hiring for I can select
the job title the company the employee location
the job type and so on I can go in next and
I can enter the details including the job description
so I've already filled them out here. The job
description and all the details that you need
to enter for any of these websites, not just
LinkedIn, but Upwork or FreeUp or Indeed are
all in the job description section. So just
go to the job description section for each of
these roles. If you're hiring for an executive
assistant, this will include all the details
that platforms need to post a job or post a
freelancing opportunity and start getting applications.
So just copy paste this, you can reword it
and edit it as you like, but this is the exact
same things that we use to hire our team members.
You can just go ahead and use them and create
multiple job posts for the roles that you want
to hire for among executive assistants, content
managers, copywriters, graphic designers, video
editors or sales development reps. Now, once
this is done, once you've posted the jobs and
you're starting to get applications, This is
the ideal workflow that we need to follow.
Sending over the test task is the best way to
quickly evaluate applicants. So you don't need
to spend your time going through getting on
a call with them and doing a face-to-face interview
with them before you even consider if, or before
you even initially evaluate if they're a good
fit for the kind of work that you want to do.
So this is the reason why test task makes a
lot of sense. This is a templated test task
that you can send to each of these roles, each
of the app candidates for each of these roles
so that you can evaluate their skills that
are specific to this role. So we have different
test tasks for executive assistants, copywriters
or content managers, graphic designers, video
editors and sales development reps, varying
from content creation to content publishing
to content automation to graphic designing
and video editing to outreach. sales outreach
and outreach management for sales development
reps. So ideally whenever you receive an application
you should be reaching out via either via email.
So in LinkedIn you can ask them to like send
you their resume on your email. On Indie the
resume will already be available so you can
take a quick look at it. On FreeUp you can
take a look at their profile on FreeUp and Upwork
as well you can take a look at their profile.
And after you do like a quick overview, like
should just take a few seconds You've gone
through their profile at least once you can
send them the test cast and tell them This
is the first round of the interview. All you
need to do is complete this test cast and send
it to me This is how we evaluate our candidates
And once the test cast is done You can also
mention the next step the next step is to get
on a one-on-one call with you so that you can
review the test tasks, the output of the test
tasks with them, and you can also have a chat
with them to evaluate whether they're a good
fit or not. One of the things that most users
make a mistake with is getting on a call before
the test task. Now, that is a waste of time
because you'll be receiving a lot of applications
if you're publishing on all these platforms.
It could be in the hundreds as well. And if
you're hiring for multiple profiles, this is
going to take a lot of time. But by sending
the test task at the start in a way that doesn't
create a lot of friction with the candidates,
so ideally you need to be telling them that
this is how you evaluate the candidates. that
apply for the jobs and this testcast will help
you evaluate faster and if you do a good job
with this you'll sail through the interview
process so keep them motivated and explain like
what the entire process is about what the next
steps will look like and then send them the
testcast they'll be more inclined to spend
some time on it and finish the testcast and
send it to you and this is going to save you
a lot of time because
Everyone who's just looking to apply, mass-applying
to jobs, and are desperate, will never spend
time to complete the test task. The good ones
will be convinced, and they will spend some
time to complete the test task. Now, after they
complete the test task, most of these just
explain rules on how the test task is supposed
to be submitted. And after they submit the
test task, we can evaluate it. It's pretty easy
to. see what the output is. But if you like
the output of the work that they did, the next
step is to get on a face-to-face call with
them, an online call with them, IDD, and evaluate
or review the output of the test task with
them on the call. So just get on a call with
them, ask them to present their test task and
explain how they did it, what they learned from
it. By doing it this way, you can save time
on the review process. You can understand how
good they are at what they do. You can also
get an understanding of how good their communication
skills are. So, communication skills are quite
important for roles like BDM, CW and CM. So
for these roles, they need to have good language
skills, good communication skills and writing
skills. So asking them to explain how they
did their test class is a good way to go about
understanding their communication skills and
how good they are. And once that is done. You
can make a decision on whether you need to
have additional rounds with them, additional
test tasks, you can come up with your own test
tasks, but in most cases by the end of the first
round, which is the test task and the end of
the second round, which is the face to face
interview, you will be able to make a decision
or you will have some candidates that you're
confident about hiring. Now that sums up and
the overview of the hiring process. I'm not
going to dive too much into detail about this
because it's pretty simple with this step-by-step
process. So step one is going and registering
on all these platforms, all of them are free.
And LinkedIn. And the next step is to post
the jobs so that either part-time roles or part-time
roles, it's up to you. You can, I recommend
starting off with part-time roles. So post the
jobs on all these platforms. And after that,
you can get applications. So take a quick look
at the profiles of these people on these platforms.
And if you like them, send them the test task.
Be polite, be respectful of their time. Explain
that this is how you evaluate candidates in
the first round and that they will get much
further along than other candidates if they
complete the test task and that you do not
use the work output that they do in any way
except to evaluate their skills. Just keep
them motivated and ask them to complete the
test task and send it to you. And when they
respond and send us the test task. You can send
them a Calendly link or send them any meeting
schedule links and get them to schedule a call
with you And the next round is the face to
face interview. We get a chat. We chat with
them. You ask them to explain.