So this is the video on how to create content
in different content formats. And in this video,
I'll explain first the general rules that you
have to follow for all content formats that
you create content on. We'll first talk about
the elements that we could link and copy. So
I'll go through each of the elements that you
should be focusing on. And these apply to all
content formats that we teach you in the IG
program. But the first element that we need
to talk about are optimizing the first three
lines. Now, when you take a look at a post
on LinkedIn, so take a look at this post or
this post or, well, any of the posts on LinkedIn,
LinkedIn only shows us the first two to three
lines of the post at the start. Only if you
click on the see more link, can we see more
of the content. Now, Think of the part before
the C-molec as the headline of an article that
convinces users to click through to read it.
So you will have to spend a lot of time to work
on optimizing these three lines because without
optimizing those three lines nobody is going
to read the post. So and this applies for both
content formats with media formats in them.
So if it's a carousel or an image post or a
video post or a normal text post it applies
to all of them. Here is an example of a great
informative first three lines. So this is of
course by Sam Jacobs, he's a good creator.
Should you exercise your equity when you leave
your startup? I get that question hundreds
of times here. Here's my biggest piece of advice.
So anybody who reads these first three lines,
they will be too enticed to click on the C-Molling
because they just want to understand what the
biggest piece of advice is, which is why you
see good engagement on this content.
hooks which is the name that we give to these
first three lines because we are hooking the
user and getting them to read more of the post.
Let's take a look at some other types of optimizations
some specific types of optimizations that you
can use for these first three lines of hooks.
So the first type of optimization is that of
a paragraph. So here's a paragraph. Columbia's
biggest
It's Latin America's third largest and fastest
growing tech talent hub with 100k skilled highly
skilled engineers. So that's a very a bit of
controversial but at the same time it's a very
interesting thing because not most people have
learned this about Columbia yet. So it's a
new statistic and take a look at this. Just
look at the infamous medley Pablo Escobar and
it's about Pablo Escobar which is already an
interesting topic. So more people will be interested
in checking VC Bowling and hence the engagement
on post. Now this is a hack sort of. With which
you can use a paragraph style beginning to start
your LinkedIn copy Now if we use a lot of white
space like this, we cannot add a lot of content
So if you add like one more line in here, it
won't be shown Before the single link, but if
you use a paragraph you can add include more
content in the first few lines without having
to add spaces so this gives you around like
30 to 50 characters to work with and this is
we first talk about a controversial statement.
So take a look at what we did here. Columbia's
biggest export post pandemic won't be cocaine,
but global tech talent, right? That's a controversial
statement. Then we added data to bracket or
the proof. So this is the data to bracket. It's
Latin America's third largest and fastest-growing
tech talent hub with 100K highly skilled engineers.
And then finally a hint that there's proof
inside of the user clicks on C, okay? So just
look at the infimius. So this is kind of leading
to the proof inside the blaster. Now, I am going
to give you more examples of this exact format
over here. Old Farts 61%, Dynos of 56%, and
old people don't understand, technology 60%,
congrats. You just stumbled into the CDRWF tech,
age discrimination. But is there really age-saving
tech? So it follows the exact same structure
that we mentioned over here. We had our control
of the statement, we add some data in it to
back it, and a hint that there is proof inside
in here. So this is how you use paragraph style
optimization to lead users to click on this
email link. We will talk about hooks in detail
later on, but this is the first type of optimization
that you can use using paragraphs. Now the second
type of optimization is using text and white
space. Now we saw this example already, but
this is using one line spacing in between like
that you can need to click get people to click
on the single link. Now this works very well
on LinkedIn, this works on Twitter a lot you
may have seen this a lot on Twitter especially
in tweets that use tweet threads so people publish
the entire post as a thread in a tweet as opposed
to a single tweet and it's also working very
well on Medium right now. With this you have
about 20 to 25 characters to work with so if
you need more content if you need to add more
is a better format but if you don't need to
just need to add like a short hook then this
is a better format that you can use and let's
take a look at some examples here is another
example old school venture capital is dead founders
just don't want money anymore here's why right
it's a very simple hook where you start with
a quarter versus statement
and then lead people to get them to click on
the Zemo link. Here is more examples. So this
is example three where we see most startups
do not fail because of a bad idea. In fact,
ideas is the little element. So it is controversy.
Here is why they really fail. So we are leading
them to the proof inside and get them to click
on the Zemo link. Let me show you one more
example. there's a massive misconception about
crypto and it's just not true. Crypto not equal
to scams, here's proof versus fiat. Right, so
we're starting off with the controversial statements
and we're leading them to click on the Simulink.
Now Now the third type of optimization is specific
for posts with media, so any kind of media,
so it can be videos, it can be images, polls
and slide posts or carousels. So for text posts
we have three lines that we can optimize, like
the examples that we just saw, we have three
lines that we can use to lead people to the
CMO leg, but for media, any posts with media,
we only have two lines, the dictionary only
offers us two lines, this may change later on,
but at the moment we only have two lines.
that get people to click on the CBO link and
read the rest of the post copy. So in such
cases, we get to the controversy faster and
we need people to the proof that is covered
inside the post copy faster. So we start off
with a controversial statement in one single
line, so it needs to be shorter and then we
add one single line to get people to click
on the CBO example of a pole and this is another
example of a carousel so stop using keyword
difficulties goes in SU tools so that's a very
controversial statement because keyword difficulty
is typically used a lot in SU tools all SUs
use them and then he's talking about keyword
difficulty only considers one variable backlinks
so I get that now I'm curious as a as an ex-SU
because now I want to understand what are the
variables are included or like why is a keyword
So we leading people into click on the Cmolink
very quickly. So one controversy statement
and then the leading in To the rest of the post
copy. So it's not way more faster than typical
Expose Now while these are good examples of
the structure that you should follow or the
hook optimization guidelines that you have to
keep in mind while creating the hook or the
first three lines of your post. It's quite difficult
to like keep coming up with new hooks for each
and every single post that you create which
is why we've created, we've included over a
hundred viral hook ideas that we've tested that
we figured out in the past and we use these
constantly for our own posts. So these are all
borrowed. online from other creators or the
well-known creators and Our own booths that
we've created in the past and we've organized
them in the playbook for you So all you need
to do every single time you you're looking
to create a good hook is come in here Scroll
through all the hooks that we've used over
here and just use them According to the outline
that is offered over here So what I'm gonna
do is I'm gonna go through some of these and
I'm gonna explain like how to use a hook So
that you can use these in your booths. Take
a look at this one Give me two minutes and
I'll teach you six rules to be charismatic.
So if you're writing a post about building
your charisma, this is a hook that you can use.
Now what I've included in brackets over here
is an outline that is built around this hook.
So we've reverse engineered the hook and created
an outline for you. So give me x minutes and
I'll teach you y rules, okay, to achieve whatever
desirable thing it is.
teaching construction project managers about
managing their team better. I would kind of
personalize this to say give me three minutes
and I'll teach you seven cardinal rules to
manage your team in the best fashion, manage
your construction workforce in the best fashion
or manage a project in the best fashion. So
whatever topic or like value addition you're
offering in the post which is the
to like 2 minutes and extra rolls or like 6
rolls or 7 rolls or whatever it is. So that
is how you use a hook. So this is an example
of the hook, the original hook and this is
the reverse engineered outline that you can
use on it. Here's another one, the 95 is getting
pummeled. So this is a bold opening statement,
so which is why we reverse engineer that if
you have an outline over here, the grade designation
is growing faster than ever. So we are adding
more fuel to the fire and love it. Why? loop.
So, to get lead people into the C MOLING. So,
here is another simple hook that you can use
for a lot of different types of content that
you create. Most advice about X is wrong, a
lot of personal plan advice will set you up
for failure. So, we say a lot of what they teach
is wrong. So, how about a specific topic? Here
are five things you should ignore if you are
thinking of getting started. So we say reveal
common means that Guru is right. So that is
another outline for a hook that you can use
to create a piece of content. Now here is another
one, how to make money on LinkedIn. So we promised
to teach something valuable and how to build
the algo. Then we add a second promise. In
a second, you'll read about how to take advantage
of LinkedIn, how to beat the algo, how you
can monetize. So we get teasing them and building
the anticipation You can feel free to edit
these, feel free to add your own hooks in the
future, in your own copy or your own documents
that you use for the copywriters so that over
time, you build a good hook database. But these
100 viral hooks should be a very good starting
point to help you craft really good hooks for
your posts for different types of content. So
this is not restricted to any one content format
you can use these for all types of content formats.
So after the hook optimization or the optimizing
the first three lines, the next element we come
to is the paragraph optimization. So by default
whenever a writer creates content, the idea
is to create paragraphs. So that is only the
case language works, you create paragraphs as
combinations of sentences. But when you are
creating social media content, you need to follow
a different approach. The truth is nobody reads
long paragraphs anymore. Paragraphs should be
short and broken down into multiple short sentences
because what for attention. If you add like
clunky paragraphs or long paragraphs subconsciously
whenever a reader is seeing that paragraph they
immediately think there is a lot of work to
see that paragraph and they would not read it
irrespective of how good the post may be or
how valuable the content may be. So this is
something that you always have to keep in mind
when you are creating content. What I am about
to show you is a few examples of well structured
posts even if there are paragraphs so that they
have kept the paragraphs with sentences short
and with one line proper one line spacing so
that whenever a reader sees the post they just
read through the lines. If they do not like
say get blocked or they do not feel a subconscious
blocker to reading that post because when they
see like clunky paragraphs they do not feel
that simply because the structure dwell. So
this is the right way to optimize your paragraphs.
So take a look at this one what this reader
job what this creator Jonathan has done is
he's included an okay hook not a very good hook
a little bit but take a look at his how he
structured it so he's added a topic and he's
added two lines spaced by with a one line spacing.
Next topic two paragraphs but again spaced out
well. Again a topic and then again these are
basically sentences but again. with one line
spacing in them. So they've done it really
well as opposed to like say using something
like this. So this is a very bad example of
how you shouldn't be doing it. So adding like
say very sizable paragraphs with like multiple
lines over two sentences is a very bad idea.
Take a look at this one. Immediately like as
you see something like this as opposed to seeing
something like this. He won't make this decision
consciously, the reader won't make this decision
consciously. As soon as they see something
like this, their eye will just skip away. subconsciously
because they do not want to read, they do not
want to take a lot of put a lot of work into
reading something. Consumption should be made
as easy as possible so that they can read through
the post and understand what you are talking
about. So it is a very simple thing to do all
you need to do is create short sentences and
always add one line spacing in between those
lines. So formatting optimization is the next
step and it is just like paragraph optimization,
but what we are trying to do here is the way
the information is presented to the audience
in the most. So there is two things that we
need to focus on here. take two types of formatting
it was. So, one is what we call skimming. So,
skimming is when you create a post that is very
easily consumable, very easily readable. And
for that we use what we call meme style formatting.
So, meme style formatting is something that
has been popularized by a creator called Justin
Welch. So, what he does is he creates quickly
readable short posts. So, most of the posts
that you see on LinkedIn and he just adds quick
bullet points like a very quick pointer on how
it looks. It is not exactly like paragraphs,
it is not exactly one lines because he is structuring
them accordingly. So, if it is eight questions,
so the eight questions are written as one liners
and then there are a few other lines for the
intro or the hook and the
Here is another example of something by Jess
Cook. So Jess Cook is also a content marketer.
So take a look at this. So she is talking about.
tackling the first research reporter. So, this
is one topic, so starting the first three steps
for the starting and that leads to the survey
questions which is the next two steps for the
survey questions which leads to the top line
stats, the next two questions for the top line
stats. So, you see how the formatting is done
for each of these. So, she is categorized them
into specific topics or stages in the process
that she is about to cover, that she wants to
cover and it is segregated or segmented accordingly
in the post. So, come up with skimmability is
all about coming up with easy to read formats
that people can quickly skim through. So, skimming
is reading very quickly. So, take a look at
the 60 second
one type of content, four of them. Pick your
industrial level topic, four of them. So, people
can read these quickly and this type of content
performs really well. We format it in this
manner, it performs really well for the simple
reason that people can consume it very quickly.
and read through it really quickly. Always remember
that copywriting is all about, the first line
should be about getting users to read the second
line, the second line should be about getting
readers to read the third line. So, every single
line in your post should be optimized for getting
people to be able to consume it quickly, you
need to reduce the friction of, of the mental
friction of people having to. read the post
and spend time of the post. So make it as easy
as possible for them. This is the goal of formatting.
Now what we took a look at over here is called
skimming optimization. There is another type
of formatting that we can use which is called
concentrating. So concentrating is about getting
people to focus on a specific topic and we
keep like a few paragraphs or lines in between.
So This is very good for formats like listicle.
So for example, we already saw this example
where Jonathan wrote a four pointer about four
pointer post about major content books you need
for like a paid social strategy. So he talked
about thought leadership and some detail about
thought leadership, product marketing and some
detail about product marketing, social proof
and some detail about social proof. So he is
concentrating on each of these topics one by
one and detailing about it. So that is the
way he is formatted the content of the post.
Now you can use both of these elements in your
content but pay some attention to the skimming
formatting because it's a very important formatting
element that you need to keep in mind when you
structure the content of your posts and this
is across the board for all content formats
all types of content formats you create not
specifically for like informative posts which
is what this content format is.
Yeah, all of these are informative posts, content
formats. Now we have lead videos later on in
the program that are dedicated to each content
format. that will teach you about how the content
management process looks like in the content
world for each of the content formats one by
one. I'll talk about how the content management
process works in ClickUp. I'll talk about how
the content ideation process works and how we
can go about creating the content formats easily.
And I'll talk about the differences in the content
creation for each of those content formats
as well. But the next topic we are moving on
to is hashtags. So hashtags are important because
they help you categorize your post, help the
algorithm categorize your post and present
it to a more relevant audience. And the typical
usage of hashtags is very wrong you could say.
Even on LinkedIn because what most users do
is they add they find a lot of relevant hashtags
that you later to the post They don't do much
research about it And they assume that adding
more hashtags will get you more reach that is
completely wrong The way hashtags work on LinkedIn
is clearly outlined in the LinkedIn algorithm
report And what it states what it found is
that statistically Posts with hashtags more
than five hashtags tend to reduce the reach
of the post. So the maximum number of hashtags
that you should be adding in your post should
be five so you shouldn't go beyond five now
how do we select these hashtags which is the
big question so selecting these hashtags is
done by manually researching so assume let's
take this post as an example so this is about
content buckets you need for successful paid
social strategy right so social media marketing
is obviously the first hashtag that I would
consider so what I would do is I would type
a hashtag at the start and then I would do
social media marketing now what I would
to see how many followers it has because The
best hashtags have the most number of followers
So ideally you should be selecting hashtags
that are topically relevant to your posts and
at the same time have a good following So if
I wanted to compare social media marketing
and social media I could easily see
that social media has way more followers than
social media marketing. So if I was to choose
between social media and social media marketing,
I would definitely go with social media. Now
how do you find more hashtags? So product marketing
is one of the... Pointers mentioning here thought
leadership is a point I mentioned in here. So
all of these are Our stuff I could include
all of this is basically about Content marketing
in general or marketing in general. So all
of these are hashtags that I can search for
I would look for specific more niche Topics
so I've included social media in here. So now
what I could do is I would look for product
Marketing let's see if product marketing is
there and see like what the hashtag what the
follower count is So what eight thousand followers
not too bad, but I wouldn't see it's too big
either So let's try to find some better hashtags
So single image ads so they're talking about
advertising right so advertising is a good broad
hashtag that I could use so advertising if
you take a look at it should have okay large
number of followers so this is a good hashtag
I can use and then we're talking about successful
paid social strategy so it's basically social
media advertising, social advertising. So let's
take a look at social advertising. Okay, not
very impressive. So we'll keep doing this process
until I figure out some good hashtags. So image
ads, let's see, okay, image ads doesn't seem
to have much. So let's see, how about ads,
like just ads? That should be a hashtag. Okay,
not very big, but somewhat okay. Thought leadership,
how about thought leadership?
Boom 26,000 there you got your third hashtag.
So this is how you go about doing this. So
we have content So content and content marketing
are both Stuff you would consider so content
marketing seems to have A good number of followers
and content also seems to have a good number
of followers. I'm pretty sure it has quite a
large follow, basically 61,000. So there, we
have found our five hashtags. So this is how
you go about doing it. You take a look at the
post that you've already written and you do
searches on LinkedIn to identify the most relevant
hashtags. Now, over time, you should ideally
be creating a hashtag list of the best hashtags
that you can use for your content. And this
is the hashtag sheet in the content analysis
sheet. So it's a simple sheet. We just have
the hashtag where you can include the hashtags
and the follower count so that over time, you
can build a list of hashtags that have very
good followings on LinkedIn. So whenever you
create a post, come in here and drop the hashtags
on the follower counts in here. When you're
writing the post itself, so that over time,
it'll be very easy for you to just copy paste
hashtags and use them in your content. the
best hashtags with really good follow-ups and
save a lot of time. And now that we're done
with hashtags, let's talk a bit about publishing
content on LinkedIn. So publishing process,
this part of the video specifically for your
team members who are handling the publishing
process. If you're doing this yourself, great.
But this is quite simple. For any kind of content
that you wanna publish, you can do it from here.
So all you need to do is click on start a post,
which will bring a pop-up. this icon over here
there are all the different media types that
you want to create or include so if you want
to create an event directly from your user
profile you can do it here if you want to create
a poll you can do it here if you want to add
a carousel or a slide post to your post you
can add it here if you want to add an image
or a photo you can do it here if you want to
add a video you can do it here. Let me go through
like say some of the content
so that it's easy for you. So this is some sample
post copy that I'm just doing, using for showing
you how to create a post. So you add the post,
make sure the line spacing is correct. This
is important. It has to be exactly as it is
in Raptor in ClickUp. So, however it is in
ClickUp, I make sure it's come, you come in
here and it's formatted exactly the same way.
Sometimes the way this format in ClickUp, when
you copy paste it into LinkedIn, there may
be like additional spaces like these. or the
spaces may be absent. So make sure you review
both the ClickUp content card or task and look
at it and come back here and make sure the
formatting is exactly the same way. All right,
then make sure that the tags that are included
of people in ClickUp are mentioned the correct
way. So the real tag is suppose I want to include
Immortal Tag Captura, which is a company in
here. at the rate and I would select the correct
company from here. So in most cases the copywriters
will mention like which company it is in the
post copy itself so that you can tag the correct
company in brackets. So make sure that gets
done properly. Pay special attention to tagging
the correct company and then if there's any
additional details mentioned by the copywriters
in brackets on which our company is to be tagged
or the company page URL or something like that
or the company page username or something like
that. Please make sure you remove that bracket
and just tag the correct person. That is just
given for reference so that you can tag the
correct companies. And then after you select
the correct companies like this, make sure the
spacing is correct, make sure the CTAs are
correct, the hashtags selected correctly. So
after you take a quick look at this, look at
formatting options. So formatting is about making
sure points if any bullet points have been
included in ClickUp make sure the bullet points
are mentioned correctly are given correctly
so for example if is these three points were
bullet points I have to come in here and manually
added this one two three, right? Or if the bullet
points are just not numbered, they're just
normal bullet points, you can come in here and
manually add in here as bullet points in this
manner. All right, so please pay special attention
before you hit publish to the formatting. It
is very important on LinkedIn. And after you're
done with that, take a look at any media that
is supposed to be added. So if you're just creating
like a text post, so experiential stories,
informative posts. engagement page, customer
experience text stories, then if it is a viral
post, it is like viral text post or viral influencer
persona, text post or similar formats, it is
all just text. So, in that case, it is this
is a good to go and you can go ahead and schedule
a publish directly. But in case there is media
to be added, media can be an image. So, if
it is an image post, it will be included in
the. Clickup task for that specific content
piece and in the later videos I will be explaining
how you can how the process differs for each
content format. But These three buttons over
here cover almost every single content format
that you would want to publish on LinkedIn.
So these are image posts for all posts that
include images. Just click on this, click on
select images to share and select the screenshot.
So whatever the screenshot is, you can select
it over here.
So here's an image that I'm just using to demonstrate
how it's done. So I just uploaded the image,
I can add the post copy in here and then I can
click on this pencil icon over here to. edit
it so I can crop the image as I see fit I can
zoom in as I see fit I can straighten or like
rotate it as I see fit all of this stuff is
possible I can add filters to the image as
well but I can also tag people on the post so
if you're if it's of an event or something
like that there's additional team members that
are in the photo or there's additional influencers
you took a
include them in the post of that they get notifications
that they were tagged in a post and so on just
like how we do on Facebook and so on all of
that stuff can be done in here. For videos
there is a small difference that we can also
include thumbnail images for the videos. So
let me show you that quickly as well. So I'm
going to drag and drop a video. Okay, that
content format is not supported. And we can
see the supported content formats here so that
you understand what format the video should
be in and the issue. Let's go back and let
me upload our direct content format.
I click on video, I select a test file to upload,
and while it's loading, I can upload a thumbnail.
So this is where you click on upload thumbnail
and select the thumbnail image. So you should
have downloaded the thumbnail image from the
clicker class to your computer, your laptop
or PC, and then uploaded it. And you can also
auto-generate captions if you'd like. and you
can also review the captions before viewers
can see them so you can edit them quickly stuff
through them but in most cases if you're creating
videos we have a subtitling process in the
clicker class so there should be or there could
be an SRT file in the clicker class so take
a look at it and you can also upload an SRT
file instead of auto generating captions in
English all right and once you're done you can
click on done and add the post copy and you're
good to go
it's a PDF file that you need to upload so you
need to select the document option over here
so at the bottom click on the document option
click on choose file and then finally click
on the PDF that you want to upload so I'm taking
this one as an example because it's a PDF I
click on open and we can add a title so the
title is displayed in LinkedIn so ideally add
like the relevant document
about you can just add that topic in there.
The topic can be the same topic of the clickable
task as well and once you are done with that
you can click on done. So let me just enter
a text for now. You can enter your own title.
But once you add, upload the PDF and you add
the post copy, you can go ahead and schedule
a quick publish. So that's it. This is how
you publish content. Now, the only other thing
that you'll need to do in terms of like after
the publishing process is collecting the analytics.
So let's take a look at the posts and see how
we can collect the analytics.
Just copying the link to the LinkedIn post,
just click on this button over here at the
side of the post and click on copy link to the
post and the post should be, the post link
should be copied to your clipboard and then
you can paste them after you publish it to
the click of task. And in addition to that if
you want to take a look at the... view counts
so just come to the post and in here you should
be able to see like the impressions you can
also see additional stats but you can get the
like count the comment count the repost count
as well as the impressions in here if you click
on this button you can also see the analytics
for the post if you'd like to see if you'd like
to take a look at additional analytics for
your analytics process and you can see viewer
demographics on like say what the job titles
are
people that engage with the post and so on.
So this is how you go about collecting analytics
and copying post links of the posts and the
content that you publish on LinkedIn. Now content
promotion which comes after publishing is an
advanced process. So we are covering it in
the later modules. So you will need to progress
after the content creation step. into the growth
hack in your content engine what you will do.
understand how to promote your content, learn
how to promote your content. We did cover a
quick video on using GlingBoost at the start
of the content marketing modules. So you can
use the same process, but we cover far more
detailed processes on how to promote your content
manually using manual communities of pods as
well as using automated tools like GlingBoost
and GlamPod later on in the program. So you
can either choose to not follow the promotion
steps until that stage until you've gotten there
to those videos or you can take a look at those
videos right now in the growth acne content
engine and you can start with the promotion
activity as well using manual automated pods.
one of the final lessons in this video. is the
times to post. So it is very important that
you go publish your content at the right time
when you receive the most engagement. So what
we've done here is in the content format sheet,
we've included the best times to post, a screenshot
of the best times to post. These suggested times
come from the LinkedIn algorithm report, which
is a statistical study that discovered the best
times to post, when LinkedIn post received
the best engagement. So this is the best data
back source that we have right now on when
you will receive the most engagement. Now the
good thing is that we have this but the bad
thing is that the times differ on several days.
So if you take a look at Sundays it's from
1 p.m. to around 3 p.m. On one days it's from
10 a.m. to around 1 p.m. On Tuesdays it's 8
a.m. to around 11 a.m. On Wednesdays it's 9
a.m. to around 12 a.m. I'm sorry 12 p.m. Thursdays
its from 8am to 11am, Fridays from 1pm to 3pm
and Saturdays its from 11pm to 10 a.m. to 1
p.m. So you can either choose like a slot that
works on most days and choose to ignore the
remaining days. Say for example 10 a.m. is a
time slot that works on most days which is
why in most of the coaching calls we recommend
10 a.m. for most of you. But please remember
that these time zones are for the time zones
of your target audience. So if you're located
in Europe
need to be focusing on the time zones in the
US audience, time zones of the US audience
and publishing at 10 am in their time zone.
In similar fashion if you are in the US and
you are targeting an audience in EU or the European
Union, you need to be focusing on time zones
in the European Union and publishing it at those
time zones at 10 am. So 10 am is just a suggestion,
you can choose to publish at the most optimal
time. So the most optimal times for each of
these days will be the start of these times.
slots so that's 1 p.m. on Sundays, 10 a.m.
on Mondays, 8 a.m. on Tuesdays, 9 a.m. on Wednesdays,
8 a.m. on Thursdays, 1 p.m. on Fridays and
10 a.m. on Saturdays. So these are the best
times to post for each of these days. If you're
manually publishing this and promoting the content
this will be a bit difficult but the best way
you can structure this process is to set due
dates and reminders and allow. or calendar
blockers which is the best option for these
specific times in the calendars of the team
members who are handling the posting. So what
I recommend is blocking of your calendars at
this exact time. If the strategy you want to
follow is posting at the most optimal times.
If for convenience you want to post at the best
time, just add a scheduled calendar blocker
at 10 a.m. on every day and just post and promote
and engage on the content during that period.
Now, let us see how to do this. So, let us say
that I have a video on a particular topic.
While replying to comments is an optional part
of this process, especially when you're getting
started and you just want to create and promote
a post, this is something that takes a significant
amount of time investment. But time and time
again, we've come across creators or participants
in the program who have achieved really good
results simply because they were engaging on
every single comment. So we've included a process
for this in the click-up boards as well. So
after you publish and promote every single post.
Ideally, you should be setting aside the calendar
blocker not just for publishing and promoting
the post but also for the time required for
engaging with the users that comment. Now which
is why we have.
recommend that those calendar blockers that
you scheduled for the publishing at different
times or at the same time every day be for a
minimum of one hour so that after you publish
and promote the post you can come in here wait
for the automated pod comments or the manual
pod comments or the genuine comments from the
users to trickle in time by time so they'll
trickle in like say over the first hour and
Whenever you receive a comment, keep reloading
the page. Whenever you receive a comment, reply
with a really good response. Ideally tag the
people who drop the comment so that they can
come in here, include some questions at the
end of the comment on.
their comments so that you can proceed with
the conversation. So here are some examples
of say how we do this. Say for example, say
here, has dropped a comment, I love the idea
of setting expectations on each team member,
I have to ensure that everyone is on the same
page and working towards the same goals. So
we just responded with absolutely setting clear
expectations, essentially we're ensuring that
everyone is aligned and working towards the
same goals, which can lead to greater success.
We focus on employee happiness is so refreshing,
it gets, it's great to see a leader who sees,
who values their team as people, not just workers.
And we respond obviously, thank you for doing
that, app is crucial to creating a positive
environment where everyone can thrive and succeed.
So you can also choose to create these comments,
these responses to the comments automatically
in CharsgVD. So the process that we teach you
in the content promotion videos later on. in
the growth-acquired engine modules, covers
the process for creating these comments. All
you need to do is edit that prompt a little
bit. If you also want the... the comments to
be generated here, comments that applies to
the comments also to be automatically generated
by ggbt. This is not a process that I would
recommend though. This would save you a lot
of time if you just want to do this and just
assign it to a team member and not spend a lot
of time or focus on it. But ideally, you should
be manually taking a look at every single comment
that comes in and responding manually, engaging
with them, liking the comments, reviewing if
these prospects are good prospects. So if C
is a good prospect. fits my bypass or not I
could start a conversation with him right now
simply because he dropped a comment. So that
sums up this video. where we talked about creating
content in different content formats. We went
through the different elements that make good
LinkedIn post copy. We talked about how we'll
be having dedicated videos for each content
format later on. We talked about hashtags, how
to publish content on LinkedIn with different
media formats, how promotions are advanced tactic
and how we can do it later on in the process.
And finally, we talked about the best times
to post, how to block your calendars for the
best times to post based on the time slots mentioned
in here. which are the most optimal times to
post and in the later videos in this module
we will be getting into the dedicated processes
for each content format so that you can understand
exactly how to ideate and create content for
each of those content formats. That is it for
this video, see you in the next one.