So let's take a look at how to
schedule weekly content ideation
calls and assign content tasks.
So first, let's talk about what
is the content ideation call.
So the content ideation call is ideally
a weekly call with the content team
comprising of the executive, the
content manager, and the copywriters
who are involved in the creation of
the content piece and The content
manager will be moderating these calls.
So what that means is, they'll
take in charge of the calls,
they'll schedule the calls or the
calendars of the team members.
They'll set up the call, they make sure
everyone attends and they'll be moderating
the call as in leading the call and
directing what to discuss on the call.
The content ideation calls
have a specific purpose.
The purpose is to discuss content, review
content generate ideas and discuss ideas
with the executive and get approvals
on, on existing content pieces that have
already been created in the previous week.
So The management of the entire content
ideation was done by the content manager,
of course but all of the team members
will actively participate in these calls
by asking questions to the executive and
the executive is the thought leader who
has the expertise in the niche expertise
in the content and the knowledge to
create really good content will be
sharing and answering those questions
and sharing their ideas and, and.
thoughts and opinions and their
own experiences and so on on
the content ideation call.
Now there is an ideal structure
for a content ideation call.
So this is the structure that has
worked for us over the past few years.
So on every content ideation call,
which is typically at least one hour
each, the first 20 minutes will go
towards content review and feedback.
The second 20 minutes will go towards
the content manager and the copywriters
discussing the ideas they came up
with, with the executive and asking
the executive to add more information
and knowledge to that idea or opinion.
Say for example.
You come across a new story
about let's take construction
as an example niche for this.
If you come across a post idea in
construction, say on how construction
is a risky industry, then once the
content copywriter or content manager
adds it to ClickUp as a content idea
these ideas will be discussed with the
executive and the executive will share
their own opinions on that specific.
News post on that specific topic of
construction being a risky business, and
they may share an experience or two, or
they may share their own take on it, and
this is what we mean by the interview.
So for, after each idea is shared in
the next 20 minutes, the second slot
the content manager and copywriter
can ask questions about that specific
idea to the executive, and the
executive will share those ideas.
They first approve those
ideas if they're good or not.
If they're bad ideas,
they can reject them.
If they're good ideas, they can
share their opinions on them.
And the content manager and the copywriter
will note them down in the cleanup task.
We'll explain more about this.
But the last 20 minutes of the content
ideation call are of the executives
sharing their own content ideas.
So this can also include
them sharing their opinions.
on questions asked by the
copywriter and the content manager.
But this time will be exclusively
for the executives to share
their own content pieces.
And if we have time left the copywriters
and content managers can ask more
questions and continue the second stage.
So, let's take a look at what
each of these are in detail.
So, but before we get into that,
we need to discuss what happens
before the content addition call.
So, before the content addition call,
before every content addition call
that happens ideally in a weekly
fashion, the content manager ensures
that at least two content ideas for
each content calendar, content format,
or admin click up and outlines.
So, in the content format sheet in the
content analysis, Work spreadsheet.
We've already detailed the content
formats that we'll be using in this cycle.
So we can constantly change this and
like add more content formats from
the content format queue and test more
formats, but Considering that we are
using these formats to get started with
our content management process or content
marketing process These are the content
formats that the content manager should
be checking to ensure that they have at
least Two content ideas for each of these
content formats So we need to make sure
that we have at least two experiences
to these two slide posts to kna video
ideas to informative post ideas And to
engage in beta ideas now i'm not talking
about the finished post i'm talking
about topic ideas for each of these.
We will dive deep into how to ideate
content for experiences stories and
for each of these content formats,
in fact for all of these content
formats later on in this module.
But this is just so that you understand
like what is supposed to be done
right before the content ideation
call when you actually go ahead and
schedule a content ideation call.
So two content ideas for each of the
content calendar content formats,
so these are the content calendar
content formats And they need to
be added in ClickUp in outlines.
So they need to create a copy of
the template card, like we discussed
earlier, and they need to add it as
in ClickUp in the outline section.
It may not be a finished outline.
A finished outline will be created
only during the content edition call
or after the content ideation call.
But this needs to be done.
Now, It's not necessary that the
content manager creates comes up
with all these ideas by themselves.
So it's not always it's not the case that
they they need to do the research and come
up with the ideas They can also ask the
copywriters to come up with ideas So if
the copywriters you can content manager
can reach out to the copywriters every
week once every week and i'll tell them
that okay You need to come up with three
two post ideas for experience stories
two post ideas for Slight pose and two
post ideas for q and a videos and the
remaining he can either do it himself Or
he can assign it to the same copywriter
or assign it to a different copywriter.
It's up to him.
So based on your working setup,
the process might change.
But the goal is that we ensure that at
least two content ideas for each content
format are added in ClickUp and Outlines.
Now doing like say the ideation process
is covered in detail later on this module.
But let's move on to the first 20
minutes and the ideal structure and,
and what we do in the first 20 minutes.
Now, During the first 20 minutes
we'll take a few actions.
So first the content manager will
share their screen, present their
screen on the call, and present
the content pieces in the need
executive approval stage in ClickUp.
So it's in the need of executive
approval that we have the finished
content pieces and all the executive
needs to do is review the, the pieces
and either they can give the feedback.
About that content piece if they have any
feedback and they need something revised
or edited Or they can straight away say
that this post is approved and it go to
the approval queue now So what the content
manager will do is content manager will
either update the status of that content
piece So if it's approved, of course, it
will go to the next queue in the process,
which is the ready to be posted queue but
if it is not approved it will go to the
previous stage in the process, which is
Drafts so that the copywriter can edit
that content piece again and then send
it again to the copywriter for reviewing.
So the content manager for reviewing.
So these are the three steps
that the content manager will
take during the first 20 minutes
because it is for content review.
So ideally The content reviewing should be
done on the content ideation calls itself.
So a lot of executives because they
like to sit and think through about
before they approve a piece of content
they will recommend that this can
be done after the call, so that the
call can just be used for meetings.
But the purpose of the content edition
call is not just to communicate.
The different tasks that were done and
the different tasks that are to be done.
The purpose of the content addition
call is also to give the copywriters as
well as the content manager a very good
idea about what the executive prefers.
Because not all of this content will
be published on the company pages.
They can also be published
on the user profiles.
And many of these posts will have to
include the personality and tone of
voice of the Executive so ideally the
reviewing and the feedback needs to
be given on the call itself so that
the content manager and copywriter can
live ask questions and understand more
about the tone of voice and the type of
content formats and the type of writing
that the that the executive prefers.
So this feedback has to be live on
the call itself and not later on.
So as much as possible, the content
manager will make sure that the
executive will give the feedback on
the calls itself, give approvals and
review the posts on the calls itself.
And they will facilitate this
by sharing their screen and
going through each click up.
task that is ready in
the EX Approval stage.
So that's the Executive Approval stage.
They'll go through each of those
ClickUp tasks, they'll share the screen,
they'll walk them through the post
and they'll make sure it's approved.
Now once, I'll straight away show
you how to do this in ClickUp.
So, here is a ClickUp post example.
So this is a slide post that is
in the need executive approval.
So we have the outline, we have the
slide content already created, we
have the post copy added in here, and
we also have the slide that has been
designed by the design team and this
is ready for the executive's approval.
So what the content manager will do
in the review process is first they
will share their screen and present
this piece they'll walk them through
walk the executive through the slide
content and then the post copy and
then the designed post and how it
looks like and if everything is
good to go then the Content manager
will move it to the approved queue.
So the approved queue after need executive
approval will be ready to be posted on
the user profile and the company page.
So they can move it to the queue,
but if the executive has any feedback
on it, they can drop a comment
to tagging the, the copywriter.
So assume this is the copywriter.
This is me, but assume it's a copywriter.
And you'll see here's...
Feedback for edits.
All right.
And they can just mentioned
like a bulleted list of
change a Change B and so on.
So that the copywriter can go ahead and
make the changes and then commented.
And then after that, what the copywriter
will will do, the content manager will
do, is take a look at the subtasks.
So in the subtasks they can see
that all these tasks still, the
content managers the executives
approval has been completed.
So it's in this stage right now, but
since the, we need edits in this.
This has to be reverted back to the
drafts queue or if the edits are design
suggestions, it can be done in this queue.
So he will have to move it, this back
to assigned and this back to assigned.
So that moves back to that stage.
And then he'll move it back to a
waiting media file, which is the stage.
So it's really simple.
We just move it back to two queues
so that the design can be edited.
By the designer who's working on it.
So that sums up this step.
And finally, the updated status
and note the feedback in the
ClickUp Tasks requirement,
which they've already done here.
And that should be it.
Now, the second step in the content
addition call is when Content
manager and the copywriter will
suggest ideas, will present the
ideas that they've come up with.
So, some of the content formats
have to be ideated only on the
calls by the copywriters and content
managers, ideating, say, experiential
stories with the executive.
But some content formats, like especially
the viral content formats, almost all
the viral content formats in Viral
Newsguy and, Viral influencer personas
can all be created before the call.
So right before the call, they can
come up with the ideas of, they don't
need like a lot of input from the
executive for each of these ideas.
They just need to be reviewed by
the executive and feedback given on
whether that's a good idea or not.
Again, this is not a content like
fully created content piece reviewer.
So that was this, this first minute,
20 minutes of the call is only for
content that is ready to be approved.
So it's fully created.
This is simply for the ideas
that the content manager and the
copywriter have come up with.
So all of these ideas will
be present in the outlines.
So the content manager makes sure
that two ideas for each of the content
formats in the content calendar
have been added in the outline stage
before the content edition call.
So on the call they will come in
and they will share their screen
and present these content ideas.
In the outline stage in ClickUp and
the executive just needs to review
the ideas and, and be interviewed by
the content manager and copywriter.
So if it's a simple idea, like, okay,
here's a news idea about this particular
topic what are your thoughts about this?
What is your opinion about this?
So the executive will share their own
opinions and share their own thought
leadership and take on that specific
topic and the content manager adds
notes and feedback in the ClickUp task
in comments as a comment, just like
we did during the first 20 minutes
so that this idea can be worked on.
Now.
In after this step, after the next,
this 20 minutes, the next 20 minutes is
exclusively for Executives Content Ideas.
Now the executive will have a bunch of
topics that he or she wishes to share or
talk about on the Content ideation call.
And this part of the call
is specifically for that.
So they'll share the topics or ideas.
They want the content team to generate
content on both the content manager
and copywriters will interview
ask more questions so that the
executive can dive deeper into
that specific idea they suggest and
get more details of those ideas.
So the.
The role of the executive is
to share and answer questions.
And the role of the content managers
here at this step is to ask more
questions, more broad questions.
So they understand a lot more
about the ideas that are being
shared by the executives.
Now, the content manager will direct
the conversation towards our content
formats where ideation is still pending.
So in this section itself the content
managers should take a look at the content
filter, ensure that all the content.
The ideation for the content
formats listed in the content
format sheet have been completed.
If more ideas are needed in that area,
the content manager will direct the
conversation towards those content formats
where the ideation is still pending.
And whenever like an idea is shared
by the executive or a feedback
is given by the executive or, or
experiences are shared by the executor
for say an experiential story.
The content manager will create
new content tasks from the template
cards for the respective content
format that the ideas are for.
So if an experiential story is
being shared, they'll make a
copy of the experiential story.
template card template task and
add the idea in the outline section
and update the parent task status
as outlines in the ClickUp task.
So by default, whenever you create a
copy or duplicate the template card,
the status will be template itself.
So that has to be changed to the
outline skew so that now we know
that an outline has to be created.
For that specific idea.
So this is the structure of
the content edition calls.
The first 20 minutes of review and
feedback of content that is already
created the next 20 minutes of the
executive reviewing and approving and
giving feedback on ideas shared by the
content manager and copywriter and the
next 20 minutes of executing sharing
topics that they want to talk about.
Plus the content manager also making sure
that all the content formats that are in
the content calendar have been ideated.
Now let's take a look at what happens
after the content reduction call
because this is where most of the
assigning of the content tasks happens.
So the content manager first reviews
the content calendar and ensures that
two content pieces for each content
task have been assigned for the content
formats in the content calendar.
So if we take a look at the content
calendar, you can see that we have
five content formats at all times
scheduled for like Mondays to Fridays
because we are posting every day.
So why are we scheduling, why
are we assigning two posts for
each of these content formats?
So here's the reason.
You need to build up a buffer of content.
You need to build up a, a database
of content that has already been
created, reviewed, and approved
over time as you continue with
the content marketing process.
Now, the only way to do this is
to create content in advance.
So even if you only create need
to create like five posts per
week, create 10 posts per week.
So make sure that you have five piece
content pieces in advanced that the
team has already worked on that is
ready to go live and approved by the.
by the executive so that
they can be published.
Now over time this will help you a lot
because if you have like one month of
content that has already been created
in advance, even if you miss a content
ideation call or two because of a vacation
or because of the executive being busy.
This won't be an issue later
on, but the executive could be
busy at, at some point of time.
They tend to be busy and a content
edition caller too could get skipped.
So it's, it's always a good idea to
always assign two content, two content
pieces to the copywriters for each content
format that is in the content calendar.
All right.
Now the, the content manager will
also direct the copywriters to
add two content ideas for each
content format for the next call.
So for the call that happens on the next
week, the content ideation call, the
content manager will also suggest the
content ideas that has to be created.
So they can assign it accordingly
and they can tell them, okay,
these are the content formats.
I'd like you to come up with two
content ideas for each of these content
formats that are to be discussed on
the next week's content addition call.
So that the ideation is also progressing
parallelly for the next batch of
content for the next week's cycle.
Let's also take a quick look at what
happens during the ideation process.
So this typically happens during the
second 20 minute batch of content
ideation where the, the content
manager and copywriter will suggest
ideas to the executive and the
executive will, will approve those
ideas and give feedback on those
ideas or reject those ideas overwrite.
So let's take a look at IDEAP.
This is an idea of a post on
why is the construction industry
becoming Canada's pain and we
have an a draft of an outlines.
The outline is not complete yet because
the executive has not approved it.
So this has just been added by your
content manager or copywriter in here.
And after this idea is discussed.
The content manager has to make
notes on the call itself, ideally,
on like additional things to be
included in the, in the slide post.
So for example, add graphs and
comment on data and graphs and
also include the quote from the
founders mentioned in the article.
So this, these kinds of comments
are added after the article or the
source of the news is discussed
on the content ideation call.
So the executive will
share their feedback.
So the feedback has to be noted in here.
And once that is done.
This can be moved to draft.
So once the outline is completed
the content manager can go ahead
and assign it to the copywriter
that will be working on it.
And this will be moved to the next
stage regarding the assigning because
this is the launch of the content
management process for this specific card.
They just need to follow the
checklist for each of the subtasks.
So here are the checklist
for each of the subtasks.
So these are all the things to
be done for the outline step.
And later on in the module we're
covering how to do this for each
content format in a dedicated video,
so you just need to follow that.
But this is what happens during the
second 20 minutes of the content
ideation call, just so you get an idea
on how the outlines creation happens.
Now, let's take a look at some
other important things about
the content ideation calls.
So all content ideation calls should
be recorded as well as transcribed.
This is important because the
copywriters as well as the content
managers will always need to refer
these to understand what the.
Executive is shared.
So a lot of content is discussed
and a lot of experiences are shared.
A lot of opinions are given
by the executives on a one
hour content addition call.
So it's very difficult to note
it all down in like one go.
So it's important that the calls
are recorded as well as transcribed.
The reason transcription is important
is because the copywriters will
often be copying the transcription
and then starting to work on the
script or the post copy from what
was discussed in the transcriptions.
That's the easiest way for them
to go ahead and create start
creating a piece of content.
So for recordings you can use like any
platforms that you can using for meetings
like Google Meet teams, zoom, WebEx.
All of these meet platforms can be used.
All of them offer inbuilt
recording features.
You can also use additional tools
like meeting recording tools like
Fireflies and one of the interesting
features of Fireflies is that it
also has a transcription feature.
So Fireflies will automatically record
as long as Fireflies is synced to
your Gmail account or Outlook account.
It will automatically join the calls.
It will automatically record the calls
and transcribe the calls as well.
And it will also automatically send
the transcriptions and the link
to the recordings to all the team
members that attended those calls.
So it's a very useful
tool if you'd like to.
Record calls.
So this is the setup that I would
recommend for recording and transcribing
your content ideation calls.
Now, I'd also like to touch a bit
about the content manager's role
on the content ideation calls.
Now, since the content manager will be
the primary moderator of these content
edition calls they have to make sure
that they actively promote discussion.
By asking a lot of questions to the
executive, interviewing them properly
so that you get the most out of their
thought leadership, that get the
most out of their expertise in the
specific industry and niche and hold
the other team members accountable
as well for active participation.
So often what happens is the
content manager, if one person
takes a needle, they call the other.
People will just mute and stay silent.
They won't actively
participate and ask questions.
So this is a complete no no
for content ideation calls.
All the copywriters and other parties,
other members attending these calls have
to actively participate, share their
ideas, discuss opinions ask more questions
to the executive so that the executive
can, can share as much as possible about.
different angles about
that, that content topic.
Now this is a constant activity,
so the content manager has
to constantly encourage the
copywriters to ask more questions,
otherwise they just stay dormant.
And then just mute yourself
and just listen to the calls.
That is not the ideal scenario.
The copywriters need to actively
participate and ask questions so that
they can understand everything about
that content format from the executive.
Now often like whenever in like
technical content topics or like a very
specific content topic is discussed
the executive will mention that
they want to share reference links.
And from our experience if you put off
like sharing the reference links later on.
This will cause a constant source
of delays, irrespective of how
productive or timely the executive is.
So make sure that the all the reference
links are shared on the call itself
in the chat, and then the content
manager can just copy, copy the
links from the chat and add them to
the ClickUp task on the call itself.
So it's, it's best not to
put this off for later.
And that is a tip from my experience.
So that sums up the video on
how to create, how to schedule
weekly content ideation calls and
how to assign tasks efficiently.
If you have any questions at all, please
feel free to drop them in the community
or ask us to them on the coaching calls.
But the content ideation calls are the
foundation of creation, creating really
good content, because it's only if the
executive who has the thought leadership
and expertise in a, in that specific.
industry and topic.
They need to be able to
share really good content.
So you need to be approaching
them for getting really good
content ideas from them.
And at the same time you need
to be actively participating in
these content ideation calls to
get the most out of these calls.
So with that off that's it for this video.
I'll see you in the next video.