So this is the client report example that I
was talking about. And I'll walk you through
this client report and I'll explain each of
the sections. And I'll also explain how you
can find each of these metrics. And you can
find a link to this template below the video,
the link below the video. And you can just use
it to create your own reports. The design of
these reports don't really matter. If you have
an internal tech template that you use for
your internal reports, you can ask your team
and you can use that. But the design doesn't
really matter. What matters is what are metrics
you report about. Now first, we have an intro
slide about, okay, this is the client that we
work with, this is our company and this is
the name of the week, the name of the week,
the date that you created the report for and
the logo and stuff, these are the most important
limits, just make sure those are added, the
rest doesn't really matter, then we have a table
of contents with say the...
most important sections in the report so that
you can quickly skim through the report. Again,
not really important, but it helps us navigate
the report very quickly if it's a very long
report. And over time, it will become quite
long. This slide itself has 38 slides, so over
time, the length will increase. So it's better
to include a table of contents that link to
the different sections in the report. All right.
Now, let's move on to important links or resources.
important resources say for example the content
analysis sheet that you have for your brand,
the LinkedIn profiles of the team members, the
website, the Google Drive folder where you
stored all the files. So including all of these
in here will make it easy for you to quickly
take looks and make templates and updates, make
updates and assign tasks quickly on the reporting
call itself. So this is something that you should
ideally create, just link every single thing
that Make sure that you're linking the profiles.
Make sure that you're linking the content analysis
sheet. Make sure that the content character
is separately linked. Make sure that you're
linking the...
Login sheet where you're tracking all the logins
to different LinkedIn accounts and so on Make
sure that you are linking to the Google Drive
folder and make sure that you're linking to
the outreach templates document and make sure
that you're linking to The login sheet where
the expanding accounts logins are also added
So that's also important and finally make sure
that you're linking to the ClickUp board that
you're using to manage all your content your
ClickUp board for each profile in your team
Next we move on to the metrics and the actual
report. And we start off with followers and
connection metrics. So this is easy to understand.
Like every week we note down the number of followers
that we have. And this can be found on the
LinkedIn profile itself. So on my LinkedIn profile
for example, I can see the number of followers.
So I just know that in the event of a number
of followers and we do this every week. So
the next week I have something I'll just add
a row or remove this rule, move everything
up. And in the new rule, I will add being seven,
the date on which we send tickets and what
the number of followers are. Quite simple. And
the same with the number of connections to
find the number of connections. All you need
to do is go to my network. So click on my network.
you can see the number over here so it's 28618
in my case it will change every week so that
is what we add a number of connections and we
updated everything just like the number of
followers and then we have the number of profile
views that of people visiting the profile.
Now for the profile view slide what you need
to do is you need to go to your profile there
will be a small snippet in here called analytics
and tools and that is all you need to click
on and you should be able to find the profile
views in here you can click on this and this usually
shows you the profile views of the past 90 days.
So what I'd like you to do is click on past 14 days
because that is a more closer metric as to what
happens what is happening right now but that
is the most you can do so just click on past
14 days click on show results and that is it
we get the number of profile viewers and you
can include that in this slide. Moving on next
we have the number of SSI score on the profile
so the SSI can be easily found on this URL
So that's linkedin.com slash sales slash SSI.
So if you just go there you can find whatever
your SSI score is And in my case my SSI score
this week is 69. Okay, that's low not publishing
content actively at the moment And you can even
see the components in here. You can go detail
and you can include the other elements of this
You can add a screenshot of this every week,
but You should at least be reporting the this number
which is 69 So we include them in here and we mention
whatever week it is and the next metric is content.
So we have the content stats in here. Now for the
content stats what we need to include is one
it should have the name of the user profile
so there are multiple people on the team whose
profiles we are creating content on we should
be including that but either way we have both
the user profile of the company page to report
on. For the content stats so it's better to
just mention the name of the user whose profile
we are reporting on and this is a bunch of columns
in it we have six columns. So first one is
the post preview or the title and the link so
we add a name to the whatever the post
post title is, it can be the same name that
you use in ClickUp, but we add a name to the
title and we hyperlink it to the LinkedIn post
and then the date on which it was published.
The number of views at the moment as you create
this report the number of reactions or the
number of likes the number of comments What
content format it is in so you can easily realize
this if, If you go through the content modules
already, but the content format of that piece
of content. This should also be visible inside
the ClickUp Content board you can also add
the direct link to the ClickUp task for this
specific content piece as well and we should
be able to find the tags with the content formats
in there and we can also include the content
title or the actual content title. So these
are the minimum things that you should be including.
You can add additional columns, it's up to you.
But then we do this for all the content pieces
and it looks like two of them perform really
well. So that's a good sign. And next we have
the company page, the content stats for the company
page, we publish two posts on the company page
and we have the exact same columns in here as
well with data publishing, the post review,
the title and the link. We have the views, the
reactions, the comments, the content format
and the content title and in addition to having
this in a tabular format in here so that you
can quickly take a look we'll have screenshots
of each of the content pieces so adding screenshots
to the content pieces will help us quickly look
at review what exactly was this content piece,
like, especially if it's a visual content format.
So we've included screenshots to all of the
content pieces that we published as well. And
then we have genuine comments. So genuine comments,
it's good that you track the genuine comments
that you're receiving in some place, but adding
screenshots to genuine comments will enable
us to quickly understand, okay, what are the
good ones that we need to be looking at? If
there are any leads in here, so just quickly
taking a look at the headline will help us understand
which are the... interesting leads that we need
to follow up with and we can note them down
as tasks when we discuss this on the weekly
reporting card. All right now we have the genuine
comments section so there can be a bunch of
slides with the genuine comments and now we have
the outreach campaign stats. So based on whatever
campaigns you can be running you should be reporting
a bare minimum of the outreach campaigns at least.
So we have the name of the campaign in expandi, what
the campaign type is in Expandi, the start date of
the campaign, the number of prospects in the campaign,
the number of people who have been contacted, accepted
and replied. You can find all these stats in
the expandi campaign screen, so the main
campaign screen with the list of all the campaigns.
You can find these stats easily from there.
And we can do this for multiple LinkedIn profiles.
So I'm going to pull up expanding and I'm going
to show you how to do this. So here is the expandi
campaign screen.
You should only be reporting the active campaign,
so the inactive campaigns you can ignore, but
the active campaign should be reported. And
then the total number of prospects in the campaign,
number of people that have been contacted, number
of people who accepted the connection request
and replied to the connection request or replied
to others. So all of these are columns that
you can include in the reports. And you need
to do this, create different separate slides
for, include all of the campaigns for each profile
that you're running outreach on so that you
can take a look at it. to this we also include
stats from each of the campaigns that are active
so in addition to documenting the data here
in a tabular format. We also need to include
the finer details of the campaign stats. So
let's take a look at how to do this inside
the expandi campaigns. So this is an example
expandi campaigns so that I can explain how
to take the screenshot. So we just go to the
campaign and we open the campaign. So we come
in here and we click on any one of these campaigns.
So I'm gonna take this one as an example. and
I'm going to open it. So let's take a look at
GCWebinar 2 and it'll first load the people
screen by default but click on stats over here
and that'll pull up these screenshots that
we need. So take one screenshot of this. You
can take like one combined screenshot of both
of this but take someone's screenshot of this
and take one screenshot of this and just drop
it as an image in here. I recommend using skitch
to take screenshots. So this is the tool it's
called skitch. It's very easy to do this. You
can just select screenshot, control C to copy,
and just paste it into the slide, and it's very
easy to create it. So we do this for each campaign
that we've reported on in the tables, and we
create a separate slide for each campaign,
and there will be a bunch of campaigns that
we are running, so you can include them in
here. Now, in addition to this, You can include
additional stats to the screen. So you can
select like a weekly stat and you can choose.
It's not an active campaign anymore, but you
can include screenshots or metrics that you
come across over here on like the number of
connections requests, emails, endorsements,
like whatever action that you're using that
campaign. There's over 15 actions that the expandi
gives you. You can use a report on any of these.
It's up to you. But this is the bare minimum
that you should be doing while creating the
reporting. Thanks for watching! Now in addition
to the expandi outreach process, if you're
sending cold emails or if you're emailing people
for webinar promotion and so on, you should
be reporting on that as well. So what we do
is these are all cold emailing campaigns that
we run by a mailshake. You can use any cold
emailing software, but the metrics will more
or less be the same. So we include the campaign
name, the total number of prospects in the
campaign, the total number of prospects the
email was sent to, the number of emails sent
this week, the number of emails engaged this
week. So these are open rates and so on. the
number of prospects who replied and the number
of bounces this week and the name and people
of name and email of people who replied. We
have redacted this so that it stays confidential
but we have all the campaigns that we are running
on different email platforms as well reported
in this manner in here. You can find all these
metrics in most of the outreach tools, most
of the email outreach tools that you may be
using and you can include them in here in
a weekly manner and keep just like expandi,
we take a look at the active campaigns that
are running right now and we report on these
metrics so that we can make decisions on them
on the basis of this data that we see in here.
And finally, we move to the to-do section.
So at the end of every reporting call, ideally
there should be a bunch of to-dos. So based
on what you analyze that you understand from
these metrics, you should be forming your own
opinions on what is working and what is not
working. Say for example, in the content what
we noticed is that carousels and this was on
the topic of a belief, lessons from a book
called Autobiography of a Yogi that performed
really well because of the hook in the post
and if you see take a look at the hook in the
post it was a... When India was in the brink
of independence, one yogi was spending one of
the most important books of the 21st century.
This book seems to have changed both Virat Kohli.
So I guess many of you are not familiar with
Virat Kohli, but he is the most followed cricketer
in the world. But Steve Jobs is, well you know
who Steve Jobs is. So this post performed really
well. So try to gain opinions and try to gain
inferences from why this content piece performed
really well.So whatever is working, try to gain inferences
from it and whatever is not working try to gain
inferences from it and note them down in the
to-do section in the end. This will be a constant
activity for you for all your reporting calls
so you have to take a look at each of these
things and whenever you gain an interesting
insight that you want to experiment further
you can note them down in here. So in this
case what I've done is since it's just like
six weeks since we began
company, we just mentioned carousels and Experiential
Stories performed really well, so this needs
to be a fixture on the content calendar. Hooks
need to be analyzed, so I can mention something
like hooks need to be analyzed and more of these
type of hooks should be used. So this is good
insight for the content manager of the team
who will take a look at this and he will understand
what to do. So in our case it is Akshi and she
is going to be handling this task. So it is
a simple structure, we have a to do's intro
slide and then we have a task and we have a
status. So it is to be done because it has just been
discussed. So that is one to do, and these are other To do's
for the overall process. So one is content pieces need
to be approved and calendar accounts need to
be integrated. So that is to be shared by the
client's team. So we've just documented all
the lessons here. This is a very small to-do
because we took care of most of it but over
time ideally your to-dos should be large like
almost every single integrity task that you
want to work on. You should be documenting them
in here so that after the call you can move
them to your task management platform, assign them as
tasks to different team members like whoever team members
are and then assign it to them so that they
can get started with those tasks and in the
next week's report what you should ideally be
doing is make a copy of this report and then
update each of these slides with a new metrics
so that's a very easy way to go about this
so that the data is in here and again just add
another row for week seven the date and how
much it increased or decreased so that's a good
way to create the next week's report as well
but this is the weekly reporting structure that I
would recommend for you
This, please note that this is
a basic template, so this is not like
very in depth, this is the bare minimum that
you should be doing, but over time if you need
more insights on a specific matrix, say like
you want a link to a sheet where the genuine
comments have been tracked, you can include that as
a separate section in the reporting, in the report.
So you can make these notes in here, so that after the
reporting call, whatever changes you need in this process
or any process in your LinkedIn marketing process
can be documented properly and executed. One
of the things I learned over the years working
on LinkedIn is that you will be able to constantly
come up with process improvements and gain inferences
from the experiments that you run, but unless
you document those inferences and take action
on it, the process will never improve. So just
adding this to-do section at the end of the report has
greatly improved our own process, internally at Growth Club
both for our own brand as well as for our clients.
So this is something that you should be actively
doing. And that's it for the reporting video.
This is how you create a report. I've included
a link to a template in the link below the video.
So you can take a look at that reporting template.
It's in Google Slides. You can make a copy of
it and go ahead and create your own report.
If you use an internal tech template, you can
go ahead and use that and just replicate the
we have used in this report that I showed you
after watching this video and use that for
your weekly reports. See you in the next video.