So how do you structure your content management
process for efficiency? Now improper content
management is the hash one reason for content
failure. It's easy to assume that content marketing
strategy failures or lack of results from content
marketing happens because of improper. internal
processes or because you are not able to create
content on the right topics or because the
team members or the copywriters or the content
managers are not skilled enough but the actual
truth is that improper and inefficient content
management or lack of a process of proper content
management is the number one cause of failure
when you are not generating results from content
marketing. Now let me explain that for a minute.
There are There are three quick topics to discuss
here. So the first one is people and team members.
The second one is consistency. And the third
one are content formats. Now in a scenario where
you're creating your own content and you're
reviewing it yourself, you're editing it yourself,
you're approving it yourself and you're publishing
it, promoting it yourself, you don't really
need a very robust content management process.
So if you're handling the process end to end,
you can simply track it in a Google Sheet,
that's more than enough. But... If you have
a cotton strategy that you're trying to scale
up where you're creating cotton consistently
in multiple cotton formats that require the
input of multiple team members, let's take an
example. So assume you're creating a video
where somebody is scripting the video for you
and you're recording the video and you're sending
it to a video editor who edits the video, which
is then reviewed by a cotton manager for revision
suggestions.
post copy corrections and so on and then sent
to you for approval and you finally take a
look at it and you approve it, give the final
approval for the publishing and then a team
member goes and publishes it on your LinkedIn
page and promotes the content and replies to
the comments and drag the leads coming in. Now
a process like these requires the input of
multiple team members and it is very difficult
handle this in a simple Google Sheet. What
you need to solve this is a content management
system that has the ability to track statuses
of multiple content pieces, the ability to handle
different process workflows. Say for example,
the process workflow for an experiential story
video is different from the process workflow
for a Q&A video. We will get into these formats
later on so that you understand better but
different kinds of content formats have different
process workflows. The content workflow for
a text post is very different from the content
workflow for a video, any video. The content
workflow for a text post is very different from
that of a carousel that involves the inputs
of a designer who designs the carousel on the
slide post. Now are these the only challenges?
No. We need to be able to categorize each of
the content pieces into different buckets based
on content formats, like experience stories,
or slide posts, Q&A videos, and social media
and so on. we need to be able to search and
filter for different content pieces as needed.
So over time as you build your content database
and you've published a couple dozens of content
and you want to search a particular post, you
need to have a sheet or a content management
system or a dashboard that is able to, where
you're able to quickly find the content piece
that you're looking for. And in the creation
of each content piece, there are subtasks,
say for example, the entire content creation
process is not handled by one person. So there
are sub-cores in it. The post copy is created
by a copywriter, the video script is also created
by a copywriter, but the reviewing is done by
a content manager. The video is being edited
by a video editor, and the carousels are being
designed, or the thumbnail images for the videos
are being designed by a graphic designer. So
each of these are subtasks within the creation
of a post. And because different people may
be handling this process in a team, we need
the ability to assign these subtasks to different
members on the team. And then if you're working
with freelancers or contingency members or consultants,
you also need the ability to track the amount
of work that they're putting in, say track the
number of hours or track the number of videos
or track the number of copies that they're writing.
maybe even track the time that they're putting
in for, so that they can bill you at an hourly
rate. Now what you see here is ClickUp. ClickUp
is a task management platform. It is one of
the most customizable and robust task management
platforms in the world today. And the interesting
thing about ClickUp is that they bring everything
into one platform. So they market themselves
or position themselves as one app to roll them
all. So everything from task management to chats
to gun charts and goal setting dashboards to
documents and dashboards and whiteboards, everything
is brought into one single platform. And in
our case, every single requirement that we have
of a robust content management platform. is
met by ClickUp. So now I am going to jump in
into the Imagine Growth Content Board which
is built on ClickUp and walk you through how
it works and how the ClickUp platform works
as a whole. So this is the Imagine Growth Content
Platform and it looks a bit confusing but This
these are the template cards for each of the
content formats. I'll explain what they are.
But these are the template cards for each of
the content formats that we coach you on in
the program. Now in the template code you can
see tasks statuses. Now what do we mean by
task statuses? Task statuses are the different
stages in which a content piece moves through
the content management process. So task analysis
begins with outlines, which is where the content
manager takes an idea that is either suggested
by the copywriter or discussed on the weekly
content edition calls with the executive and
the content team and creates an outline for
that piece of content and adds it in a template
card. Now after the outline stage, the copywriter
works on it in the draft stage, which is why
we mark it as CW and creates a draft for that
content piece. Now the drafts, the type of drafts
we differ, if it's an experiential video, it
is just the post copy as well as the script
for the experiential video. If it's an informative
course, it is just the post copy. If it is a
carousel, then it's the post copy as well as
the... slide deck content with which the designer
is supposed to design it. And then after the
draft stage, after the copywriter is done creating
the drafts, for that content format it moves
to the content manager approval or revision
stage, which is where the content manager reviews
the content created, the draft created by the
copywriter, either suggests changes and moves
it back to the drafts queue or he approves it
and moves it to sensitive approval. But in
some cases there may be the creation of a media
file. Now these media files may be videos,
they may be carousels, they may be images and
so on which is why we have an awaiting media
file step over here and it's in this stage that
the graphic designer the video editor will
edit the videos or design the text or images
and send it for approval to the content manager
again. Now after all this is done then it goes
to the executives approval queue and the executive
reviews it and if it's good to go he can go
ahead and either directly move into the publishing
queue but if there's a video to be recorded
by the executor say an exponential video or
a Q&A video there is a recording step as well
inbuilt into this and the publishing queue
is in two stages so it can either be published
on the user profile or it can be published
on the company page we also have an option and
that takes up in here so that we can track
the analytics for the published content pieces
right within ClickUp itself. Next, let's take
a look at how template cards work. So each of
these are template cards for different content
formats. And What I'm going to do now is I'm
going to make a copy of this template card.
Say assume you're creating an exponential video.
This is what the process will look like. The
content manager or the copywriters will first
come in here and they will click on this icon
over here. They'll click on duplicate and rename
it according to the topic of the post, the
exponential video that they want to create.
So for the sake of this example, let's say
the topic I choose the video to be on is how
I was the lowest paid member on my team. So
I type that out over here.
as the title and I uncheck attachments and comments
and comment attachments, remove the assignees
and the watches and all I need to do is click
on duplicate task and a new task will be created.
In here it could take like a few seconds but
after it is created I will click on the open
link after this pop-up comes up. and it will
open up the newly created card. Now this is
what the template card structure looks like.
So we have a bunch of guidelines about how
the task is supposed to be used. I'll shortly
read through them. Always work directly the
parent task. Do not add descriptions or comments
inside some tasks. So this is what you see.
What you see on the screen here is the parent
task and In the parent task we may have subtasks,
for example we have 10 subtasks in this parent
task for experiential videos, so it's a video
content format and these are the subtasks. You
are not supposed to update anything in the
subtasks, it has also been specified here. Everything
is to be updated in the main parent task. So
all the descriptions, post copies, updates,
everything is to be updated from the parent
task itself. Just to be clear. The second guideline
is that you always need to read through checklists
for each sub-task or status and after you're
done with all the checklists for your sub-task
update the status. Now the interesting thing
about the ClickUp templates is that for each
stage, say for example, this is a task for the
content manager. So for each of these sub-tasks,
we have a dedicated checklist section that details
each and every minute step that is to be taken
by the content manager for the sub-task. So
whenever you have a... sub-tasks that is assigned
to you all you need is look at the checklist
for that specific section see each of these
sub-tasks will have their own dedicated checklist
sections that you can look through to understand
the different steps for completing that sub-task
so it's basically like a short standard operating
procedure for each content format so that you
don't have to think through about what to do
for each content format everything is goes according
to process and you need to coordinate much
with each team member for each content format
you just need to follow the process that is
being outlined in this template card. Now in
addition to these, each of these subtasks can
be assigned to different team members. Say for
example if the outlines, creating the outlines
for a piece of cotton is being done by the cotton
manager, then it can be assigned to that cotton
manager on the team. If the drafts is being
created by a copywriter on your team, you can
assign that to a copywriter on the team and
select them in here. If the executive who reviews
the cotton and gives the approvals, So if you
do the content, you can select them and assign
that specific sub-task to that theme. In addition
to these, we also have
relationships built into each of these subtasks
so that this task will not become due until
this task is completed. So considering that
graphs can only be created after outlines have
been created there is a relationship set between
these tasks so that this task will not become
due until this task is completed. So all of
the subtasks have relationships, all of them
have mapped due dates
could take if it's being handled by a team member
who's experienced with the process. We have
tag for the individual sub-tasks as well as
tags for the main content formats so that later
on you can filter them and search them easily
inside the job. And in the description section
of the task, so this is the description, editable
description section of the task, you have a
rich text editor that you can use to add rich
text, and at the same time, separate sections
for outlines, for the video script, for the
post copy, as well as first comment. thumbnail
image captions if a thumbnail image is supposed
to be created for that experiential video the
mail drive folder link where all the videos
will be uploaded for that content process the
recordings folder link where This videos recording
folder will be uploaded finished video you
ordered so that the Team members can easily
access the video after it's done, review it
and publish it on LinkedIn, a subtitles file
line, the thumbnail image for the video, and
the LinkedIn post URL after it is published.
And you don't need to worry about how to fill
each of these. Again, for each of these steps
from the ideation of the process, so right
when the content manager creates an outline,
to publishing and promoting it on the user
profile and the company page, every single step
of the process outlined in the checklist section
corresponding to each of the sub-tasks. So for
the outline of an experience story video we
have a list of steps in the checklist that the
content manager needs to do. If it's a different
content format, then the checklist has been
personalized for that content format. So it's
different. Each template card is different,
follows different process workflows specific
to that particular content format.
The reason we do this is because one of the
biggest reasons for inefficiencies in a content
management process is the amount of coordination
and communication that is required. I've been
running an agency for about four years now.
And what I've learned is that even if you're
publishing content consistently, and a lot of
the communication and coordination from your
team is manual one-on-one. You can still make
content marketing work for you, but you will
be wasting a lot of your time. In fact, up to
40% of your team's time involved in creating
and publishing and promoting a piece of content
will go just into coordination and communication
and making sure everybody's on the same page.
a structured content management process that
lists exactly what to do, assigns it to the
team members who are supposed to do it, who
are responsible for it, and explains what is
to be done to each of them in a single place
so that everyone is on the same page is the
best way to manage a content management process.
And that is what the ClickUp content management
code does. Now I won't go into detail about
like how the each of these content stages will
go in how the content piece will go through
each of these stages. You've gotten a brief
overview but I will be explaining these in the
dedicated videos for each of the content formats
later on in the module. Now let's take a look
at how to. create or make a copy of this content
board for your own usage and then personalize
it for your own usage. So below this video
you will find a link to this template content
board. I'd like you to check that and open
that link in your browser. So ClickUp will first
ask you to sign up. So I'm going to enter my
name in here and the email address and password.
They're going to ask you to enter a complex
password so let me just go ahead and enter the
password and click on the table. So I just
did that and I'm clicking on play with ClickUp
and now a form should load asking us to enter
a confirmation code that was sent to the email
address. I'm just going to copy that and paste
it in there and we are done and now ClickUp
should take us in and here there'll be another
form where they'll ask us a bunch of details
about the workspace so you can name this as
whatever your company name is.
the content.
and just click on avatar you can drop like your
logo or something that sort of here I'm just
gonna skip it so far and then color theme but
I love red so I'm just gonna go with that how
many people will you be working with this is
not really important So you can just mention
this I don't know. How do you want to start
using click up? So you can say something like
marketing your context. How did you hear about
us? We can say other This is not really important.
You can say anything you want Just click on
something or just said to imagine true because
we he prefer I refer a lot of people to click
up because I think It's been cast soon. You
don't need to invite people at this stage I
will show you how to do this later on so click
on I am done You can integrate click up to slack
and a bunch of other apps point you can do
it later on, click on no thanks. Any of these
tools for project management that's up to you,
I'm just going to go ahead and no thanks and
click on play with ClickUp. And that's it and
ClickUp is going to load and set up a workspace
for us. So I'm going to, you can watch the
video if you'd like, I'm going to skip it for
now. I suggest you walk in so that you get
familiar with the tool and you understand how
to use it. And then... I just opened the link
which you can find in the description below
which is the link to the template board. So
just open that link in the same browser window
and they will ask you to create your own list,
copy that list and use that template. So you
can name it as you like, it's up to you. Select
a space or folder, it's up to you, you can select
a space but it's not really needed. and you
can click on also save a list copy of this template
to my workspace and share it with all members
click on use template and that should be more
than enough i think i need to select this piece
over here so i just select this piece and then
click on use template okay we need a unique
name as well so let's just see i'm just gonna
call it IGCon For now, you can personalize
it as you like and click on use template. And
now, clitorp will copy the template list and
template board and the view and all. template
cards with all the sub tests, tasks, checklists,
all the tags, everything is going to be copied
into your list. So what you see here is a view.
So that's the way we view the tasks. So what
you see here is a list view. But what we are
interested in is a board view. So the board
view is what we saw earlier, where it looks
like this. And of these cards represent a template
card for each post and you need to duplicate
this whenever you want to create a new experiential
video or if you want to create say a Q&A video
or a slide post you can click on here you can
click on duplicate rename it okay again you
need to uncheck attachments and comments and
comment attachments and then you don't need
either and then you can click on duplicate task
and a new task will be created there will be
a small pop-up in this corner if you want to
create it and that is what you can open and
edit let me just show it to you quickly so that
you understand again you take a template card
so if you want to create a new slide post you
take a template card you click on duplicate
and you theme it as you like so in my case it's
how do i um first be released
So, gonna create a carousel on that. So you
uncheck attachments. Every single time you
do it, you uncheck attachments. Comments and
comment attachments, as well as assignees and
copywatches. We don't need these. So, I mean,
it's okay if you've selected them. It doesn't
matter much. But if there's any attachments
that you've made by mistake in the template
cards, if you've edited the template cards,
you should never do. the attachments won't
get copied, so the task will stay clean. But
once you're done with that, you can just click
on duplicate task, and you should wait for a
while ClickerPace is copying the task right
now. So this will finish loading in a while,
takes about 10 seconds, it's done, and it will
open it up directly, or you can click on this
open, and it will open it up, and then you
can start working on the task where the content
manager goes through each step in his... list
so it takes a look at the subtask and then the
first thing is create a copy of the template
task and change parent task status to outlines
so he comes in here and he selects the parent
task to outlines but i'm not going to discuss
more about the individual steps for the content
management process for each content format because
we have separate videos later on in the module
for that all right so this is how you create
your own click up template code and start using
it and now Let's talk a bit about how to filter
for specific content formats as needed. So,
filtering is good because it allows you to easily
identify content formats. So you can search
and filter. There's options for both filtering
and searching in here. So if you want to quickly
find the content format for informative posts,
we just need to search that and it will bring
it up here. See if you want slide posts, just
type out the first few words and it will come
up here. Q&A videos it will come up here in
this manner. So it's pretty easy to search
and you can do this for even for like say content
pieces that have been created in the board.
So if you have a lot of content formats already
for different for content that you've already
created you can come in here and just search
for whatever the topic of that post was and
it should bring it up for you. In my case for
example I've already created a post on how
was the least paid member. So all I need to
do, and there's not a lot of tasks on this
board. So it is not very important, but if you
want to do it, I could just create it like
this and I would be able to get the template
more easily. So that is how you search for
tasks. And now let's take a look at the filtering.
So in here, there is an option to... filter
for tasks you can be able to see it find it
here or if you're using the website you'll
be the ux is a bit different the filtering option
is in here and you can use it i recommend using
the desktop app because it's faster and ease
of access of any platform is very important
if you want to actively take action. So the
more easier ClickUp is to access and let's
say create, edit, suggest, edit, so review content,
the more you'll end up using it and the more
results you'll be able to generate with the
content management process. So our filtering
is a bit different, but it works the same way
on. for the actual filtering process, you click
on this and you get filtered by every single
data field inside the ClickUp task, starting
from the due dates to the priorities to who
it's assigned to, to when it's created, what
the due dates are, if there's any dependencies,
what the location is. So it's one of the most
customizable task management platforms in the
world today. This is why I said that. And if
you want to quickly filter for a specific task
that is in a specific status or that specific
tag. You can do it over here step by step. So
it's pretty easy to understand if task status
is or is not, and you can select like all the
task status options. If assignee is, you can
select like any particular assignee of the team.
So you can filter for like whatever we want.
But typically, almost all data fields that are
available in the task, you can filter using
them all.
Now the next step after this is to of course
add more team members to the template board
so that more team members can come in.
you can start assigning tasks and launch the
content process. So for that, all you need
to do is go over here, click on this three dots
icon over here, that is the list settings.
So whatever you've named your content board
as, just click go to over here at the top and
click on list settings. And then at the bottom,
you can find sharing and permissions. If you
click on sharing and permissions, you will be
able to invite people by name. So I've already
added a lot of, added a lot of team. of people
on my team but in addition to that you can
add your team members you can if you already
bulk added them and you can you want to share
access to them to the specific list you can
just type their name but if they're not signed
up to clicker yet you just need to their email
address in this manner and send them an email
and an email should get sent to them and after
they click on invite they join they should
be able to access kick up. So
At the moment, click-up usage is completely
free, so this entire template board can be
used for free. You can take a paint plan if
you want to customize it and if you want to
use it for more task management and so on, but
at the moment, you can add sufficient team
members for the entire content management process
completely for free. Now one of the things
I want to assure you of is that you do not need
to follow. the exact structure. While the structure
or the process flow that we teach in the program
is based on actual work that we've done as
an agency over the past four years, you don't
really need to follow the exact process. Now
we've seen this process to work really well,
so you can follow this exact same process.
But if you have a better process that you think
will work better for your team structure or
for your own use case, say suppose you're not
using a different content manager or a different
copywriter. What you can do is you can combine
both these checklists into one. So you can
edit each, all of these elements on the clickup
task. You can edit everything from the tags
to the statuses. You can customize the statuses
of the content board by clicking on the status
column. So you click on this. Sorry, I can't
talk about this. click on this button of the
status and we click on add or edit statuses
and you can update the statuses in here. So
statuses are categorized as not started statuses
or templates as a not started status which
means we're not using the task or the task is
not activated it's not been assigned it. Active
statuses is when we begin the work on that task
and finally done statuses is when we post it
to be some content or the sub tasks are complete
and so on. So That is it with statuses. The
statuses can be edited. The descriptions and
the titles can be edited. The different sections
and the descriptions can be edited. The subtasks
can be edited. So you can edit each of these
subtasks, rename them. You can add different
time estimates for them. You can edit the...
different tags added for the sub-tasks. You
can change the due dates. So all of these things
can be done within the sub-tasks itself. Or
you can even change the relationships of each
of these sub-tasks and edit the names of the
sub-tasks, change the order, delete sub-tasks.
We can edit or delete, sub-type this checklist
as well so that you can personalize it if you
need, if you'd like, for your own process workflow.
We would recommend that you stick to this process
workflow if you work with multiple team members.
Say you have a copywriter and a content manager
or a graphic designer or a video editor. So
there are multiple members of the team and
you're not handling the entire content management
process yourself. this workflow should work
more than fine. Even if you're handling multiple
responsibilities, say there is a content that
the same person is handling both the content
management and the copywriting process, you
can assign both the sub-tasks to the same person.
It's completely fine. The only scenario where
this entire click-up process is not needed is
if you're handling the entire process on your
own. Say you're handling the entire ideation
creation process on your own and you're only
having an executive assistant or a virtual assistant
on your team publishing the content. So in
such a scenario, a content management board
like this is not needed. You can simply create
a Google Sheet and add it there. But if you
have like more team members involved in the
content creation process itself or the content
approval process itself or the ideation process
itself.
This is the best structure that you can flow,
that you can follow for a content management
process that is well optimized and efficient.
So there are two types of views in the template
board. So one is the board view where you can
see all the content, the entire content management
process, all the cards in all the formats, and
the different content management stages they
are in, like outlines or graphs or content management.
approval or awaiting media file on EDX approval
and so on. And in addition to that, we have
a list for the subtasks. Now while the board
is for an overall view of all the content pieces,
the list is for the subtasks that the individual
team members have to work on.
graphic designing of the video editing tasks
or the approval tasking or the task sub-tasks
for posting on the company page or the user
profile and so on. So all the sub-tasks have
been listed in the list sub-tasks view and the
main board with all the content pieces, if
you'd like to take a look at how many we have
in the approved stage, how many are ready for
approval, how many are being edited on. how
many adjusted drafts and the copywriters are
working on them and how many are just in outlines
waiting for the content manager to add an outline.
So the board is for an overall view of the entire
content management process and the list or
the subtasks are for the individual subtasks
that the that the team needs to work on. So
all you need to do is handle the board while
you're working on the the content addition
call. So the content managers will come in here,
the copywriters will come in here, and they
can make a copy of the individual template cards.
They can duplicate the individual template
cards, rename them, and start working on the
tasks, the sub-tasks, interview, adding outlines,
creating graphs, and so on. They can go about
their work. But if you'd like to take, if any
of the team members in the content marketing
team needs to take a look at the tasks that
they need to work on every day for the content
management process, they can just come to list
and in here you can see all the assigned tasks
that are yet as still in assigned stage that
the team members need to work on. So if they'd
like to come in here and if you want to see
only the tasks that are assigned to you in your
queue in ClickUp, just click on this mean button
and it will filter out all the sub tasks that
are assigned to other team members. So for
example, these are all the tasks that are assigned
to me. So I do a lot of different kinds of
work, which is why you see different kinds of
tasks in here. Say for example, posting, client
review, writing outlines or video editing. But
if a video editor comes in here, they will
only see video editing tasks. If a copywriter
or content manager comes in here, they will
only see the content tasks or the copywriting
tasks or the content review tasks. If you're
the executive, when you come in here, you will
only see the client tasks or the review tasks
that you need to focus on. So It is segregated
easily so that you can quickly work, you can
quickly take a look at the tasks, the sub tasks
that you need to work on. So the copy, if you're
a copywriter, you'll only see the posts that
you have to create, the copies that you have
to generate. If you're a video editor, you'll
only see the links to the actual videos that
you need to edit and so on. Now one thing to
note over here which is very, very important
and I want you to internalize this a gift in
your mind is do not work on the sub task. If
you come in here and we click on this it will
open the sub task. But in here we've dropped
something in here. Do not update anything in
the sub task. Always work on parent task. So
if you go up you'll see the button to the main
parent task in here. But even in the list in
the sub task list that you see over here you
have an option to click go directly to the
parent task. So always whenever you come in
here. irrespective of what role you're working
in, just don't work on the subtasks in here.
Click on this main parent task link instead,
which will open up a parent task. You can see
the subtasks that are assigned to you in here
and you can start working on them as opposed
to working on the individual subtasks. So we
do not work on subtasks in this because all
the details of all the post copies, all the
work, the links, everything is added inside
the parent task. So please keep that in mind.
When you come in here, do not click on this
link, click on this main link of the parent
task. So this link. All right. Now, while the
subtasks are for an overview of the task that
you need to work on, and you can filter for
your own task by clicking on this me button
over here. The board view is an overall view
for the content-addition calls. So when you're
working on the content-addition calls, and you
want to note down a bunch of ideas from the
ideas discussed by the executive or by other
team members on the content-edition calls or
after the content-edition calls, you can come
in here, you can make a copy of this template
card and include the outline or the ideas in
there. Even if you are a copywriter and you
want to suggest a few ideas that are to be discussed
on the content-edition calls before the content-edition
call, you can come in here and make a copy of
the template card. and add them in here. Now
that sums up how you can use the different views
in ClickUp, both for content, the overall content
management, as well as the individual sub-tasks
that you should be working on every day. So
this is the main list that you should be working
on every day to see the tasks that are assigned
to you, the individual sub-tasks that are assigned
to you, so that you can continue with the work
and progress each content piece to the next
content next stage in the content marketing
process. And the content board is only for creating
templates and getting an overall view of where
we are in the content management process for
each content piece. So you can quickly get
an overview of like each content piece in here.
There will be different stages in the content
management process and that can be seen on the
board. So you have two modes. You have two
views. One is board and the other is a list
called subtasks. where you can see the subtasks
that are assigned to you. Next, let's go over
a few rules that you have to follow when you're
working in ClickUp and using the template boards.
So the first rule is that the correct views
that you need. So these views have settings.
So all of them have been configured in the
template board already for you. So all you need
to do is just take a look at the board view
and the list view. And all the filters are set.
in here so we only have one filter and the
one filter in the list subtasks list view is
that you can only see the assigned subtask
so this status has been selected and that is
the only type of type of task that you can
see in here so you can see only the subtask
with the assigned status in this board and
in addition to that we've also set a setting
for the subtasks so that subtasks are all shown
as separate tasks as part of like the original
parent task. So these settings have already
been configured for you. You don't need to make
any changes. But whenever you make an additional
filter, say for example, I'm adding an additional
filter for QDate, all right? So I want to see
the task that I do today. ClickUp will ask you
to save it. You see this prompt called, you
change the layout, save or reload. And this
view has unsaved changes. Do not save on this.
So if you add any additional filters and you
want to go back to the original thing, you
just need to reload your view. reload clickup
so if I reload clickup like this I just reloaded
it by entering command R or control R and it
will automatically revert to the old view so
that nothing is changed do not save the additional
views that you want because it could mess up
the filtering and the settings and that we've
already saved in the clickup view for you okay
so this is the best view you can personalize
this view for your own use case but until you've
tested it out properly and you're made should
you sure that this is the view that you need
do not update the view because the view will
be updated for all the team members who are
using this specific list. So the views that
you want are already configured. If you make
any additional filtering say for example if
I entered filtering in this board as well,
ClickUp will ask me if I want to save this.
Then go ahead and save it. If you change the
view it will get updated for
If you want filtering, you can just use it as
you like. You can filter and use it as you
like, but do not save it. When you save it,
it will get updated for all the team members.
All right. So that was the first rule. The second
rule is that subtasks and parent tasks have
different types of statuses. So let me explain
that for a moment. So subtasks, for example,
will have two task statuses. So the first task
status for subtasks will be assigned and this
other task status for subtasks will be completed.
So there is only two task statuses for subtasks,
assigned and completed. So if something is assigned
to you, you just need to work on it and market
is complete. That is it, very simple. But parent
tasks will have different statuses. So a content
piece on LinkedIn can go from outlines to drafts
to CM approval revisions to a waiting media
file to DDEX approval to a waiting recording.
to need to be ready to be posted to user profile,
ready to be posted to company page. And we have
an extra analytics step if you'd like to track
analytics, but this is not included in your
existing process. But these from outlines to
ready to be posted on company page are the task
statuses for the parent task. To make sure
that you don't get confused by this, everything
has been mentioned in here. So like whenever
you need to update the status after you're done
with a specific sub task. What status updates
like what you need to change it to and how you
need to change it are all mentioned in here
So that you don't get confused and this is different
for each content format So you have like personalized
step-by-step checklist for each Content format
created for you in the template cards so that
you don't get confused But this is just so that
you understand that this is the structure that
is to be followed Or the process that is to
be followed for parent tasks and sub tasks.
So just recapping The subtasks which are included
in the main parent tasks, so these are all
subtasks, will have only two task statuses.
One will be assigned and the other one is completed.
So at the start when the cotton manager or the
CM creates the cotton piece from the template
card and he'll assign, he or she will assign
all the individual subtasks to all the team
members who were involved in the creation of
that cotton piece. And When the team members
work on them, they'll have it in assigned status
and all they need to do is mark it as complete
after they're done. So sub-tasks will have only
two task statuses. One is assigned when it's
assigned to them and one is completed when they've
completed working on their task. But parent
task statuses, the parent tasks will have multiple
statuses. So it will start from outlines to
graphs to scene approval to awaiting media file
to media approval, awaiting recording based
on like what stage that content is in and finally
in ready to be posted company page which will
be the last status and after the post is published
and all the work has been done for that post
they can mark it as posted. So posted is the
final done or completed status for the main
parent task. Now the reason we specify is this
because when you select the task status is
in here there is an option to like say add this
as outlines or drafts. So do not mark the subtask
statuses as anything other than assigned or
completed. So whenever you work on a content
piece the subtask should only have assigned
or completed statuses. Do not update them as
any of these any of these main parent task statuses.
So make sure you follow this process exactly
to avoid confusions in the team. So that was
the ClickUp Cottonboard. And now let's talk
about some final updates. The templates will
be updated from time to time. So over the course
of your program, as you're taking the IG program,
the templates will be updated by us. We could
add update existing templates or we could be
adding new templates for new cotton formats
that are performing very well on LinkedIn. But
all of these updates will be announced in the
group watching calls. or in the WhatsApp communities.
So make sure that you are paying attention
to any of these announcements that we make in
the WhatsApp community or via email or in the
group coaching calls. We typically announce
these updates everywhere so that you can come
in here and add the new template cards for new
content formats or update the existing template
cards. Now let's take a look at how you can
replace your existing template card. All you
need to do is take a look at the link below
this video. So below this video, there'll always
be a link of the template board. All you need
to do is create a new copy. It's just like
how I created this board from a template board
from the link below the video. Create a new
board and just copy this to the list, the new
list, the new template board that you created.
So let me show you how to do that. So after
you create a copy of the template board, whenever
we announce any updates, just make a new copy
in here. And this is, for example, the template
board with all the content formats, all the
updated content formats is the most updated
version of it. So if the announcement is that
I've added two new content formats, we've added
two new content formats, say, viral text posts
and viral tweets, for example, all you need
to do is duplicate this into your existing content.
So assume this is your existing content board
with all the content formats that you're using
right now with all the additional tasks if
you've already started your content management
process. So there could be additional tasks
in here but the templates are in this column
with the content formats that you're using
right now and we announce two new content formats.
Say assume the two new content formats are
viral tweets and viral text posts and you need
to start using these. All you need to do is
come in here, click on this button of more options,
click on duplicate and copy the content formats
to the content board that you're using right
now. So in our case it's the IG content board
that is the content board that we're using right
now. So I just click on this and I click on
duplicate task and that is it. So this is how
you copy new content formats that we announced.
in the program to your content board. So just
click on more options and click on duplicate
and select the content board that you want to
copy to, just click on duplicate and that's
it. Now, what do you do if you want to update
a template? So if you want to update a template,
so assume we've announced an update for the
experiential videos process, or we've announced
an update for the news text post process. something
like that all you need to do is come to your
content board and find the content piece that
you need to update okay so even if you mess
up like a template and you want to revert to
the original template so you messed up some
checklist and you want to revert to the original
template from the program all you need to do
is come to the content board that you're using
so this is the content board that we are using
and delete that template card so just delete
the
template card and then I come to this template
which is the template that I just copied. Again
you can find the link to the original template
board that we are sharing below the video as
well as in the progress tracking sheet. But
go to that template and then all you need to
do is duplicate this from the template board
to your own content management board. So I
just deleted the template card, the outdated
template card or the wrong template card, the
messed up template card. from my content board
and I just come to the content board template
that I found from the link below the video and
I just copied that to my own content board
and now it will come in here as in the. templates
list as a new template task. So it'll take
some time to duplicate and copy, but once it's
done, it'll come into this list. So this is
how you get updates, get updated template cards
or get new template cards from the content
board that we're sharing with you. So assume
that we will constantly be updating new content
formats. We'll be introducing new content formats.
If there is any change, significant change
in the process that will save a lot of your
time, we will be including, we'll be updating
the existing templates, but all of these updates
of new content formats and updates in existing,
in the existing process or the existing templates
will be announced to you in via email, via
the WhatsApp community, as well as in the group
Keep an eye out for it. Now before we close
off this lesson, what I want to assure you
is that this same content management board can
be used for additional content formats. So
you want to create a content format for a blog
post, all you need to do is look at the most
similar content formats. Say for example for
blog post, I would say that experience story,
the process that we use for experience stories
would be more or less the same one, the content
process for it. when we create an outline for
a blog post, and then a draft is created by
a copywriter or a content writer, and then the
content manager reviews it and approves it.
And then finally, the executive approves it,
and then goes to a ready-to-be-posted queue.
But the ready-to-be-posted queue is not for
LinkedIn, but it's for the website. But if
you create a copy, if you duplicate this, you
can create a new template for content formats
that you want to introduce into the process,
say, blog posts or white papers. or any other
content format that you can think of because
of the ability of the structuring process for
sub-tasks to different team members in the team,
say content managers or copywriters or executives,
or video editors and graphic designers. This
structure that we teach you in the program
can be used for additional content formats that
you want to create yourself. So what we're
teaching you here is, in addition to like offering
these templates for content formats, we train
you and coach you in the program. The structure
and framework can be used for additional content
formats that you want to come up with for your
own business or for your own brand. And these
can be white papers, these can be blog posts,
this can be ad copies, this can be a new video
series or a new interview video series that
you want to introduce. So try to internalize
the framework that we're teaching over here
and try to use it for your own content formats.
Ideally, you should be using the same system
for all of your content, because if everything
is in one place, it'll be far more easier for
you to track. And...
To make your content management process efficient,
you need to have it in a single place with
multiple team members collaborating in a single
board with a list of sub tasks for each stages
of the content management process assigned individually
to each of the team members, and they can see
it in a single view in the lists view in the
content management board. So with that, I'm
signing off from this video. I'll see you in
the next video. If you have any questions at
all about the content management process, ask
them in the group coaching calls and drop them
in the WhatsApp communities so that we can answer
them for you. See you in the next video.