So the first thing you want to do
is create an endorsement and liking
post liking campaign for your first
degree connections in, in in LinkedIn.
And the way we do that is we first
come to sales navigator lead search
and we click on connections and
we select first degree connections
and then click on see all filters.
And if your network size is over 5,
000 connections on LinkedIn you can
filter for the people who've posted
on LinkedIn in the past 30 days.
If your network size is below 5,
000 connections, you don't need to
include this filter so that you have
a sizable number of people in this
list a sizable number of people that
you reach out to, but I am going
to select posted on LinkedIn in the
past 30 days because my network size
is well over 5, 000 connections.
So we connect, select the connections
and the posted on LinkedIn in 30 days.
And the next thing you need
to select is the geography.
So the geography should ideally be
The target locations that you're
focusing on on a country level.
So if you're targeting Canada,
for example, so for trace
cost, we're targeting Canada.
So I'm going to take that as an
example, I will select all of
Canada as the target geography.
And in addition to that, I will also
select the United States because
that is also a target geography.
So we have about 4000 people in this list.
And yeah.
Expatly only allows imports up
to 2, 500 per search, which is
why I will segment this list now
into two separate lists ideally.
So one thing you could do is you
could look at the company headcount
and select like two separate buckets.
So I will go every anywhere
up to say self 2, 500.
Yeah.
So this, these three lists
make up about 2, 500.
And this is the first list I will take.
And the next list I would take
would be the remaining buckets.
So I would remain, remove
all of these still 50 people.
So this is the first list I will import
into expanding, but the next list I will
import into expanding will be this one.
So up from 51 and above.
I will select the remaining people
and I will try to activate them.
So this will be the remaining people,
that's 2, 000 about 2, 000 results.
So I will take both these lists
and I will import them into Expandi
that process is pretty simple.
All you need to do is
first go into Expandi.
So this is my Expandi and then
click on search to load the search
box and then copy the URLs of
both the searches that you want.
So I'll copy the search URL.
I come in here, I click on add
new search and I will choose sales
navigator search, enter the search name.
So this is supposed to be a
network post campaign one.
So this is the first one.
So I'll just click on next.
I'll enter the search URL and I will click
on search and now Expandi will go ahead
and scrape 2, 500 results in that search.
It's loading right now.
And in the meantime, I will go to
campaigns and I will create a new
campaign which is a smart builder campaign
for getting endorsements and liking
for giving endorsements and liking.
Posts of the people in this list.
So let's just wait for
the campaigns to load.
It's still in search.
Let's load that.
Okay.
The campaigns are loading.
And what I'm going to do now is
click on add campaign and click
on campaign builder in here.
So I'm going to give it a campaign name.
So this is a network activation campaign,
click on next, and then click
on create without template.
And after we create the campaign,
it will open up in a while.
And this is what the
campaign will open up to.
So this is the smart builder
campaign where we can add
additional actions for each.
Person in that list.
So what I will do is I will add skill
endorsement as the first step and
then like a post as the next step.
You could add additional steps for
visiting profiles and follow profiles,
but this is already being done by
Expandi for a lot of other accounts.
So you're actively running campaigns, so
you don't want to affect the limits of
those campaigns, which is why these, this
is the bare minimum that you can set up.
And what I will do is I
will connect these in here.
So we need to add a check condition
for whether they're connected or not.
So if connected, we'll mark it in here
and we'll connect this to if connected
and this tick is for if they've connected.
So we connect this to this
and the next step after if
they've connected is this one.
And after you set this up, you can
just click on this save button in here
to save the campaign and that is it.
You've selected, you've saved this flow.
You can also configure the first
step stats so you can check You can
set a time delay, but I wouldn't
recommend setting a time delay.
Maybe you can set like 15
minutes after as a time delay.
But then you also need to like their post.
So for this, I would set as one delay.
So we first send them an endorsement and
then one day later we send them a like.
That is the way I would do it.
And then after that we need to
take a look at the setting screen.
So you click on, okay,
you need to save it.
So.
I set this as 15 minutes again, click
on this and this is selected as one day.
These are steps for like say when the
last engagement is there the minimum
number of likes that the post should have.
So it shouldn't be like a
post with like literally zero.
You could enter this as five.
That is the bare minimum I would go with.
And you could enter keywords for posts.
So only the posts with those
keywords would be engaged with,
but I wouldn't recommend using this
because it's not necessary that
they contain a specific keyword.
Once this is done, you click on save.
And then once Expandi shows the green
button with steps are successfully
saved, you go to settings.
And in the settings, we need to set the
number of new people to be contacted by
the first actions of the campaign daily.
So ideally I'd like at least
30 people contacted per day.
So you can increase this.
But I would, since you have other
campaigns running, I would set it at 30.
If you don't have other campaigns
running, you can set this up to 70.
It's fine.
But if you have campaigns running
parallelly, 30 is the ideal
number that you need to set.
All right.
You can increase this over time.
It's fine.
But at the start When you're
working on this, just start it
off at 30 and then click on apply.
And these settings should be updated.
And now we go to people and in here
we need to import the prospect.
So let's take a look at whether
a search is loaded completely.
So if I go back to search I will
be able to see the search that
I just ran from sales navigator.
So my network booster search is loaded,
so I'll just click on it and I now need
to assign these prospects to a campaign.
So what I will do is I will click on.
Assign filtered contacts.
So we click on assign filtered contacts.
We select a campaign.
So just type the name
of the campaign in here.
So I have the network activation campaign.
So I just click on this, I
click outside and click on add
filtered contacts to campaign.
So sometimes when you add this, a lot
of Expandi will show a notification or a
pop up saying that there are duplicates
in, in the campaign or the duplicates
in the existing campaign and so on.
That is completely fine.
Some of the prospects will,
could be there in other expanding
campaigns that you're running.
So they may they may, they may be
removed automatically, but now if I
go to the campaign and I take that
specific campaigns, if I go to campaigns
right now and search for work, I can
now find that my network activation
campaign is, is ready with two, three.
Thank you.
9 1 1 prospects.
So from about 2, 500, about 100 prospects
were removed because they were running,
they were included in other campaigns.
That's completely fine.
And now we need to
switch on this campaign.
So all you need to do is click
on status and the network
activation campaign is live.
And that's all you need to do to.
Run an endorsement and liking campaigning
using smart builder campaigns and Expandi.
Now that was the first step in
activating your existing campaign,
existing network on LinkedIn.
The second step is commenting
on other posts on LinkedIn.
So commenting is a very
important activity.
It is an art in itself.
And dropping a comment on a LinkedIn
post is a very good way to prime
your network, even generate positive.
Results by optimizing
it for the algorithm.
So if you do it immediately before
publishing a post, that is the
best time to do it because the
algorithm will prime, will be primed
for your post to be published.
And just because you've dropped a comment
on several other posts in the feed or in
the sales navigator feed or on influencer
posts your post will generate more
result, more reach as a result immediately
So the first thing I'll show you
how to do is finding posts from the
LinkedIn feed and commenting on them.
The target for these is 10 per day.
So ideally the ideal time for doing
this is right before you publish.
So you should be starting this process,
say like half an hour before you
publish the post or whatever time
you publish the post on that day.
And the way you go about doing this
is you go to the LinkedIn feed.
So this is my LinkedIn feed of the case
study client that I want to show you.
So we'll go through this feed and
we'll take a look at relevant posts
that have somewhat good engagement.
So I'm going through this, I'll
see like some stuff about wire and
cable industry, not very relevant.
Plus they don't have
like a lot of engagement.
This one is about Shakuntala Devi
who is a human is a mathematical
genius solving problems.
Let's move on.
This one is about polarization,
equity, diversity and inclusion.
Yeah, it's an okay topic.
You can comment on it, but
it's not really relevant.
So I'm not going to do it.
Let's take a look at space planning
data stories, hmm, data is one of our
clients for this client for pre order.
Okay, this is an okay post, it has
good engagement as well, but no, this
is not something I would look at.
I'm going to keep doing this until I
find good posts that I can talk about.
Sifarish,
this one is about some
LinkedIn posting stuff.
I know that this is a construction
company and this is the founder
of that construction company.
And this is somewhat okay engagement,
120 likes and five comments.
This is a post I would comment on.
So there's two ways you
can go about doing this.
One is manually taking a look at
this and dropping your comment.
And.
This is how I would comment on this post
and almost all posts in the same format.
So, what I would first
do is tag the author.
Tagging the author is important.
We need to grab their
attention with this comment.
So what I would do is say something
along the lines of let me read the post.
It feels great when you appreciate
the work of what you've built to
help you during this new journey.
Teams, I must thank everyone
who has worked with Kalpataru.
So much of a framework known
as Javi, but without my cross,
Donna, Paulson, and team.
Okay.
Can't.
So I'm going to say can't beat the
suits analogy because I know that
this is from a series called suits.
So I'm going to say can't
beat the suits analogy.
Maybe I would say something like,
and Jessica wouldn't be Jessica
without having Jessica without having
so medical stop over there and say, can't
be in the seats analogy produce to watch.
You accomplished.
I know you will tag him again.
You can tag him multiple times.
That's fine.
And then ideally we need to end the
comment with a question so that they
feel prompted to respond and they
under, let's say, getting replies to
our comments is a good thing again.
So ideally I would end
it off with a question.
So Sometimes life in success
feels overwhelming if you
rise back from the dead.
I appreciate you rewarded for
what you have built, but with
the good it's also overwhelming.
And while this is a new journey
new team is being built.
I must thank everyone who is being worked.
Okay, let's talk about
Okay, it's a new journey.
He mentioned it's a new journey.
So maybe you could ask
about the new journey.
Let me take a look at his
profile so that I am in context.
So he's a founder of Urbanwork.
Oh, I see.
He founded a new company.
So Kalpataru.
Okay, I could ask him about Urbanwork,
like the company that he's working on.
Ideas
how are things progressing
at, I would say, Urbanwork.
But I would also, I
could also tag Urbanwork
and I would post it.
This is it.
So, I will talk about the the second
approach to commenting on this.
You could use ChatGPT to create an
automated comment for this and quickly
so that you can speed up the commenting.
But the manual approach is the best way to
do it so that you can add good comments.
But this is how you find posts in the
LinkedIn feed that have somewhat good
engagement and is a relevant post.
So ideally you need to be
finding relevant posts, even if
you have to scroll for a while.
Digital platforms and construction.
See this one, this is a relevant post.
So I would drop a comment on this, tag
this guy, drop a relevant comment, end
it off with a question and post it.
Now let's talk about the second type of
posts that you should be commenting on.
And those are Posts from
your sales navigator feed.
The next step is to go to sales navigator.
So go to sales navigator and go to
home and this is the feed for different
types of alerts for leads that you've
saved as saved searches on linkedin So
you need to be saving them or creating
lead lists or of of people that you
are reaching out to On linkedin.
So this these are people
that fit your icps.
So we're not just commenting on posts
on the LinkedIn feed of other creators.
We are also commenting on posts of our
ideal customer personas of the people
that we are targeting on LinkedIn.
And after you save them in a search,
after you save the search or save
them to a need list on, on LinkedIn.
Their feed will come in here.
So these are all the updates about all
their posts and they can be found in
the same sales navigator home screen.
If you haven't already saved a
lead list what you need to do is
you need to create a lead list.
I need to save prospects in leads.
This has been covered in the outreach
modules, but when you've done
that it'll start populating with
updates about accounts and leads.
What you should be doing is you should
click on leads to see updates from leads.
But what I want to show you is how easy
it is to Comment on posts from here.
So you can receive updates
from different leads over here.
So if you find like a relevant lead
update from a relevant lead who's
in the in the niche that you're
targeting So in our case, it's it's
it services and it consulting or
business consulting and services or
Construction like the case study that
that we showed we walked into earlier.
So clicked on view the view link and
Load the post directly in the sidebar
and you also have the option to comment
over here So this is how it go about
I let again tag the person who posted
so it can be a company or a lead But
what I would recommend is only focusing
on lead conversations So it's people
people should be seeing the updates
people you should be posting on people's
comments people's posts but you click
on you tag the person who posted,
in our case it's a company page, so
I'm just going to proceed with it.
I'm looking forward to learn more about
Scandinavian scene, so you could say
something along the lines of, you should
be attending I'm not a gift to 833, but
I'm just giving this to you as an example.
Looking forward to meeting there.
Been waiting.
Okay.
So I would also have something
like, what's the best way to
reach out to you or something like
when will you be in Scandinavia?
What date will you be in Scandinavia?
Something to build the conversation.
So that you receive a response and
they notice you on LinkedIn, you
receive replies to the comments.
So this is how you go about commenting
on the feed in the sales navigator
of lead updates of people who've,
that you've saved in your lead
lists in sales navigator the posts.
That they publish will come in
here as a feed and all you need
to do is, is click on view and
comment, drop a comment on them.
Now let's move on to the last
step, the last type of comments
that you should be dropping.
And those are comments
on influencer posts.
So the first step for this
is to find influencers.
Now ideally when you publish posts
on influencers, it should be at the
immediately after they've published.
So influencers tend to generate a lot of
comments on their posts so your comment
can generate a lot of brand awareness
as well, a lot of responses as well.
So it's important that you post
as early as possible as soon
as the influencers publish.
But the first step in this process is
to find the influencers and document
them so that you understand exactly
which profiles posts to comment on.
So how do you go about
finding influencers?
So all you need to do is use Taplio again.
Taplio was covered earlier in at the
start of the content marketing modules.
But Taplio is a tool that you can use
to search for good content pieces that
find, that have gone viral on LinkedIn.
So we set up Taplio.
Take a look at that video if
you'd like to take a look at it.
We do cover, we do have a video
about how to use a combination of
Taplio, ChatGPT, and LinkBoost to
create a lot of content very quickly.
Take a look at that.
We cover Taplio in detail over there,
but we go back to search mode in Taplio.
And once we are in Taplio we just
search for the specific keyword
that is related to our industry.
In our case, it's construction.
And then what we do is
we click on this filter.
button over here and we select the
minimum number of likes as 500.
The reason we do this, we want to
find influencers who are generating
a lot of engagement on their
content with good followings.
So set it as at least 500 and publishes
at least 60 days ago publish at most 500
two days ago and that should be enough.
Click on apply and now Taplio will find
posts that have performed really well
that are in on this topic, construction.
So let's take a look at the profiles
of the people who have published.
So if you scroll, if you like hover
over the the profile image over
here, it will show you like what
that person says and this is the
link to their LinkedIn profile.
So if you click over here, it
will go to their LinkedIn profile.
And it'll also give you a summary of like.
What that person does so in this case
tyler campbell is a generation of builders
So he's he's into construction already.
So this would be a relevant Profile
that we could look for and what you
need to be checking is The type of
engagement that is getting on his post.
So take a look at this one So not
a lot of engagement is getting like
below 10 comments for each post.
So I wouldn't regard this
as very good Influencer.
So I'll move on to the next person.
So for the example, this person
is Sophie Hogan is the director
of Hogan Homes and Development.
So I would take a look at that.
This person is Simon Doherty.
He's a construction recruitment manager.
So I would take a look at that.
I'll move on to the next person.
So this is Mehta Soltani social
media platform, civil engineering.
Okay.
He's talking about construction stuff.
So let's open his profile.
Then take a look at this.
She is unstoppable media.
Okay.
It looks like she's a coach
in, let's take a look anyway,
construction, irrigation stuff.
So let's take a look at
this profile, see who it is.
Okay.
It's not showing us the profile for
some reason, but I'll keep moving on.
Future of construction is here.
Let's take a look at who this is.
Successfully even more never see.
Okay.
Let me just take a look
at that profile anyway.
And then
let's take a look at that profile as well.
So we're trying to find
influencers in this manner.
So over time, if you scroll through
and like, say, you have to try
multiple variations of keywords.
You can't just select one keyword and
find all influencers in that space.
So after you go through like
a bunch of profiles in here,
human resources, that's HR post.
Tracy, let's take a look at that.
These are all job posts.
Augmented reality, okay, not really.
Construction,
let's take a look at his profile.
Engineering and Geosys
companies reach massive.
Engineering companies, yes,
to an extent this is relevant.
So it may not exactly be in construction
as long as they publish good content
on construction, it should be fine.
Construction, again, he's
a construction creator.
So very good prospect there.
Now what I'll do is I'll go
through each of these profiles
and see if they're relevant.
So this guy is creating good
content on construction.
I could use this as an influencer, but
he's not generating a lot of engagement.
So I'm a bit skeptical over there.
So we'll move on.
She's in the construction space.
Oh, she's getting good engagement.
Look at that content.
So this is somebody I would consider,
but the first thing you need to look
at is, is checking if they have good,
relevant posts that are the type of
posts that we're looking to engage on.
So this is announcement post so this is
announcements about stuff in creating.
Okay.
This is a good creator.
Daily grind.
She's publishing like a variety
of types of content pieces.
Budget rant.
Okay.
This is a good creator.
So now what I'll do is I will make
sure that the post screen is selected.
The post screen is selected and
I will copy this URL and I'll go
to the content analysis sheet.
Okay.
Your content analysis sheet.
And one of the worksheets in
the content analysis sheet is
called the influencer sheet.
All right.
So what I will do is
I will paste the post.
Post page URL.
Okay.
Look at the post page URL and I will
copy the name of the influencer.
So come in here, copy the name of
the influencer and I'll come in here.
All right.
Now there is a bit of manual
work involved in here.
After you create like a list of
influencers, you need to take
a look at, you need to figure
out when they're publishing.
Now this is difficult because
it's difficult to understand.
They don't exactly show the
time of posting on LinkedIn.
You need to.
Check their profile frequently
every day until you figure out
like at what times they post.
So you should be able to figure
out what time they're posting
within a margin of 30 minutes.
And this is a constant activity.
So ideally for the next few days,
you should be checking these
influencer profiles every day.
And if the post is published today
or like within 24 hours, you can
see like the exact hour count.
So 18 hours, 12 hours, et cetera.
So you should be able to figure out.
at what times they're posting.
Most creators publish at
the same time every day.
So this should be somewhat easy.
But once you figure that out, you
should be coming in here and dropping
your comment in the comments column and
saying something like she posts at 10 a.
m.
day.
So the reason we do this is because for
influencer posts, we need to comment on
their posts, ideally within the first 30
minutes after they publish so that the
future comments that are coming in on that
post see our comment and we generate some
engagement and brand awareness using that.
Alright this is not important for sales
navigator feed posts and, and posts on
your feed when you comment on them, but
this is important for influencer posts.
So the next step is to go through
like all the tabs that you've
opened with different influencers
as he's building teams for tomorrow.
He looks like in the construction
space from the cover image.
And take a look at the engagement.
He's getting good engagement
like likes are good.
Managing partner TLO.
So he, they specifically focus
on architecture, engineering
and construction firms.
So yeah, our same target audience.
So the content should be relevant as well.
So this is another guy I would consider.
And I'll keep doing this latest
development in engineering.
So could be relevant.
Circle building, construction industry,
alerting traffic like the forklift.
So this is very relevant.
And you see the engagement is
getting, this is another good
influencer that we could use.
Corina.
So let's take a look at Corina.
Corina is I guess this
is a branding agency.
Oh, no.
CPR construction cleaning.
So she, she's created in
the construction space.
So I'm assuming that
construction cleaning.
Okay.
So she does publish some content about
construction, but not very relevant.
So you could take a look at the post
before making a decision, whether she's a
good influencer or not, but I'm moving on
to the next person creating innovation.
A few harmless.
Avalanche of destruction.
Google announces mind
boggling universally.
A translator tool.
Personal brand.
Can I be better at everything?
So not really very
relevant on construction.
So I'm going to move on to the next
person and take a look at the content.
Sponsorship.
No, this is not a relevant conversation.
Relevant influencer.
Mobility, freedom for people to
reduce mobility, automating it.
So he powers stuff about tech.
So this could be a good example for the
niche sorry, the viral influencer persona.
So this is a good example you can take.
So many of these that we saw are all
good examples of viral influencer
persona because they are getting
very good engagement on the content.
But for for niche persona
this is not a good example.
We need to be focusing on people in the
construction space because construction is
a case study that we are targeting, right?
So look at this.
No, not a good.
example.
So I keep doing this until I generate
a list of at least 20 influencers.
Now 20 is the number, the target number.
So in here we need to be documenting at
least 20 people with their posts page URL.
And you need to do this for a couple
of days, check their profiles for a
couple of days until you can figure
out at what time they're posting.
So most influencers will be posting
at the same time because they're
consistent with their content process.
And that is how they build the
followings in the first place.
But once you fill this out.
You should be checking these over every
day and then taking a look at the posts
that they're publishing every day.
And after they publish the post of piece
of content, you should be following the
exact same commanding process that we
just walked through for sales navigator,
feed posts and your LinkedIn feed posts.
Now, that is how we find influencers
and go about and comment.
But the next step is to talk about how to
use ChatGPT for quick comment generation
for all of the different types of posts.
So any post you want to do, you can use
ChatGPT to create the comments quickly.
And I'm going to show you
quickly how to do that.
All right, so this is ChatGPT and
we use a very simple prompt in here,
like, I want you to create a 25 to 40
word comment for a post I sent you.
The tone of voice used in the comment
you generate should be that of a thought
leader who's an expert in construction.
So this should be personalized for
whatever your own industry is, for your
business, whatever your industry is in
you should personalize this with that.
And then we say the
comment should be positive.
And first reference some details
mentioned in the post and then end with
a question about some related detail.
Do not include hashtags in the comment.
And then we say this is the post and
we drop the link to drop the post copy.
Just copy paste the entire post
post copy and drop it in here.
And chat GPT will create a comment for
you saying as a fellow construction
professional, I empathize with your
disappointment regarding the lack of
support in the recent budget streamlining.
The bureaucratic process is crucial.
How can we ensure timely
approvals and remove obstacles
for small house builders like us?
Very easy and very easy to create.
And all I need to do now is
copy paste this into LinkedIn.
So I can go to LinkedIn and this is
the post I want to create comment on.
And I can click on comment.
And paste it in there.
And I can also tag the person
the creator of the post.
All right.
And click on post.
That's it.
Very simple process for creating comments.
If you don't want to like write the
comments manually yourself, and you
can do this for all kinds of posts
to generate comments very quickly.
So that sums up the
network activation video and this
helps us activate our existing network
on LinkedIn very quickly so that we
prime the algorithm to get more users
to see our content, engage on our
content, and quickly build a following
and start generating inbound leads.
And it's important that you set this
up quickly, especially the endorsements
and the liking post liking campaign so
that that happens in an ongoing fashion.
Every few months you can do a new sales
navigator search and add more of your new
first degree connections to that list.
So that's it for this video.
See you in the next video.