The first step of improving your
LinkedIn content engine is learning how
content promotion works on LinkedIn.
Before we get into LinkedIn
content promotion specifically,
I'd like to touch a bit about the
80 20 rule of content marketing.
The 80 20 rule of content marketing
states that only 20 percent of
all your content marketing efforts
should go into content creation.
Only 20 percent of the time and
effort you spend on content marketing
should go into content creation.
And 80 percent of it should
go into content promotion.
Now beyond this being a guideline on
how to utilize your time for content
marketing, it is a principle that you
should follow for your mindset when you
approach LinkedIn content marketing.
1820 rule of content marketing means
you should be spending most of your
focus on content promotion and it
underlines the importance of promotion
in any content marketing strategy.
If you take a look at content marketing as
a whole with some statistics, there are 3.
7 million videos uploaded
on YouTube every day.
That's every single day.
There's over 2 million blog
posts published every single day.
There's millions and millions of social
media posts that are published on all the
social media platforms every single day.
Now, when there is so much noise on
every single social media platform, it
is important to figure out how to promote
your content actively and efficiently.
Now, how does content
promotion work on social media?
The difference with social media
or say like publishing a piece of
content on your website is that on
your website, you can reach out to
a couple contacts in your industry.
You can reach out to journalists.
And get them to feature your content.
You can send it to your target
audience via an email list and
get them to read your content.
But on social media, the algorithm decides
who sees and doesn't see your content.
It is the algorithm on LinkedIn or
Tok that decides who in your first
degree network or who among your
followers should read the content.
There is a network aspect to promoting
your content on social media.
So say, one of your connections shares
or likes or comments on your content.
On your video, the algorithm will
show to more of their network,
which can be your first, second
degree or third degree network.
And as more and more people engage with
your content, the LinkedIn algorithm
or the Facebook algorithm or the TikTok
algorithm opens it up to more of your
wider network on these platforms.
This is especially true in LinkedIn's
case, even if you have a hundred
thousand connections on LinkedIn,
LinkedIn will not show your content
to those a hundred thousand people.
They will show you
content to a small subset.
of those 100, 000 people, which
could be like a thousand connections.
And once LinkedIn shows your content
to them, if they engage, LinkedIn
will measure their engagement and
then show it to a wider subset of
your followers or your connections.
And then as more people engage,
LinkedIn will show it to more people.
And this trend continues.
So unless you gain engagement
consistently with your content, by
creating really good content, your
content will not generate a lot of reach.
But on most social media platforms
and on LinkedIn specifically, you can
give an initial push to your content.
with the help of pods.
Pods, that's P O D S, are
communities of content creators
on social media platforms.
That help engage with
each other's content.
So it could be videos, it could be content
posts, it could be random statuses or
images, or images of you holding a cap.
But these people like, comment,
and share on each other's content.
So that it gets that initial push,
which is very important on LinkedIn.
The algorithm takes into account
the engagement, which is the
likes, comments, and shares.
That you get in the first few hours of
posting, especially the first two hours.
So if you get a significant number
of likes comments and shares in the
first hour That is a signal to the
linkedin algorithm that your content is
engaging and valuable and interesting
think about the scenario You post
a piece of content on LinkedIn and
you get one like and one comment.
The algorithm is going to assume that
that is not a good piece of content.
But if you get like a hundred likes
and a hundred comments in the first
two hours after you post something,
that is a signal to the algorithm
that your content is very engaging.
But how do you get a hundred likes
and a hundred comments on your posts?
This is what we're going to show you.
In the content promotion lessons,
there are two ways you can do this.
The first approach is using
manual pods and the second
approach is using automated pods.
Let me explain both of these.
Manual pods are communities.
Think Facebook groups or WhatsApp groups
or Telegram groups of content creators on
LinkedIn that you can join as a member.
You can share your content and other
members of these communities will
like, comment and share all your posts
so that you get that initial push.
And these communities work
on a reciprocal engagement.
So if other members are posting their
content, you will be expected to engage
with those content pieces as well.
Automated pods are manual
pods in an automated fashion.
With the help of software and
tech, you can connect your LinkedIn
account to automation tools like
LinkBoost, Lempod, and so on.
That will help you quickly
gain a large number of likes
and comments on your posts.
Posts.
The approach here is simple.
You add a link to your LinkedIn post
into these softwares and it can get you
a couple hundred likes and a couple dozen
comments in the first one to two hours.
So in the eyes of the LinkedIn algorithm,
you are generating a lot of engagement on
your content as soon as you post the link.
This will get the LinkedIn algorithm.
to open up the reach on your content
to a larger percentage of your
first degree, second degree and
third degree network on LinkedIn.
And ultimately you'll get a lot more
reach and views on your content.
The other advantage of using Paul's
or content promotion communities is
that all the social engagement that
you're getting on this content that
you're posting on LinkedIn will give
you social proof as a thought leader.
The main goal of content
promotion is very simple.
Whenever one of your
prospects on LinkedIn.
opens up their social media feed
or their linkedin feed, your
content has to be at the very top.
And if you're able to replicate
this consistently by consistently
creating content and consistently
promoting that content with the
help of pods, over time, they will
begin to know, like, and trust you.
Now let's take a look at how
to join manual pods or set
up an automated pod system.
And show you three ways in
which you can find manual pods.
And then I'll show you how link
boost works, which is an automated
pod tool that we recommend.
Now, finding manual pods is It's not
very difficult, but you'll have to
put some work into it at the start.
So what all you need to do is go to Google
and search for LinkedIn engagement pod.
That's it.
When you do this, it will bring up
a bunch of blog posts about stuff.
But now what you can do is go through
each of these and see if they are
recommending any engagement pod.
So If you go into Lempod, which is
an engagement pod tool themselves you
won't be able to find a lot of them.
But when you look through the post you
can see like a lot of communities that
they mentioned, like Game of Content, this
is a LinkedIn group that they recommend.
They have LinkedIn growth hackers,
which looks, seems to be a Facebook
group that they recommend that
they've linked it over here.
They've mentioned, okay, these are
automatic pods, but this is one way in
which you can go about finding pods.
So you'll have to browse around a bit
on Google and find some engagement pods.
This is one way.
The engagement pods exist on
Facebook, WhatsApp, and LinkedIn.
These are three platforms
you should be focusing on.
So if you want to look for engagement
pods specifically on WhatsApp,
you'll have to enter them like this.
WhatsApp.
And you should be able to find
when you scroll through these,
you should be able to find.
Some specific pods that they link to in
whatsapp like publish engagement pods
or invite links to whatsapp And you can
join their whatsapp groups and try to get
engagement from those pods and so on now.
This is just one way to find it
The next way is to go to LinkedIn.
So again, just you go to
sorry, you go to Facebook.
So the next way to do
this is go to Facebook.
And in the search box, just
for LinkedIn engagement pod,
and you can look for groups.
So these are the groups I'm a part of.
So these are all.
LinkedIn engagement post
growth hacking marketing pods.
You can join that pod.
Check if they're active
or they seem to be active.
They post four posts published a week.
This one is 10 plus posts.
Okay.
This is LinkedIn for jobs
are not really relevant.
This is 10 posts a year.
So it's not very engaging.
So I'm going to keep going.
LinkedIn networking, six posts a day.
Okay.
This one seems to be good.
So I would join that.
VaynerNation, they don't see
how many posts are there.
Then I'm going to keep going.
I'm going to keep going.
Social media influencers.
So I would join this
and see if it's a pod.
Many of them don't publicly
market them as pods.
So they would just.
Name it as social media
influencers or social media content
promotion and stuff like that.
So you could look for other
keywords or try joining these
groups and see if that works.
Engagement groups.
So this is something 10 plus posts a day.
They're active.
So all of these I would join and
see if they're a good part to join.
This requires some manual checking.
The reason I'm not suggesting some
specific parts, like doing the
research myself and suggesting some
specific parts is that from what
we've seen over time, many groups
tend to become less and less active.
So it's important that you look.
For the updated for an updated part is
the most updated part is the most updated
communities on facebook or whatsapp or
linkedin that are actively creating where
users are actively sharing content and
engaging with other users All right.
So this is the second way of doing
it on facebook And the third way
is to look on LinkedIn itself.
So if you look at LinkedIn you can
just search for content engagement
pods and click on see all results.
And if you filter specifically for groups,
you can see a lot of engagement pods.
So this is an engagement pod.
This is a content engagement pod,
but this one is only three members.
So I can just close this off.
Lawyers, native engagement booster,
not a pod, more impressions,
organically hassle free.
There's 23 members.
It could be active.
So I would want to open that professional.
So these are all small.
So i'm going to move on to the next page
and see personal branding community.
I would try joining this grow your
personal brand become consistent again.
I would join this and see if it's
good quality content for sas sdrs
There's niche specific parts as well.
So you could join them
and see if that works.
Otherwise what I would do
is move on to the next one.
All right.
Now, please note that you will
have to try with multiple keywords.
So all I did was search for
LinkedIn engagement pods
or content engagement pods.
You could look for engagement pods
just like that engagement product
for the golden Goldman Lattin.
So there's engagement pod, L I E C.
All of these are pods that you
can join on LinkedIn itself.
These are groups that you
can share a piece of content.
And get other members to engage.
And at the same time you will need
to reciprocate engagement as well.
So this is how you find pods.
Now, how do you use a pod?
So let me pull up like a
pod that I'm a part of.
So in most pods, this is how it works.
So they'll post an update.
On like when we should start the posting.
So usually on the morning
sometime in your time zone.
If they're in your same time zone
and they will ask us to drop them in.
And all you need to do is come in and
drop comments with the link to your post.
This is Facebook, for example, but
it works in exactly the same way.
All you need to do is come in and
drop a comment and people will engage.
And there'll be some ways in which
you can denote that you've engaged.
So this person is liked because these
people, these people have liked because
they've already engaged with this post.
That they've shared and the
same manner you reciprocate
engagement on other posts as well.
And you get engagement from that content.
Now manual posts are good.
You will have to spend at least half
an hour to just dig through Google,
dig through Facebook, dig through
LinkedIn to find some good communities.
You'll have to join those communities.
You should also be searching for
bots on WhatsApp because bots on
WhatsApp tend to be more active.
And after you're done and you find some
communities and you join them, join some
WhatsApp groups you need to pay attention
to them for at least a week to see which
ones are engaging and which ones you're
getting good engagement from and so on.
So once you're done with that what I'd
recommend is, is documenting the pods that
you're already part of and making sure
that it's included in the process so that
the person who's handling the promotion
of the content actively use these.
Pods are moving forward
for promoting the content.
Now let's take a look at link boost.
Now link boost is an easier way if you're
willing to spend a couple of bucks.
Paying for a software that can automate
this process for us because the problem
With manual engagement bots is that
you'll have to spend you'll have to
reciprocate engagement So you'll have to
go to their each of their posts You'll
have to drop a comment and like on their
posts And if there are considerable number
of members in the community if it's an
active community You will have to spend
at least like one hour a day to do this.
So in my opinion if you take a look at
the expenses for one hour, it's far better
to just sign up to a tool like LingBoost.
There are other tools that are
available that do the same thing.
So, Lempod is another tool
that allows you to do it.
But what we use is LingBoost.
You can experiment with both.
You can use both and try to get engagement
from the users of both tools as well.
It's up to you.
But for the sake of this video to
explain the process, I'm going to
explain like how Lingboos works.
Lempod works in, in almost
exactly the same way as well.
So this should work for both.
All right.
Now what is linkBoost?
So what automated pods do is
you can join a bunch of pods.
There'll be other members in those
pods, all of the LinkedIn accounts
of all of those members and you
will be connected to the software.
So the software handles the
liking and the commenting.
You can also input comments that
you want to come below your post.
And LinkBoost will automate
all of that for you.
Now, what I'm going to do is
I'm going to show you how we use
LinkBoost actively to create content.
Sorry, to promote content.
So the first thing you need
to do is sign up for a plan.
What I'd recommend is when you get
started to sign up for the premium plan.
If multiple users from your team, multiple
members from your team are creating
content, I'd recommend the plus plan.
And if you take the you'll be
able to get a bit of a discount,
but premium monthly is what I'd
recommend for you to get started.
And later on, you can
move to the plus monthly.
All right.
Now I already have.
The plus quaternary plan and
I am in link boost right now.
It's a simple process to sign up.
You just need to Sign up for the
tool By clicking on get link boost.
You will have to install
a chrome extension.
So this is the chrome extension
i've installed and that's about
it and then after you've installed
the Chrome extension, they'll
ask you to log into LinkedIn.
So you'll have to log into
LinkedIn from the Chrome profile.
So that link posts can fetch
your LinkedIn session cookies.
You don't need to give them the
password or anything, you just
need to log into LinkedIn account
from your browser as usual.
But once you've done that link, boom,
will link post will automatically
connect with your LinkedIn account
and then you're ready to get started.
So the first thing that you need to
do is find pods find communities.
So even in LinkBoost there are a
lot of communities that you should.
The joining ideally what I'm going
to do now is I'd like you to pause
this video in bits and take a look
at all of these communities that have
at least a hundred members of them.
So you can see the number
of members in here.
done all the hard work for you.
And we've taken a look at all of
the best communities on LinkBoost.
So LinkBoost because the engagement is
automated the pods will remain over there.
You will continue to get engagement
from these pods in LinkBoost.
So you can take a look at these
pod names and you can search them.
In the pod section.
So once you go to find pods, you
can in this section, you can enter
the names of each of the pods that
I'm about to show you right now, and
you can find them and you can join
them by clicking on this button.
So after you search for something,
say digital marketing as an example.
So if you search for digital marketing
as an example, and you find the
digital marketing group here, you
can click on join pod, this link,
and a request will be sent to the
admin of this pod to join the pod.
They can also, it can also
be an auto approval pod.
So new members will automatically
be accepted, but some cases
admins will be moderating.
The request to join from the new members
and you'd have to wait for approval
for a couple of days until you're
accepted, but let's take a look at
the pods that you should be joining.
So take a look at the pods in here
that have at least a hundred members.
So that is what you should be
aiming for to not join any pods that
have less than a hundred members.
The more number of members you have.
in these pods the better.
So what I want you to do in here
is search for each of these pods in
the find pod screen, this tab, and
search for them and join those pods.
So that's all you need to do.
Once you get accepted to those
pods, you can start engaging.
So growth hacking pod is a good one.
Digital marketing is another good one.
Startups and fintech pod is a good one.
Please note that you need
to search exactly like this.
So there's a hashtag At the start you
need to use that then there's sas growth
hacks linkedin hackers experts from leads
to profit hash run growth hackers usa b2b
usa digital marketing strategies india
if you want an indian audience SAS growth
hacking tools and content, B2B leads and
prospects Asia, LinkedIn Australia if
you want Australian engagement, mutual
growth, people over 10, 000 followers
Indian part again, it's an Indian one,
QAres, digital marketing, this is a
small one, you can ignore this, then
we have innovation strategy, digital
transformation in English, take a look
at this, we have 11, we have about 1, 109
members in here, so that's good, then we
have best LinkedIn network, Brazil B2B,
we have coaches and consultant engagement
board, people with SSI score 60 plus,
It doesn't matter if you have SSI score
60 plus, you can you can request to
join the pod and you should be accepted.
In most cases, then we have
professionals in the USA only.
We have B2B needs and marketing
board, auto likes and comments,
SAS growth and marketing link.
Okay.
That's a small one.
SEO and digital marketing,
leadership content.
Startup Mentoring USA, Digital
Marketing Top Influencers, United
States, Germany, United Kingdom,
Canada, and B2B Industry, USA Growth
Post, USA Healthcare, Growth Pod.
So in this manner, just take a look.
I'm just going to scroll
through the entire page.
I think we're about done.
So just go through the remaining
ones and join all of these pods.
So I want you to go to Find Pods.
This tab, find pods and I want
you to search for these pod
names and join all of them.
And if you get accepted to these
pods, you should be able to go ahead
and start generating engagement.
So just pause this, pause the
video for a couple of minutes.
And go through each of the ones, search
for each of these names that you see
on the screen and join those pods.
Now, after you've done joining
those pods you need to start using
LinkBoost to promote your content.
And I'm going to show you how to use
So what you need to do here
is click on posts and in here,
there'll be a button for a new post.
You see, this is a new post button.
So just click on that.
And this will pull up a screen where
you can promote a new post on LinkedIn.
So what do you need to include in here?
What do you need to do to just
start generating engagement for
your content after you've been
accepted to a bunch of pods?
So these are all the pods
that I've been accepted to.
So what do you need to do to
start generating engagement?
Is first copy a link to a linkedin
post So i'm going to go ahead and
copy a post linkedin post in here.
So for example, i'll take one of my
posts i'm going to copy the url to
that post So after you've published a
linkedin post you can copy the url to
that post Like this, you can come in
here and you just need to paste the
URL of that post and that's it, right?
And then you need to select the pods.
There's two things you need to keep
in mind over here and two approaches
or routes that you can take.
So the first route is if you want to
maximize engagement on all your content.
So this is something that I'd recommend
for your for your content pieces that
you want, really want to perform well.
I'm not talking about salesy content.
I'm talking about important
content that you'd like to promote.
So if you feel that a content piece is
really valuable, it's really good content,
then maximizing the engagement on that
content will make it perform really well.
I'm not talking about like say
salesy content or like a webinar
promotion post that you really
want to get into the masses.
So don't maximize engagement on those.
Ideally the ones that you should maximize
engagement on should be the posts that
you are sure will perform well because
they're either viral posts or like a
very valuable resource
giveaway or something.
Of that sort in the post so in such cases
you can promote that you can maximize
the engagement now in order to maximize
the engagement you can auto select pods
So what linkboost will do is linkboost
will select the biggest pods that you
are a part of So these are the biggest
pods that i'm a part of and in my plan
I can promote in 20 pods, promote by
continent, 20 pods, and it automatically
selects the top 20 pods that are the
biggest parts that I'm a part of.
All right.
And I can go ahead and post it.
Now, if it is not like say a post
that you want to maximize engagement
on, you don't want to be doing that.
What you need to do is make sure
that you have selected a total
of at least thousand members.
Let me explain that.
So for example, this member, this
part is about 445 members and
this one is about 722 members.
So if I select both of these what happens
is I will have at least a thousand people.
If I am getting engagement
from the entire part.
So 1000 as a number will is the
minimum number of people that we
need to ideally be part of the pods
that we generate the engagement from.
Now the reason I suggest this is
once you've done this for these first
two pods, the next time you do it,
you can do it for the next two pods.
So I'll have to select one more in this
case to hit the number of thousand.
And the next time I promote another piece
of content, I'll select three other pods.
So because I do this, I will
generate engagement from different
users every single time I publish.
And that helps us reach more
wider audiences in the longterm.
So this is the approach that I'd
recommend for normal LinkedIn publishing.
Just make sure you select as many pods
so that you can generate engagement
from at least a thousand members, there
should be at least a thousand members
cumulatively in the pods that you select.
That is what you should keep in mind.
All right.
Now after you've selected a bunch of pods
in here I'd like to show you something.
LinkBoost also allows you to
include comments for your post.
So what I can do is I can click on either
click on generate comments using AI.
So we need to select, enter
the number of comments.
So you can click on 30 and click
on generate comments using AI.
Sorry, it's only 20.
So let's enter 20.
It's my bad.
And it automatically generates comments
using AI, but this tool is glitchy, which
is why even in one of the previous videos
where we showed you how to generate, use
link boost to generate automatic comments.
We showed you how to use chat GPT.
Now I'm going to pull up chat
GPT and show you exactly how to
go about doing this right now.
So this is chat GPT.
You can find it at chat.
openai.
com.
Just go there, sign up for a free account.
You can also sign up
using your Google account.
And once you've signed up, just create
a new chat and enter this specific
prompt that I've used over here.
So all we do is we enter this very
simple prompt like Prepare 30 comments
for this LinkedIn post by your name.
So this should be your name the
post author and here are some rules.
I'd like you to follow.
The comment should contain three
questions, some funny comments,
some positive comments, some
negative and some neutral comments.
The comment should be unique and
the length should be in between five
words and 15 words in each comment.
Add emojis in five comments
and only in five comments.
All right.
Here is the post and then we just
copy paste the post copy of the post.
So for videos, ideally you should be
adding a bit more description in here.
If you'd like but the idea is to generate
good comments that are relevant to the
to the text or the post so what I would
do is i'll just copy paste the exact post
copy of the post that I want to generate
automated comments for and chat gpt
will well save us a great deal of time.
It takes like I believe like at least 10
or 20 minutes to like put together 30 good
comments But chat gpt has gone ahead and
created for us in seconds, and that's all
you need to do to generate comments So
for every single post what I would do is
open this post in linkedin copy paste the
post copy into chat gpt Use this exact
prompt you can type this out from the
video you can mix ideally like what I'd
recommend is creating your own prompt.
So you can personalize this a little bit.
You can add more emojis.
You can increase the number of
comments that you want to generate.
You can reduce the number of questions,
increase the number of questions,
make most of them funny comments,
make I vary the length of the, of
the comments between five and 15.
If you want longer comments, you
can make it in between like 10 and
30 words in each comment and chat.
GPD will do it for you.
So what I'd like you to do is prepare
your own prompt, but in case you don't
want to spend time on it you can just
copy paste this you can just take this
this prompt from the video that I've used
So just pause the video type it out and
test this out in chatgpd now After you do
that, you just copy paste the post copy
and that's it And you click on enter and
chatgpd will generate the comments for you
And now all you need to do is just copy
paste All of these comments that ChatGPT
has generated for you and come back to
LinkBoost and paste the comments in here.
So I guess it's gone ahead and created
the, the, the, the AI comments.
But even if this works for you what I can
tell you is that AI generated comments
are not very good from LinkBoost if
you created directly using LinkBoost.
Do use doing it using
chat gpt is far better.
And sometimes this tool glitches a
little bit So what I'd recommend is
using chat gpt It's just that you have
to go out of the tool and just spend
like a minute to create it yourself but
it's It's the better process to use.
So after I've added the comments
I can choose to add more comments.
So we're going to get engagement
from a lot of users So I
could add on more comments.
I could add up to 100 comments
and you can easily create
them by simply asking chat gpt
and if you enter something like
this chat gpt will create 30 more
comments for you see very simple But
for this video, I'm just going to go
ahead and continue with the process.
So the next thing you need to
focus on is, is selecting like
what kind of engagement you want.
Now don't be misled by human
like behavior and viral effect.
What works better is
still normal engagement.
So that is what I'd recommend for you.
The random interval the best random
interval setting that you should be
setting should be 10 to 20 seconds
because we want the engagement to
come in as quickly as possible.
You could go up to 20 to 40
seconds or 40 to 60 seconds, but
do not choose any of these options
because they're not very good.
So 10 to 20 seconds, 20 or 40
seconds or 40 or 60 seconds
is what I would recommend.
You can play around and experiment
with it a little bit if you'd like.
Now there is also a setting in
Linkboost that allows you to generate
engagement from a custom audience.
So what do we mean by a custom audience?
So you can choose.
The locations that, that
you get the engagement from.
So even after you've we have about,
I guess we have about 200, 2037 users
that will be engaging on our content
from the pods that we selected.
But even among those users, you can
choose to get engagement, say only from
Belgium or only from Ireland or only from.
Europe or United Kingdom or,
or Uni, the United States.
So you can filter it
in that manner as well.
You can also filter by industries,
but what I'd recommend is
going about it like this.
What you need to do first
is click on unselect all.
So click on unselect all,
make sure all is selected.
Okay.
So click on unselect all.
Click on sorry, not,
or it's need to select.
And so it's unselect all and, and.
And then click on Australia.
Then click on United
States, United Kingdom.
You can select I don't know, all
the locations for the, from where
I want to generate engagement.
So all of them will include Germany.
India is fine.
I would select the Middle East as well.
Ireland Poland is good.
Philippines, no.
Malaysia is fine.
Singapore.
So just choose all the countries where
you'd like to generate engagement from.
And once you've done that you can
go ahead and select industries.
But the issue with industries is
that it doesn't really get you
a relevant engagement of users
from that specific industry.
So this is not something that
I would recommend you do.
You can play around with it and
experiment with it as you'd like.
But my recommendation would
be to select all of these.
If you're not selecting any industries
you need to click on, or if you are
selecting any industries, you can
select on and so what this does is if
you select and, and select like a bunch
of countries it will look at, okay,
they need to be in these countries and
they need to be in these locations.
That's how.
LinkBoost filters it.
So if you look for advertising services
and leisure and travel and tourism,
they need to be in these countries
that I've selected and they need
to be in any of these industries.
That's the way it works.
If I'm not selecting any specific industry
and I'm only selecting location, you
can click on all and you should be good.
So we have about 1, 500 users.
So this is the number I was talking about.
Ideally we should be getting engagement
from at least a thousand users.
So you should be joining as many pods.
Anything above 500 is fine, but I
like to get as much engagement as
possible, which is why I try to do this.
And once I've, I've gotten this,
I don't select a specific number
of likes I want on the post.
I'd like to get as many likes as possible.
Typically, you should be able to
generate I think this LinkBoost 700 likes
for me and up to a hundred comments.
I don't usually use the full limit.
But yeah, that should give you an
idea on like how much engagement you
can receive in an automated fashion.