So this video is going to be about informative
posts. Now, informative posts, just like the
name sounds, are about, well, informative posts
that shed light on a specific topic. Now, this
is kind of like a generic content format. There
is nothing very special about this content
format. It's just a text post on LinkedIn that
is informative to your target audience on a
specific topic that is interesting to your target
audience. So in this case, Sachin is in the
crypto space. So he published a post about how
crypto and NFT are becoming common in this sporting
world. And of course, we have a post about it.
So it's a very generic content format. You
don't need outlines for this. You can just choose
good topics. So the key thing for Informative
Posts are choosing good topics and creating good
hooks. So let's first take a look at the content
template for Informative Posts. So the process
starts with you creating a duplicate of this.
and then these need to be discussed on the content
ideation calls. You can come up with some informative
posts ideas yourself. So you can search for
interesting news. You can search for publications,
websites that have active blogs in that specific
industry. You can search and look at competitor
websites and try to come up with some ideas.
But informative posts are all about industry-specific
content that does not have any media format
in them. So you can include images with them,
but it's not necessary. It is just a simple
text post that provides information on a specific
topic. Now you can add an outline, and you can
discuss it with the executive on the calls.
The executive will share some information about
their take on that specific topic. And once
you've beefed out the outline, the content management
process begins with the content manager assigning
each of the content tasks. And the content management
process for informative posts works exactly
like an experiencial story, except the post copy
part, everything else is the same, including
all the subtasks. So I'm not going to dive deep
into that because it's exactly the same. But
let's take a look at how to optimize. Informative
posts. So, informative posts, the key element
you need to focus on are hooks, just like usual.
So, go through the hooks. In fact, many of
these hooks can be used on informative stories
because there is no restriction on the media
or the content format. They work for almost
all topics. So, go through the hooks, find
a suitable hook that works for your topic. And
then after you create the hook for the for
the informative posts and write the post out,
then you need to focus on the formatting, which
is very important. So the formatting optimization
for informative posts, this section will really
help you. So that's skimming and the other type
of formatting that you can use are concentrating.
So both of these, in fact, what you see over
here is an informative post that we covered
in the video. So this was covered in one of
the previous videos called how to create content
in different content formats. So rewatch that
video if you'd like, if you'd like to learn
more. and revise yourself on the formatting
lessons. But formatting and hooks are all you
need for creating informative posts. It's all
about choosing the right topics that are relevant
in the industry, and that is interesting to
your target audience. And that will be shared
by your executive on the team, or you can Google
around, you can take a look at competitor websites.
So competitors tend to do their own research
and try to come up with interesting.
or you can look at news in the industry. Now
news is very easy. All you need to do is search
for a specific keyword and then click on news
in the industry. And you can come up with a
bunch of interesting news topics that you can
use for finding really good informative post
ideas. So that's it for this video. I'll see
you in the next one.