And LinkBoost requires you to pay
right at the start,
so I think the plans
vary
from free stuff to premium to plus
the free stuff is not enough
because we'll be posting every single day ideally
so you can start off with the premium plan
and the premium plan is straight in an USD amount
and you can post
one post every single day of the month.
Alright, so
let's move on
to LinkBoost and why we use LinkBoost
so let me give you a quick introduction
into LinkedIn content promotion and why it's essential
to
gain traction with content marketing on LinkedIn first.
Now,
whenever you post a piece of content on LinkedIn,
LinkedIn does not automatically or immediately
show it to all of your connections and your followers,
but rather it shows it to
a small percentage
of your connections and your followers.
So if you post a piece of content and you get, say
one like and one comment in the first 2 hours,
2 or 3 hours of posting,
LinkedIn will immediately assume the algorithm
will immediately assume
that
the piece of content is not engaging enough,
which is why it's not generating a lot of engagement.
But if you post something
and you are able to generate
dozens of likes and dozens of
comments in the first few hours of posting,
that is a signal to the algorithm that the post is very
engaging, so it opens up
the reach of.
The post to a larger percentage
of your First degree, Second degree
and Third degree connections and your followers.
This is what we are trying to do
with content promotion tools like LinkBoost.
We will deep dive
into
content promotion later onto the program,
but for the time being
all you need to do is sign up to be time to LinkBoost.
I suggest using the premium plan.
The premium plan
will allow you
to publish one post every day
so that should be more than enough for now.
It's 29 USD a month,
just sign up for it
and it works exactly the same
way like Taplio
so you will have to install a chrome extension
to use LinkBoost
and connect to your LinkedIn account,
but it's pretty simple to set up,
but after you've done with
setting a linkboost
every day, what I want you to do is take a look at
the Queue
and the time zone that you've set up in Taplio.
So in my case
I've set up
the post to go live at 8 am my time from Taplio,
so every day 8 am
opposed those life.
Now
what I will do is I will set up a reminder or an alarm
in my calendar or in my phone
reminding me to engage of the post.
Now this is important.
You can just choose to publish
from Taplio and not engage,
but you will always get the best results
if you promote the boost using LinkBoost
and you manually respond to all the comments,
so assume this will take approximately
30 minutes of your time
on all the days.
On all the working days that you're publishing
and this has to be done manually.
You can choose
just automate the whole thing,
automate the publishing
and just not promote and not engage with the content,
but that will affect your reach
and I wouldn't recommend it.
But once I've set an alarm,
all I will do is every day when I log into
LinkedIn I will log into LinkedIn
I will copy the link to the post.
So for example,
if this is the post that I've just published,
I will just copy a link to the post,
so this is a link to the post I will come
into LinkBoost,
I will click on
posts
and I will add a new post.
So this is the daily process that you need to follow,
but let me walk you through the entire process
step by step on how to set up
LinkBoost first
for optimal
reach of your content.
So let's take a look at how to find
the right communities of pods in LinkBoost.
So think of pods as communities,
small communities,
or groups of contemporators on LinkedIn
who are trying to build engagement on each
other's content
that they publish on LinkedIn.
So
rather than find
relevant pods on specific topics or relevant pods on
specific locations like Brazil.
For example, just focus on joining the biggest pods.
I will explain how to filter them by location,
which is the main filter that matters
when we schedule and publish the content,
or for the time being
just focus on finding really big pods and joining them.
So all you need to do to join big pods
is click on join pod
in here
and Link
Boost will send a request
to the pod that meant to join the pod
so I keep doing this
until I send out requests to as many pods as possible.
I'm going to keep doing those German
so there's a bunch of them in here'
all of these are pillow hundred users so I'm not very
interested in joining parts below hundred users
because LinkBoost has some parts that have
already have hundreds of users.
I've already joined a lot of them
so you can find like
the biggest parts on LinkBoost in here already. So
just
search for these names. I'd scroll through this list.
Just search for these names in your own LinkBoost
when you're doing this
and you should be able to find the biggest pods.
So you have the Growth Hacking Pod.
Digital Marketing, Startups & Fintechs,
Saas Growth Hacks,
LinkedIn Hackers
Experts, From Leads to Profit, Growth Hackers USA, B2B
USA,
Digital Marketing Strategies - India, Saas
Growth Hacking,
B2B Leads and prospects, LinkedIn Australia,
Mutual Growth,
People over with 1000 followers, 10,000 followers
Indian pod,  Kuware's Digital Marketing,
Innovation, Travel community, Coaches and Consultant,
People with SSI score,
LinkedIn -  UK,
Professionals in the USA only,
B2B Leads,
SEO and Digital Marketing,
Leadership Content,
Startup Mentorship USA, Digital Marketing
Top Influencers,
United States,
Germany, United Kingdom,
Canada in B2B Industry, USA Growth Post,
um. Then we have High Tech US linkedIn only,
Experts, coaches and mentors,
Elite Professionals.
Let's forget big go on Saas Growth and marketing,
Auto likes and comments,
Marketing and Advertising, Best LinkedIn Network Brazil,
Finance, Startup, German B2B Digital.
I'm not sure how he pronounce that,
but yeah we have
the biggest pods in here,
so just join these pods and you're done.
And the next step after this
after you've joined
all these pods is to wait for a day
now. The reason we wait is
to give time
for the admins to approve
our request to join these pods.
That's all you need to do, and once you've done that'
all you need to do is come back.
The posts page in here and this is where you
schedule posts,
so all you need to do is first click on
new posts
so you just click on new posts in here
and it will open up a new page
which is where you can add the link
to your LinkedIn post.
So every day after you set a reminder
based on when you're publishing
See 8 AM
on the 10, all I need to do
is
set a reminder
come in here
go to my LinkedIn account,
get the link to the post that was just published,
so I'm going to take copy link to that post
and I'm going to come to
LinkBoosts.
I'm going to
copy paste that URLto the post in here
and then all I need to do is select the pods. Now
if you want unique engagement
every single time you post,
you can choose to select
some specific pods in here,
but if you want to
maximize the engagement on every single post,
all you need to do is
auto select the pods and
LinkBoost will automatically select
the biggest pods
that you can publish from
automatically.
So the next step after that is to add the comments
and again in here we are going to use ChatGPT
So now we're going to go to ChatGPT and create
some personalized comments for this post
and we're going to add them in here.
So let me show you how to do that in ChatGPT.
The first step is creating the prompt
or adding the prompt
for creating the personalized comments,
so this is the prompt in ChatGPT.
I need to click on New chat
and post this
prompt and the postcopy
out right? So the prompt goes like the
Prepare 30 comments for this LinkedIn post by
add your name over here,
so whatever your name is added over here,
I'm here as some rules
I'd like you. To follow the comment should 33
questions, some funny comments,
some positives, some negative and neutral comments.
The comment should be unique
and the length should vary in
between 5 words and 15 modes.
Add emojis in 5 comments and only in 5 comments
here are supposed
and then from LinkedIn you can simply copy paste the
post copy
that you want to create the comments for, so
all I need to do is just
copy paste this and paste it over here and
enter hit. Enter to charge a video with this prompt
and ChatGPT will create the comments for you
see how simple is that
and some of them will
also have questions so that you can respond
with your reply to the comments
so it makes it very easy.
So all you need to do now is just copy,
paste all the comments from here,
go to linkboost and paste them in here like this.
That's it. And now you can go back
and now we need to select the
type of engagement that we need.
I really select normal engagement,
set the random interval between 10 to 20 seconds.
That is the best way
and now you need to decide
the type of audience that you want to engage
on your content.
Ideally, what I would recommend is
selecting Custom Audience
and click on, Unselect All, click on Unselect All
and select type of selection and select locations
from where you want your
Engagement to come in
when you click on any of these locations.
For example, I am selecting Canada,
which is the location that we want.
Engagement from.
Linkboost will automatically show
the number of people
among all the users that will engage.
So 61 users from
all the pods, the members
that we're a part of that you selected over here
are from Canada
and now
we can go ahead and select additional countries.
I can select Finland, France,
Germany, like which all countries that I feel the
engagement will be irrelevant from
and
whatever you
get is the total number of users that will engage
on my content so that's about
1482 users
could engage on my content.
So after I've selected this
I can go ahead and
click on Create new post and Link
Boost will start engaging
on the post and start getting you likes and
comments on the post.
So that's it,
and this is the activity that you should be doing
Ideally every day after you see the reminder
that you posted online you can come in here.
Copy paste the link to the post.
Basically we hear
auto select pods are individually select pods
if you want unique engagement on every single post
you do so you can select this pod for one day,
this pod for the next day,
this pod for the
3rd day and so on.
I select these 2 pods for one day,
these 2 pods for the
second day and so on
but you need to make sure that the number of users
that will be engaging on your content
are atleast a thousand,
otherwise you will not get a lot of engagement.
So make sure this number is at least a thousand
and you are good to go
use linkboost to promote all your content,
get likes and comments automatically,
and that sums up
our video
on how to use
Taplio, ChatGPT
and LinkBoost to automatically or quickly
create content.
So research on content
find good content topics
and content pieces that are performed well in the past.
How to realize them using ChatGPT very quickly
schedule them in Ta
plio so that they go like automatically
and schedule 15
days worth of content,
so that's 15 working days and 15 posts of content
and then set their reminder
in your calendar
or on your phone to
remind you to engage
and promote the content using LinkBoost.
This cannot be done automatically,
so if you want to promote it actively
at this centerpiece,
you will have to do it manually.
Using LinkBoost.
We discuss how to set up LinkBoost
and then promote each piece of content using LinkBoost
and create AI generated comments, and then
the next step after this is obviously
to go to the post,
go to the linked post
and go to the comment section and respond to each
other comments
that have come in,
which can. Either be
a pod comment
or it can be
a non LinkBoost non pod comment.
It can be a genuine comment,
so
either way you spend at least 30 minutes
after you publish the post.
After you promote the post to come in here and respond
to
each of the comments and replay to each of the comments
but that sums up our process
and
the kick starting
your
LinkedIn content module.