So in this module, we're going to build the
foundation to your own content strategy using
some hardcore analysis of what your competitors
are doing, what you are doing, and then identify
the gaps in your existing content strategy.
When you get started with your own content
marketing on LinkedIn, it's important to analyze
and get an understanding of what's working
in your industry and then use the insights from
this analysis to craft your own strategy and
your own content formats. We'll show you how
to do this in this module in a step-by-step
manner. We will first do a thorough competitor
analysis to identify competitors and analyze
what they are doing with content on different
social media platforms, including LinkedIn
and what they are doing on their website. And
we will document them in a sheet called the
competitor analysis sheet and also segment them
into top of the funnel, middle of the funnel
and bottom of the funnel content. Now let me
explain top of the funnel or TOFU a little
bit, middle of the funnel or bottom of the funnel
content before we move on. Top of the funnel
content includes content that is used to generate
awareness or to provide a service or a product.
Middle of the funnel content is content that
is used to convey expertise and thought leadership
with content that is useful for our market audience.
And bottom of the funnel content is content
that is used to build trust and position our
productive services at the right chance for
the pain points they are facing. A good content
marketing strategy will include Tofu, MoFu
as well as BoFu content formats, which is why
we are analyzing them in-depth and documenting
them in the Competitor Analysis Sheet. And that's
just the first step. The next step is analyzing
and documenting our existing content in the
existing content analysis sheet so that we
do exactly what we're doing right now and how
our content strategy looks like. And once we're
done with both of these steps and then identify
the gaps in our existing content process by
looking at what we're doing and what else we
need to do because we now know and understand
what our competitors are doing as well. And
finally, We'll also cover the content ideation
sheet, which is where you'll be documenting
a bunch of ideas about your own experiences,
as well as some industry theme points and topics
that are interesting to your target audience.
We have two main goals with this module. The
first goal is to analyze exactly what type
of content works in our niche or industry so
that we can gain inspiration from it. And the
second goal is to document it in a structured
manner in the content analysis sheets. so that
it can be a valuable resource of inspiration
and ideas for your content team later on. This
module will take a total of 15 to 20 hours to
complete and will involve multiple team members
and you can find the different steps to completing
this module in the progress tracking sheet
as well. It is very important that you get this
module completed within a span of what are
two days and the max three days because it will
help you do it way more faster, especially
the content gap analysis step. So set aside
some good time over a span of two days, three
days and just get it done. You can also choose
to do it slowly, but doing it quickly within
2-3 days will help you get it done faster and
save you a couple of thousand work. But by
the end of this module, you will be all set
to design your own viral content marketing
strategy that is thought out and data-bound.
That's it for the overview. See you in the
next video.