In this video, we are going to cover advanced
growth tactics to growth hack your LinkedIn
content and overall LinkedIn strategy. This
module will not just help you to take your
content marketing to the next level, but it
will also help you improve a lot of the existing
processes in your content marketing strategy
so that they are more efficient and resource
driven. We will first deep dive into LinkedIn
content promotion and how it can be done with
content engagement pods. And we'll discuss both
manual pods and automated pods and how you
can use them to generate quick engagement for
your content on demand and how quick engagement
will help you promote your content and generate
way more reach than you're getting right now.
Then we'll discuss the LinkedIn SSI score, the
social selling index score and its importance
and its impact on all your LinkedIn efforts,
especially your content marketing efforts,
and then discuss the different components of
the SSI score and how you can increase it using
specific actions and steps. We then deep dive
into how you can create a reporting system,
which is one of the most important lessons in
this module because documenting the results
of everything you do in one place so that we
can see what is working and what isn't periodically,
ideally on a weekly basis and forming inferences
and learning from that is essential to understand
what's working and what's not working, but not
just in content marketing, but your entire
LinkedIn marketing strategy. This module will
take around 2 hours to fully watch and learn,
but most of the tasks we discussed in this module
are recurring tasks that you need to do on
a periodic basis, so that will be taking around
2 hours every week to complete. And the core
goal of this module is to fast track your growth
on LinkedIn and set you on a good future path.
That's it for the overview, see you in the next
video.