So in this video, we're going to be discussing
Q&A videos. So Q&A videos are another one of
my favorite content formats. And as the name
sounds, somebody asks you a question, and you
answer that in a video. So that's what you call
a Q&A video. So these videos can either be
recorded in, say, your workspace, or it can
be recorded in, say, a meeting setup of somebody
asking you a question, then you answering them,
and both of you being in the video, or it can
be like on a webinar, or it can be at a conference
or event that you're speaking at, and somebody
from the audience is asking your question, and
you're answering it, and you record that and
publish that as a video. All of these are Q&A
videos, but let's first take a look at the
entire process of creating Q&A videos first.
So let me move back to ClickUp and walk you
through the content management process for a
Q&A video. So this is the template card for
Q&A videos. So obviously the process starts
with you adding an idea. You need to create
duplicate this card, update the status to outlines,
and then add the idea in the outlines and beef
out the outline slowly. But let's take a look
at how the process looks. So the process is
almost exactly the same like an experiential
video, experiential story video. So the content
manager adds an outline or the copywriter adds
an outline. And then the copywriter, idea of
the Q&A video is approved. These need to be
discussed on the content edition calls with
the executive, and the executive will answer
what is the answer to that question. So whatever
question it is, that is the outline, and the
executive will give you information on what
their answer is, and you can document that in the
outline and then start creating the content in the
draft stage. So in this stage, you go ahead and create
a bunch of elements. So the elements will include
the video script for the Q&A video, the post copy,
the thumbnail caption. So the thumbnail caption
in most cases for Q&A videos will be the question
presented in an attention-grabbing format. So
let's take a look at the example so that you
understand how this is done. So this has a
thumbnail image. So the thumbnail image of this
video includes a question like "What's the most underrated
skill to succeed in your career?" and a question
mark. So you can include a thumbnail which
includes the question. and then the video editor
can go ahead and create a thumbnail for you.
But then we move on to the remaining steps, and
after you update the statuses of the subtask
and the parent task, it moves on to the content
manager's queue who reviews all these elements,
proceeds to the executive's approval queue who
reviews all these elements, may suggest feedback,
in which case it moves back in the process.
But if it's good to go, it moves forward in
the process, which is when the executive will
record the video. and send it to the video
editor who will edit the video, create the thumbnail
image and so on, and send it to the content
manager again for approval. And if it's good
to go, it will go to the executive queue again
for approval. And then finally, it will get
to be ready to be posted stage for the user
profile and the company page. Q&A videos ideally
can be posted on both the user profile as well
as the company page. So that is the process
for ClickUp. And now let's take a quick look
at how to ideate Q&A videos. So the most interesting
thing about Q&A videos is there's tons of ways
in which you can come up with ideas. But one
of the best ways to come up with good questions
is a tool called answerthepublic.com. So that's
answerthepublic.com without spaces. So you
can enter any keyword in here. So, for example,
in my case, I've entered "construction," and they
will give you like, I don't know, it's like
1000 questions for different topics and questions
that are being asked on Google and different
social media platforms. This is one of the
only sources that you need for that specific
topic. You can even click on any of these questions
and it'll pull up a Google search, and you can
collect more information about that specific
question and add more ideas. But if you zoom
in here, you can see that all of these are
different topics. So, can construction be done
on Sunday? Can construction adhesive be removed?
Can construction cause allergies? Can construction
make you sick? So, when construction starts?
So when is construction holiday 2022? So all
of these are different topics about different
areas in the construction industry as a whole.
If you find that these questions are not relevant,
you can refine the topic a little bit more.
So you can say something like "construction
project tracking" or "construction risk management"
or "construction tracking construction vendors,"
so on. So based on whatever topics, keywords
you want to enter, you'll get different, different
questions about this. So this is one way to
come up with really good questions. The other
way is to use Reddit. So all I need to do is
enter a keyword and search Reddit, and Google
will pull up different threads in Reddit that
have both the questions and answers. So a lot
of users will come in and if you ask a question,
they will drop comments with the answers as
well. and some will ask follow-up questions
in here. So this is an excellent way to find
really good.
ideas for Q&A videos, and another example is
Quora. So Quora is another Q&A website. You
can search for like Quora construction risks
and here you go, a thread about hazards in
construction work, major risks involved in construction,
in working in construction site. What is the
risk management in construction projects? So
you can go through these, look for like good
answers and you can find relevant questions
from Quora as well very quickly. So that sums
up the ideation process involved, how to find
ideas and document them in the ClickUp task.
So you need to add them in outlines and proceed
with the rest of the process and ask them to
the executives on the content ideation calls.
But how do you go about creating the post?
Now, we don't have outlines for Q&A videos for
the simple reason that questions and answers,
it's a very simple format. All you need are
hooks for creating a Q&A video. Questions and
answers can be formatted in different ways.
So take a look at the lesson on the elements
that make good LinkedIn copy, where we explain
what are the different types of formatting
that you should use. So that is a helpful lesson
for optimizing Q&A videos, but specifically
for like the content for Q&A videos, you don't
really need outlines. You can just ask the
question in the hook in an interesting fashion.
So go through the hooks, make sure the hook
is really good. And then after that, you can
just add the answer in the post copy in an
interesting fashion in the video script, present
the answer in an interesting fashion and just
make sure that the formatting in the post
copy,
the paragraph formatting or the skimmable text
content formatting is in the correct fashion.
We have a separate lesson about how to create
content formats, content in different formats,
which is one of the primary lessons in this
section. So just take a look at that video.
You'll understand how to format it well. But
Q&A videos are one of the easiest content formats
to create for the simple reason that when you
can find questions and answers everywhere, you
just need to answer them and get the videos
recorded and publish them. So that's it for
Q&A videos. See you in the next video.