So in this video, we're going to talk about
resource giveaways. Now, resource giveaways
are when you give away a free resource, which
can be a tool, it can be a template, it can
be a free guide, or it can be like a niche report
that is valuable to your target audience. Say
for example, for Sachin, who is in the crypto
space and the crypto regulation space, the
giveaway he's offering is that of an ultimate
guide to crypto asset regulations in the UK,
which is very important document about what
laws to follow. for crypto companies and what
he's done is he's offered a poll in which he's
asked them if they're interested in this resource,
just drop a post in the comments below and I'll
send it to you. So what you do in resource
giveaways is you don't give them a link to the
post right away. You will tell them that they
can get access to the resource, this valuable
resource or tool. If they drop a comment below
the post or if you're doing it as a poll, You
can ask the question if they're interested
in the poll or a related question and they can
click yes or no. And if they click on yes,
to everyone who voted on yes, you can send the
resource by messaging them on like that. To
everyone who votes on a normal post, you can
message them, you can connect to them and message
them and send them the resource. Now let's first
take a look at how the content management process
works like as usual for resource giveaways.
And then we'll get into the ideation and creation.
of resource giveaways. So this is the ClickUp
template task for resource giveaways. As usual,
you first create a duplicate of this and then
you start working creating on resource giveaways.
You add an outline, discuss the outline, get
it approved by the executive on the content
ideation calls and then you beef out the outline,
add some property deals and source links and
then you get started with the creation process.
The process for resource giveaways is very
simple. We are assuming that we are working
on existing resource giveaways that we've already
created. If the resources need to be created
by yourself, that is a separate process, you
need to handle that separately. But if the resources
have already been created, this is very simple
process you can follow for it. You first add
the outline, then you work on the drafts. You
create a draft for the post copy for the resource
or for the post copy for the poll that you're
publishing with the questions and stuff. then
the content manager reviews and approves it.
Then it goes to the executive approval queue.
And once the executive approves it on the content
ideation calls, it can be published on the user
profile and the company page. A very simple
process. When you add the outline to the resource,
a resource giveaway post, make sure you add
like talk about what the resource is, what pain
points it solves, what are the insights in
the resource? Like how does it solve the pain
points? What are the insights in the resource
that you're sharing and what messages to be
conveyed? And you also need to add the direct
link to the resource file uploaded in Drive.
This is important in the respective session,
the description. So when we add resource URL,
it needs to be uploaded in Drive and you need
to add the shared, anyone with the link can
access view link in here. All right. But all
of these steps as usual have been mentioned
and explained step by step for each subtask
in here. So you just need to follow the subtask
process exactly as it is. Now let's talk about
ideation of resource giveaways. So again, the
most interesting thing about resource giveaways
is that it can easily be found using Google
search itself. So all you need to do is enter
a relevant keyword. So in our case, it can be
construction, project management. So I'm just
gonna use that to explain this. Construction
project management is the keyword I'm gonna
use and templates. So if I Google for this,
boom. Excel template. So, just from a few of
these I am going to get like, I do not know,
20 different resources that I can use. So,
take a look at this. This is a construction
timeline template for Excel. That is one resource,
construction budget template for Excel. So,
you could create the resource giveaway post
where you discuss this with the executive and
the executive will give some tips on personalizing
this template or on how to use this template
and why is this important. and you could offer
it with a guide that you write yourself for
how to create construction budget estimates.
So, each of these could be a potential resource.
Now, you should be making sure that you discuss
this with the executive so that they confirm
that this is a valuable resource for your target
audience. But as long as that is done, you can
easily find resources online. So, I just use
one type of search which is keyword plus templates.
In addition to this, you can also search for.
keyword guide PDFs. I could use construction
project management guide PDF and there you
go. I'll find a bunch of PDF guides from other
publishers. I can give social attribution in
the post that's completely fine, but construction
project management PDFs from the Pennsylvania
State University, construction project management
templates from Academy Research Guide, there's
template.net, there's Coursera guides. I don't
think that's downloadable, but that's fine.
Introduction to construction project management.
So, this must be from some publication that
we can download for free from script.
Upload a bit, but we can even tag these sources
so that it is easier. And like you should be
collecting like every time you look for resource
giveaway ideas, you should be collecting a
bunch of resources like assume like 10 to 20
content ideas and then reviewing them with
the executive. on the content ideation call so
that they can choose the best ones and then
you can start working on the best ones. So don't
go about like creating like one, finding an
idea for one resource giveaway, find 10 or 20
of them. So you have your, you, you go about
it in one single step and you can dump all of
them into one single resource giveaway template
task so that it's, it's reviewed on the content
ideation calls. Now this is how you go about
ideating them. Here are some additional keywords.
So one keyword is Keyword in quotes plus templates.
Another keyword is keyword in quotes plus guide
PDF. Another search operator is keyword in
quotes plus free tool. So you can also offer
free tools that are available online and explain
how to use those tools. Another one is keyword
plus resources. Now in addition to these, the
easiest way to go about creating resource giveaways
is taking a look at the gap identification
sheet. in the content analysis spreadsheet.
So in the content analysis spreadsheet, you
have a gap identification worksheet. And in
here you can find.
eBooks, white papers about different stuff that
they've created internally about the companies
that the companies have created internally that
helps them that helps the target audience like
learn about a particular topic. So ideally don't
publish ones from your competitors. Some of
these will be from competitors, but if you've
created stuff internally, you can find it from
the gap identification sheet itself or from
the existing content analysis sheet. and you
just come down and look at white papers and
ebooks. We have not created anything like this
client, this case study that we are reviewing,
TraceCost hasn't created anything. So I cannot
show anything here, but in many cases you may
have internal white papers and ebooks that
you can repurpose as a resource giveaway post
on LinkedIn. And now let's quickly jump into
how to go about actually creating a resource
giveaway. So just like usual, we have outlines.
We have outlines for resource giveaways. So
we've found very well performing resource giveaways.
And we've reverse engineered each line to give
you an outline. And all you need to do is take
a look at each of these lines one by one. Choose
a content topic that is apt to this outline
or vice versa. Choose an outline that is apt
for your content topic. We have about five
outlines in here and just start filling them
out. Some of these are my own that have performed
very well and have generated a lot of leads
for us. And that is it. very easy PC process.
The outlines are pretty self-explanatory, plus
we have information in here on how to use the
outlines as well. But that sums up the resource
giveaway format. If you have any questions
at all, feel free to drop them in the WhatsApp
community and ask us on group coaching calls
because this is an excellent content format
for lead generation, actually generating leads
from just from publishing content. And this
post format is engineered for traction. So,
When most people vote on the polls to get access
to our resource or when most people drop a
comment to get access to our resource, more
of their network will see it. So that induces
an organic virality factor in the post and the
promotion of this post. So it's really good
for generating leads because only if the people
are interested in that specific resource, that
niche resource will be commenting on the post
or voting on the polls. So that's it for this
format. See you in the next video.