So, the next content format we are going to be
discussing are slide posts. Now, slide posts
are one of the best performing content formats
on LinkedIn right now. And it's basically just
a PDF post that is designed that you design
that has a bunch of text and images in it.
And you talk about a story, it can be a guide,
step-by-step guide. It can be a listicle of
like seven top construction projects or something
like that. This one is a story about how the
Brooklyn Bridge was created. by a woman who
was the wife of the original chief engineer.
So it's an interesting story in construction,
which is why we chose the story, and we created
a slide post about this. Now let's first take
a look at the content management process in
ClickUp for the slide post. And then let's talk
about how to ideate and create these posts.
So this is the ClickUp template task for slide
posts. And just as usual, we have everything
detailed for you in sub-tasks, as well as checklists
for each subtask. So for outlines, we have
a checklist for outlines. For the graphs, we
have a checklist for outlines explaining exactly
what to do step by step for creating slide posts.
Now, the process is very similar to that of
experiences stories, but the only difference
is that here, there is an awaiting media file
designing step where the carousel or the slides
are designed by a designer or personalized
by a designer and reviewed by the content manager
and reviewed by the executive. So one thing
here is that the drafts are first created by
the copywriter and then the content manager
reviews the draft. So the design is only worked
on after the content manager and the executive
review the slide post content, the text content,
and then it is sent to the designer for design
because the design works takes quite a bit of
time. So we're making sure that everything
is good to go before it moves to the design
queue. And once it's designed, it is sent back
to the content manager first for review. And
if the content is good to go, they can pass
it to the next stage, which is a need executive
approval stage, or if design edits are needed,
or the grammatical issues in the design or something
like that, they can assign it back to the graphic
designer and they will make the edits in the
design. and then send it to the content manager
again for review. And then he can pass it on
to the executive. And if the executive likes
it, it moves to the ready to be posted queue
and the ready to be company page queue. So
just as usual, individual steps
are covered in here. So it's easy PCA to just
go about it and complete each of the tasks
assigned to each of you for each of these sub
tasks. Now let's talk a bit about the ideation
process for slide shares. So most of the slide
posts, slide shares, slide posts will be discussed.
The ideas for the slide posts will be discussed
on the content ideation course. But if you
want to come up with ideas, one of the best
places to do this is a website called slideshare.com.
Now what slideshare is, is it's a directory
of presentation files that have been uploaded
online. So I was looking for construction and
construction project management. All I would
need to do is come in here, search for construction
project management. And okay, there's nothing
for construction project management. Okay, there
is stuff for construction project management.
And then all I need to do is myths of construction
project management. Let's take a look at this
one. So if I take a look at this one, there
will be really good expert content already
created for you about the myths of construction
project management. So this is something you
can take and you can add a link to this or you
can also download the slide post to your desktop
and you can upload it to the slide post template
card, sorry, the slide post card that you've
created. In the outline section, you can attach
the file over there like this. Click on plus,
you go down and you click on attachment and
you can upload the file over there so that
it can be reviewed on the content edition called
and the executive can share their own suggestions
and approvals. Ideally, only get started with
the slide content in the post copy after the
executive has approved the idea for the slide
content. In addition to these, you can also
use additional ways to search for slide posts.
So you can use guides, you can create guides.
So guide to construction risk management. So
I'm just thinking of different keywords that
I can use. So ultimate guide to construction
risk management, complete guide to construction
risk management. So this should have steps in
it or sections in it. So that could be like
one slide that I create for this specific topic.
five steps to manage construction press. So
these are five slides and I could create like
one slide for each of these with an introduction
slide and a final call to action sites to follow
us and so on. So this is how you go about IDing.
It's very easy to ID a slide post because you
can use it for listicles, you can use it for
tutorials, you can use it for guides. And guides
and tutorials are the best performing type of
content format. You can even cover stories
in them because they're very easy to consume
on both mobile as well as desktop. Now, how
do you get started with creating your slide
posts? So just like Experiential Stories, we
have outlines for slide posts as well. So you
can just come to the IG content marketing modules
workbook. And in there, we have outlines for
slide posts. So you just search for slide post
outlines. And you'll find these five outlines
for slide posts that have already performed
well. So you've taken a slide post that has
went viral. And we've reverse engineered it
to give you an outline. So Just take any one
of these outlines that is apt for your idea
and just go through each of these lines and
create a line based on each of these lines.
And you'll be good to go. Just as usual, after
you're done with the slide post creation for
both the content for these slides as well as
the content for the post copies, you should
be going back to hooks because hooks are very
important for making sure your post perform
well. Come back to hooks and optimize the first
two to three lines of both the slide posts.
as well as the post copy. You can choose any
of these hooks that's good for the post and
optimize it. That brings us to our end of the
slide post video. I'll see you in the next one.