LinkedIn gives you a score called the SSI score
based on a lot of things we do on LinkedIn.
It is a score between 1 and 100 that LinkedIn
gives you based on how active you are with
your social selling efforts. Here, they aren't
talking about the traditional conversion rates
and attractiveness in making quotas. Rather,
the LinkedIn SSI score is focused on network
building and engagement factors on the LinkedIn
platform. The consistency that you have been
posting, the amount of engagement on your posts
the replies or the comments on your posts, your
comments on other posts, all these elements
and more affect the SSI score. The LinkedIn
group campus has already been designed to look
at all these different elements so that your
SSI score increases over time. But this video
is so that you understand the factors behind
the SSI score. Now why is the SSI score so important?
Actual statistical studies and research shows
that people with higher SSI scores generate
more organic reach for their course and rank
higher in LinkedIn search as well. If you take
care of these elements and put in the work,
LinkedIn will award you a higher SSI score,
and in turn, you will be able to generate more
reach on your content and more search appearances
in LinkedIn search. You can check your SSI
score at LinkedIn.com slash sales slash SSI.
I'll add a link to it in the description. To
see how you perform and what you present, and
what your present SSI score is, you should
be aiming for a score of about 70 or more But
in this video, we're going to explain the different
elements that make up the SSI score and how
you can increase it. Now there are four components
that make up the SSI score. So the first one
is establishing your professional brand. The second
one is finding the right people and then engaging
with insights and then building relationships.
What I'm going to do is I'm going to walk you
through each of these and then I'm going to
explain what you can do to increase the each
of these individual scores. so that your overall
SSI score goes above 70. 75 is really good,
but you should be aiming for at least 70. All
right, now establishing your professional brand
is all based on the completeness of your LinkedIn
profile, including the endorsements you've received
and the articles you publish and the number
of followers resulting from your articles. It's
not just things you can do, it's also matters
like how good your content is and how many followers
you generate from it. But the things that you
can do make sure that you are doing efficiently.
So the first thing that you need to do is optimizing
your LinkedIn profile. We do cover this already
in the program at an early stage, but one thing
you can do in addition to this is reaching out
to a bunch of your contacts and generating
endorsements for your skills and that you've
listed on your profile. So the best way to
go about generating endorsements is actually
very simple. It is based on the law of reciprocity.
So if you endorse a bunch of your contacts,
say these could be people you know, these need
not be people you know, but if you endorse the
skills of a bunch of your contacts, if a security
connection is on LinkedIn, chances are they
will reciprocate and do the same thing for
you. So all you need to do here is set aside
a task, like assign a task to your team to...
endorse 10 contacts, 10 connections every day
and then send them a message asking, okay,
I endorse you for the skills, I was wondering
if you set aside a few minutes to endorse a
bunch of my skills, I'm trying to increase my
SSI score. So that's all you need to do to
generate some reciprocal engagement, some reciprocal
endorsement you could say on your profile,
on the skills on your profile and that will affect
your SSI score. The next thing you need to focus on
is publishing articles on LinkedIn So this is not specifically
newsletter posts. These are articles on LinkedIn,
which is a content format on LinkedIn. You can
publish normal posts or you can publish articles.
So publishing a bunch of articles can be used
to generate and generating some followers will
it from it will help you establish a professional
profile. It will increase the This confidence
score which will increase your overall score.
Now, how do you go about doing this? The only
thing you need to do is take a look at your
website the blog post on your website and try
to repurpose them actively to your profile.
So this is a recommendation that you can give
to the content manager or to the content team.
Who can go ahead and just repurpose the exact
same content, just copy paste the content. You
could add a source link at the end of the article,
linking to the original blog post on the website.
But that's all you need to do, to quickly take
advantage of this one specific element. Now
let's move on to the next one. The next one
is finding the right people. Now finding the
right people. is all about creating people
searches on a regular basis using advanced filters
and sales navigator. So if you do people searches,
so people searches mean lead searches on LinkedIn
on a regular basis and then use advanced filters
that will help you improve this goal to some
extent. If you're running outreach, you're
doing this actively. So that's not a huge step
that you have to take. The second one is saving
your searches and going through them weekly
to look for new relevant profiles. Again, Expandly
takes care of this. In fact, Expandi takes
care of this as well. But the most important
element that you need to pay attention to for
this specific component is getting a high acceptance
rate on sent invitations. So when we are sending
connection requests and connection invitations,
we need to get a high acceptance rate on that.
Now, how do you go about doing this? This is
about A-B testing. multiple campaigns. This
is something that we already recommend for
you in the operation modules. But if you do
that actively and get your acceptance rates
to a recommended percentage of 40%, then that
alone will increase this specific component
of the SSI score, which will get you an overall
increase in the SSI score, the overall SSI
score. I'm going to move on to the next one.
The next one is engaging with insights. Engaging
with insights is a bit difficult to grow. because
it depends on getting engagement on your own
posts, like likes, comments, and shares in the
feed. So the engagement needs to come from
the feed. So the pod engagement doesn't really
count for this. We've tested this out already.
It doesn't count towards this, getting the higher
SSI score for this component. But if you're
getting organic engagement on your content,
which means you need to be publishing really
good, valuable content, then you will get more
engagement on your posts, and that will eventually
help you do this. The pod engagement to an extent
will help you get like it in front of more
users, which could get you more organic engagement.
But in the end, it depends on how good your
content is. That's why you need to get really
good engagement for your content. The second
thing is the content that you post in groups.
So if you get if you are part of a bunch of
communities, you need to be posting engagement
of those communities. And if you generate engagement
of those communities, that is good. Now, this
is one of the reasons, in fact, why we suggest.
joining engagement groups on LinkedIn, which
we covered earlier in this module. And I asked
you to join a bunch of engagement groups on
LinkedIn and actively try to engage with the
content in there. So when you post something
and you get engagement on that content or that
comment, what's going to happen is it's going
to affect your SSI score as well. The next
thing is the acceptance rate on the emails sent
from sales navigator. Now, this is not something
that we usually do because the emails that we
sent by expandi are open emails. So that's
a different type of in-mail, but the acceptance
rate on the in-mail sent from your sales navigator.
So you get like in between 30 and 50 credits
every month when you have a sales navigator
license that you can use to reach out to people
on a priority basis. So you don't need to send
them a connection request at the start, you
can just send them an in-mail. But this is
a signal that if you get like a higher acceptance
rates on in-mails that you send from sales
navigator. you will get an increase in this
engage with inside score. Now the next thing
is activities on Smart Links. So this is a very
crucial feature because without Sales Navigator,
the usage of Smart Links, it is extremely difficult
to get a sweet score of about 80 for this component.
But Smart Links will help you usage of Smart
Links, which is kind of like a feature in Sales
Navigator, where you can upload like a presentation.
or a deck that you want to present to people.
And it allows you to track the number of users
who are viewing that content. So it's mostly
for business presentations and sales processes.
But using Smart Links actively, say if you
have a pitch deck or a case study deck that
you want to send to one of your users, upload
them to Smart Links and send them a Smart Link
rather than just sending them a link to a Canva
file or a Google Slides or a Microsoft Presentations
file link. So instead of that, use a smart
link and send them a smart link and that should
help you increase the score as well. Finally,
we want the last one, which is building relationships.
Now, for building relationships are all about
using the daily, all actions that you take towards
your connection. So it can be starting from
sending them connection requests, sending them
follow messages, which is already taken care
of by expandi, liking their content, commenting
their contents, all of these things. are taken
into account. So this is something that is covered
already in our process, so that you don't have
to fret about that. And the other thing you
need to focus on is engaging with posts from
your network in the field. So you need to actively
look at posts from your network in the LinkedIn
feed. You need to be engaging, dropping a couple
of times every day, and this will help you
increase the build relationships score. The
third one is responding and checking your messages,
invites, and notifications. Now, this is something
most of us ignore. Because even though we look
at messages, because they can be messages from
leads and we look at inbound connection requests,
many of us just leave the notifications tab
around. Don't pay any attention to notifications
tab. In fact, checking the notifications tab,
clicking on the links in there are all important
to get a high score on this. Now, one thing
that we've noticed for the build relationships
score is that if you use the LinkedIn mobile
app actively, you can keep the score. And what
I will do is, it's a signal to LinkedIn that
you are a more engaged user because you're
using the mobile app and that will help you
increase the score a little bit. Now that sums
up the different components of the LinkedIn
SSI score. You don't need to think too much
about it. We do cover a lot of these things,
but after you watch this video, you make a
few notes on what needs to be done. And you
could. Give some recommendations to the content
manager or to the content team on the basis
of what you've learned from this video. If
you'd like to take any initial steps to increase
your SSI score even higher. That's it for this
video, we'll see you in the next video.