So, I'm gonna walk you through a video right now.
Let's just click play.
You see?
LinkedIn works.
Differently from most other marketing channels.
Whenever a user.
Sees a message from you in their inbox.
Or a post from you in their feed.
The first thing that they do is check out your profile.
It's only after they check out your profile do they make that.
So, I'm gonna skip it.
To the best office rental spaces in New York.
Or like in my case.
I help B2B brands grow their business on LinkedIn.
The work experience listing was.
Simply create a company page on.
Leading that you can use.
Or simply.
So.
This is what you call a Tips and tricks video.
Now, Tips and tricks videos are all about.
Tips and tricks that you explain in a video format.
So, this can be short videos or it can be long videos.
But the idea is to make it really valuable for them.
So, not just a generic video that.
Um, shares and and uh.
A process or a tutorial that everybody.
Knows that everybody in the industry knows.
It has to be uh, it has to include special hacks or.
A special processes that not many people are aware of.
Or a specific tutorial.
Or process that you use internally.
Or that you've developed internally.
That would be valuable for your target audience.
So, it may not be exactly like specific to.
Your core niche and the core industry that you're in.
It can also. Be about general business processes.
That.
Could be interesting to your target audience.
Now, Tips and Tricks.
Um, follow the exact same content format similar to.
Um.
Experiential stories.
So, you can find the content format in the content board.
Um.
They follow the exact same process um for experiential.
Story videos um where.
The copywriter creates a script for the video.
And the Content Manager approves it.
And then goes to Executive.
Then the Executive.
Records the video in bits according to the script.
And then the media file is created.
By the video editor from the recording.
And then it goes through the Content Manager approval.
Executive approval and finally it gets published. So.
Not many changes over there.
The only difference in Tips and Tricks videos is the key.
Topic of the post.
And these topics can't be found online.
So all of these.
Topics need to be discussed on the content ideation call.
Call.
So, you need to give the executive the copyrighters.
And the content managers.
Need to give the executive an idea on exactly.
What the tips and tricks video format is.
And almost every single executive you talk to.
Will have a very good idea on.
Exactly like what tricks and tips of the trade.
Can they talk about. They can create a video about.
So these are special hacks or.
Special secret sauce elements in their process.
That they use that had them a lot in their business.
So we're just sharing that and sharing value openly.
To our audience using these videos.
That's it. This is just a quick video.
We're gonna move on to the next part in format.
Which is an interesting one called Engagement baits.