So, this is the viral tweets template in ClickUp.
Viral tweets are all about taking screenshots.
Or images of viral tweets and then adding a
post copy, and then repurposing them very quickly.
But the process starts with the content manager
creating an outline for this. So they make
a copy of the template card. They add a name
to it, so they create a copy of the template.
Card and change the parent task status to outline,
so that's this outlines, and then they add
the post topic in the task title, so that's
over here, they add the post topic, so that's
whatever the topic of the post is, section so
that's in here they need to add this description.
In here. And then they also need to convey what
the tweet is. So you add to the tweet what
the context is, what the tweet is about, what
are the insights, what messages to be conveyed.
In the tweet, the source URL of the tweet also
needs to be added in the section so that the
copywriter has a good perspective about what
to write for the post copy and so on, and how
to take the post images. So the next task after
that is you need to assign all the tasks like
usual. So you need to assign the drafts to the
copywriter who will be working on it. So like
this. Select who the other copywriter is. This
to himself, this to the executive will be reviewing.
The content, this to the executive assistants
on the team who will be going ahead and posting.
These.
After he is done with this, he can mark this
task as complete. So he just needs to select
this and mark it as complete. So the only two
sub-statuses for the subtasks are assigned
and complete. So once that is done, he can go
ahead and change the main parent task status
to drafts because the copywriter now needs to
start working on it and since it's already
assigned it will be visible in the editor queue.
And then the process continues with the copywriter.
Creating a post copy and adding three to four
relevant hashtags, rereading the hook of the
post and making sure it's catchy enough, adding
any required first comments, adding the tweet
image in the respective section. So if the tweet
when the tweet URL has been added in the outline
section, he just needs to open that tweet, take
a screenshot of the and then add the image
URL in here in the tweet image. He also needs
to add in the first comments in here just to
be clear. And then after he's doing that, after
he's done with that, he can take a quick grammatical
check of all the post elements, the copy elements,
and then finally move the parent task. So the
parent task needs to be moved to the CM approval
status so that the quarter manager can provide
and approve it or suggest revisions and then
the sub-task that has been assigned to him.
Which is this one, to complete it. So he goes
here and marks it as completed. That's it.
That we have done. Then we move on to the same
approval, So it's this one, which is where
the content manager reviews it and suggests
any changes. Now, in case he has any feedback,
he can comment with the feedback in here, tagging
the copywriter, the CW, and then move it back.
the status of the draft CW task back to assign
so that the drafts so that the copywriter will
come back to it and start working on it again.
So if we move it back to assign, it will be
able to see it in his queue or if it's good
to go, he can mark his task as complete. The
same approval task is complete and move the
main one to the need ex approval status. So
again, it's been outlined over here. You just
need to read through it and execute it. Then
if all the post elements are good to go. We
can mark it to Need EX approval status, the parent
task, and mask status of the same approval revision
subtasks to complete. And that's it. And then
the executive comes in here. And he reviews
the post copy and tweets me, just like the
content manager. He can suggest any revisions,
just like content manager. And if all post
elements are good to go, we can mark the status
of the subtasks completed. Then finally, we
go to the user profile posting. So if you
can't receive posted on the user profile, you
can, they can prepare the first, prepare the
relevant comments using chat GPT, and then
add the generated comments as a comment in here.
And if all the post elements are good to go,
so they need to make sure that they have the
post copy ready, the tweet image needs to be
accessible. So you should open the tweet URL
and see if it's accessible. The hashtags need
to be there in the post copy. So if everything
is done, they can go ahead and publish it on
the ex profile as an image post. So you just
need to publish the post copy and upload the
image. And then after they publish, they need
to come and add the link, the LinkedIn post
URL in here, and that is it. So after that is
done, they can mark this subtask as complete.
Everything is done; we can mark the subtasks
complete and then move on to the next one.
This may not be there in some cases if the content
manager chooses not to publish it on the company
page as well, but if it is there, then they
can go ahead and.
So if it is there, he can follow the exact same
process that you use for the user profile.
In here, he needs to create new comments so
you cannot use the same comments. You've already
done this step, so it's not important that you
do it again. You add the link to Post-URL
after you publish it on the company page, and
you promote the post separately in the pods
with the comments that you generated, and you
mark the ready-to-be-posted company subtask
in here as completed. And... And you're done.
Then you can finally move the parent task to
the posted status. All right. So this is the
posted status. So that's it for the viral tweets
template. See you in the next video.