In this video, we're going to be covering all
the viral influencer content personas, which
includes viral images or memes. Then we have
viral infographics and then we have viral videos.
We'll be covering viral tweets, which is also
included in this content format in this content
persona in a separate video. But in this video,
we're going to be covering all these three
content formats. But before that, let's do a
recap of what the viral influencer persona
is. In the LinkedIn Growth Campus, if you scroll
to the viral content marketing system, there
is a lesson called content strategy and team.
If you expand that, one of the videos was on
how to choose your content persona and select
content formats to build a content calendar.
One of the content personas that we covered
in that lesson is that of the viral influencer
persona. The main goal of the viral influencer
persona is to generate brand awareness as much
as possible using the content that they publish
and generate a large following irrespective
of what the niche is or the industry is or the
topics of the content are. So unlike the niche
expert persona or the viral news guy persona,
they do not focus on publishing content on
a specific topic or a specific set of topics
or a specific industry. It can be anything.
So perfect example of this content persona is
Daniel Abrahams. So, Daniel Abrahams has been
publishing for about four years now on LinkedIn
actively. He publishes about four posts a day.
Almost, all of them are on very, very different
topics. Almos never original content. So, all
of these are content pieces that he borrows
from elsewhere, that he sources from other
platforms, but he borrows them from other platforms
and publish them or repurposes them onto his
profile with or without source attribution.
But this sums up what a viral influencer persona
is. All they focus on is finding posts that
have already performed well online and repurposing
them for their LinkedIn. If you go through this,
look at this. This is a quote by an actor.
This is a conversation between an H.R. and
a boss. This is what we call a viral tweet.
This is again a viral tweet with a different
format. This is... A random meme that he found
online. This is again a tweet again a tweet
This is a video that he found online, which
is about let's take a look for it Which is about
I don't know some sort of play that they're
doing or I believe This is um, yeah, this is
a show being recorded somewhere or an illusion
Um, this is a poll. This is again a meme. So
you see this so all of these constitute content
formats that we can use for the viral influencer
persona. Take a look at Daniel Abraham's profile,
you'll get a better idea on what types of content
can be included and where we can find these
content pieces from. But now, I'm going to walk
you through some sources where you can find
these content formats for each of those content
formats that we just discussed. So, the first
content format we're going to be talking about
are viral images. So, this is an example of
a viral image post. that was published by Daniel.
So take a look at this. This is about the actor,
Hollywood actor, Keanu Reeves and how he's a
kind human being. Definitely sourced online,
founded on other platforms or other social media
platforms and he just whipped up a post copy
for it and he published it and look at the engagement.
Or we could look at infographics, which is
the next content format. So infographics are
data represented visually to prove a point.
You can find infographics on lots and lots of
different sources. Just Google statistics with
any keyword you want and you can find infographics
and images on Google Images. But there's an
image on how when it's too late to change career,
the failure date. So he's proving a point with
that. The next content format I can talk about
are memes. Take a look at how we blocked people
in 1980s and the picture of an old phone. He
found this meme from an online website as well.
This is also from an online website. and we
have viral videos of videos that he founds
from other social media profiles and he just
drops like one line with the social attribution
of where he found the video. So, this is all
there is to it with viral influencer personas.
It is one of the easiest personas you can adopt
if you want to quickly create content and just
focus on building a following. But now we are
going to talk about a couple sources that you
can use to find good posts
the viral influence of us or not. And this includes
the different content formats. The first content
format I want to talk about are memes because
memes performed really well on most social
media platforms. So let's take a look at some
very good sources for memes. So the first source
I want you to talk about is memes.com. So that's
M-E-M-E-S.com. We'll drop a link in the description,
but in memes you can come in here and you can
search for any keyword, for example, construction,
and you can enter like a, get a bunch of. sources
for construction and it's an infinite load.
You can keep scrolling down until you find a
really good meme that you can find is appropriate.
You can also find a like on for this denoting
the social proof of how well that meme could
perform. Find a good meme and use it and just
repurpose it. You can get ChatGPT to create
a quick description. Just tell them, okay, this
is a meme I'd like you to do. This is a meme
on a specific topic.
word post description for this or post copy
for this and just whip it out. It doesn't matter
like what length you add for the post copies
for viral influencer because the main goal
is to find posts that have already performed
well online and that can be the main focus
of the post. So almost all of these have media
with them. There are very few text posts that
we can see for Daniel's profile, for example.
It's all images or videos or tweets or memes
and so on. So don't focus too much on the post
copy. Almost all of them, almost all of this
post have like single line or two line post
copies. That should be more than enough for
a post. So either if you want to create a longer
one, you can use chargegpd or you can just
type out a line for each of the posts. All right,
so meme.com is the first source. This is specifically
for memes. Another one that you can use is supermeme.ai,
that's S-U-P-E-R-M-E-M-E.ai. and this is a
tool that you can use to create memes of your
own. This is an AI meme generator. All you
need to do is type something like, just got
a raise from the boss and click on generate
and it's going to generate some memes for you.
These are an easy way to generate memes. The
tool has a free plan. You can generate about
more than 50 memes every month using that.
That should be more than enough. This is a very
good source for finding and creating memes.
The next source I want to talk about is 9Gag.
So 9Gag is a comedy website. They post funny
content on it. And you can come in here and
you can use the search option to search for
a specific keyword and you can find names, videos,
et cetera, that is really performed well. And
you can also find like the import count on 9Gag.
And 9Gag is mostly like a social media platform,
but it's kind of like a forum where people can
post different stuff. There's a lot of traffic
coming into the website. So there's a lot of
engagement on the content and you can find
Posts that have performed really well so you
can see this is about 2,200 upwards 1,700 upwards
This one got 16,000 upwards. So there must be
something good about this video. It's about
construction, which is a keyword that I entered
over here But I hope you are all good here
This Okay, this is about China's manufacturing
being below a dam That's a funny one. 9Gag
is a very good source for videos, memes, images.
You don't come find a lot of text content on
here but videos, memes and images. 9Gag is
a very good source that you can use. The next
three sources are basically the social media
platforms. The first one is YouTube. Now YouTube
makes this content format, creation of this
content format very easy. for the simple reason
that you can enter like any keywords. I can
just enter something like viral construction.
Okay. I can enter viral construction. I click
on filters and I click on under four minutes
because we don't want very long videos for viral
influencers. Ideally it should always be, videos
should be always below four minutes. So I click
on four minutes and I sort by the view count.
That is all I do. And what I get are posts that
have generated millions and millions of views
for different kinds of stuff. So this post has
performed like 164 million views and it's a
shot. It's like... I don't know, 30 seconds
long. So this is a very easy way to find videos
on every single topic under the sun because
YouTube is the biggest video platform in the
world. And you can find videos on virtually
every topic and you can find shorts. And you
can search for them as well. Now, in addition
to YouTube, you can also use platforms like
Instagram. But on Instagram, the way you go
about it is you search for the hashtags. So
the URL looks somewhat like this, but you just
open up your Instagram app and search for a
specific keyword like construction, and you
can find a lot of posts about construction.
And you keep scrolling through until you find
a good post that is relevant enough to be published
on your profile. Then you can either copy the
existing... You can either copy the existing
post copy, just put it into ChatGPT and ask
ChatGPT to rewrite this. You can even define
the number of characters in ChartGPT. This is
an easy way to go about doing this. Or you
can just whip up a one- to two-line post-copy
if you don't want to spend a lot of time into
the post-copy element. Now, see, the general
rule of thumb is that keeping your post-copy
in between 1,200 and 1,700 characters is the
best way to go about doing it. But the truth
is, viral influencer posts are so easy to create.
that you can easily publish three to four posts
every single day. And the focus over here is
more on the volume and finding content that
performed the best as opposed to the quality
of the content itself. So you're not focusing
about being too authentic or creating content
on your own. All you need to focus on is finding
really good sources on all these different platforms.
You can find really good publishers on YouTube
that publish the exact type of videos that you
want. or you can find really good creators
on Instagram who publish the exact type of content
that you want and keep following them and repurpose
their content with or without source attribution
onto LinkedIn. The best way is to give source
attribution in this manner. So I can just show
you a couple examples where source attribution
has been given properly. Say like. This one,
see this one line over here, that is the source
attribution is given. So it's good to give source
attribution in this manner. You don't even
need to tag them or link them. You just need
to mention the name of the company. And you
can even keep this contextual. So for example,
if we take a look at the latest Daniel Abrahams
post, this is an ad pushed out by Apple and
all he did was Apple transfers a boring sustainable
report into storytelling code. So it was an
ad and all they did was just publish it. just
mention Apple's name and that's more source
attribution. That's more than enough for source
attribution. That's all you need to do to create
viral influencer posts in all these content
formats. Just find them online and then repurpose
them from LinkedIn. For creating posts like
these, these are called viral tweet posts. I
will cover this in the next video.